<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Bundles>
	<Bundle id="Ultimate Mercy" title="Ultimate Mercy" groups="" description="By using lay on hands, you can bring the dead back to life.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 19, Greater Mercy, lay on hands, mercy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can expend 10 uses of lay on hands to bring a single dead creature you touch back to life as a raise dead spell with a caster level equal to your paladin level. You must provide the material component for raise dead or choose to accept 1 temporary negative level; this level automatically goes away after 24 hours, never becomes a permanent negative level, and cannot be overcome in any way except by waiting for the duration to expire.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ultimate Resolve" title="Ultimate Resolve" groups="" description="Your aura of resolve does not fall with you.">
		<Prerequisites>Aura of resolve class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your aura of resolve is a 20-foot emanation, and does not end if you fall unconscious.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The aura of resolve affects each ally within 10 feet, and ends when you fall unconscious.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Umbral Scion" title="Umbral Scion" groups="Drow" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Wis 13, Drow Nobility, Greater Drow Nobility, Improved Drow Nobility, able to use drow spell-like abilities, drow.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one of the following: dispel magic, divine favor, or suggestion. You may use this spell once per day as a spell-like ability. Your caster level is equal to your character level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Umbral Shift" title="Umbral Shift" groups="Teamwork" description="Your shadows dance in the darkness, carrying you with them swiftly and silently so that you're able to swap places with your kindred.">
		<Prerequisites>Darkness racial spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you and an ally with the darkness racial spell-like ability who also has this feat are each in an area of darkness within 20 feet of an object radiating darkness from a darkness spell, you can swap places with that ally as a swift action. Your ally must be willing and must spend an immediate action to complete the swap.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Umbral Spell" title="Umbral Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Targets of your darkness spells radiate darkness.">
		<Prerequisites>Tenebrous Spell.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>An umbral spell gains the darkness descriptor. As long as the spell is in effect, the creature or object affected radiates darkness in a 10-foot radius, reducing illumination similar to the effects of the darkness spell. Nonmagical sources of light, such as torches or lanterns, do not increase the light level in this area. Magical light sources only increase the light level in an area affected by an umbral spell if they are of a higher level than the umbral spell&apos;s unmodified spell level. This effect does not stack with itself or with any other effect that creates darkness.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (an umbral spell uses up a spell slot two levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)You cannot use this feat on a spell with an instantaneous duration or a spell that does not target a creature or object.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unbalancing Blow" title="Unbalancing Blow" groups="Combat" description="With a forceful strike, you throw your foe off-balance.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using this feat, in addition to dealing damage normally, you force a foe damaged by your unarmed attack to attempt a Reflex saving throw (DC = 10 + half your character level + your Wisdom modifier). A creature that fails this saving throw is flat-footed, and if it is larger than Medium size, it loses any special size modifier to its CMD against effects or combat maneuvers that would move it until its next turn. It is also knocked out of any stance associated with a style feat. You must declare that you are using this feat before you make your attack roll; if your attack roll fails, the target is unaffected and your attempt is wasted. You can attempt to use Unbalancing Blow once per day for every 4 character levels you have, but no more than once per round.</p>
			<p>Creatures immune to tripping are immune to this effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unblinking Flame Feint" title="Unblinking Flame Feint" groups="Combat" description="You move as swiftly and unpredictably as a flickering flame.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13; Wis 13; Combat Expertise; Perfect Style; base attack bonus +9 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Perfect Style, you can use your Wisdom modifier in place of your Charisma modifier when attempting Bluff checks to feint. You can spend 1 ki point as a swift action to gain the benefits of Improved Feint for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points instead of 1 ki point when using Unblinking Flame Feint.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unblinking Flame Fist" title="Unblinking Flame Fist" groups="Combat" description="You can exploit the weaknesses in your opponents' defenses, like a flame seeking fuel to consume.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Wis 13, Combat Expertise, Perfect Style, Stunning Fist, Unblinking Flame Feint, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 13th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Perfect Style, the save DC of your stunning fist attack increases by 2 against flat-footed targets. When you spend 1 ki point to gain the benefits of Improved Feint for 1 round, you may attempt a feint as part of your movement when charging.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points instead of 1 ki point when using Unblinking Flame Fist.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unbound Bravery" title="Unbound Bravery" groups="" description="Your firm dedication to the principles of courage and freedom allows you to escape your bonds more easily.">
		<Prerequisites>Bravery class feature, worshiper of a god of luck or drink.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can add the bonus from bravery to Escape Artist checks and combat maneuver checks to escape a grapple. If your bonus from bravery is +2 or higher, then once per day, you can grant that bonus to an ally within 30 feet on a Will save against a fear effect, an Escape Artist check, or a combat maneuver check to escape a grapple.</p>
			<p>Granting this bonus to an ally is an immediate action and must be declared before the result of your ally&apos;s check is revealed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unbreakable" title="Unbreakable" groups="Combat" description="You can endure a staggering amount of punishment.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Endurance, Toughness, fighter level 4th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you gain 1 hit point as a fighter favored class benefit, you gain an additional hit point. Treat your effective Constitution score as being 4 higher for the purpose of determining when you would die from hit point damage. These benefits are retroactive.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Uncanny Alertness" title="Uncanny Alertness" groups="" description="Your research into arcana and the nature of reality has given you heightened senses.">
		<Prerequisites>Alertness</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>This feat gives you an additional +1 bonus on Perception and Sense Motive checks, and you gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against sleep and charm effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Uncanny Concentration" title="Uncanny Concentration" groups="" description="You have learned to enter a deeper state when casting spells, allowing you to shrug off distractions, damage, weather effects, and even the effects of other spells.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Casting.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You do not need to make concentration checks when affected by vigorous or violent motion or by violent weather. You gain a +2 bonus on all other concentration checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Uncanny Defense" title="Uncanny Defense" groups="Combat, Halfling" description="Your instinct for self-preservation gives you many advantages.">
		<Prerequisites>Cautious Fighter, base attack bonus +3, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While fighting defensively or taking the total defense action, you gain a bonus on your Reflex saving throws and to your CMD equal to 1/2 of the dodge bonus to AC you gained from taking that action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unconquerable Resolve" title="Unconquerable Resolve" groups="Combat" description="Each time you tap into your inner strength, your bodily strength is renewed, making you much more resilient than you might look.">
		<Prerequisites>Resolve class feature, samurai level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you spend a daily use of the resolve class feature, you gain 1 temporary hit point per Hit Die you have. These temporary hit points are lost first when you take damage, disappear after 1 minute, and are replenished each time you use the resolve class feature. Temporary hit points gained in this way persist for 24 hours and then, if you haven&apos;t lost them, they disappear.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat can be taken multiple times. Each time you take it, the number of temporary hit points you gain each time you spend a daily use of the resolve class feature increases by 1 per Hit Die you have.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Undaunted Bravery" title="Undaunted Bravery" groups="" description="It takes more than the average threat to intimidate you, and you've mastered the art of menacing your foes by implying violence through your cheerful smile.">
		<Prerequisites>Bravery class feature, worshiper of a god of luck or drink.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can add your bonus from bravery to Intimidate checks and to the DC to intimidate you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Undead Master" title="Undead Master" groups="" description="You can marshal vast armies of the undead to serve you.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell focus (necromancy), the ability to cast animate dead or command undead.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast animate dead or use the Command Undead feat, you are considered to be four levels higher when determining the number of Hit Dice you animate. When you cast command undead, your duration is doubled.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Under and Over" title="Under and Over" groups="Combat" description="You can slip under a foe trying to grab you, knocking him off balance.">
		<Prerequisites>Agile Maneuvers, Small size or smaller.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If an opponent larger than you attempts to grapple you and fails, you may make a trip attack as an immediate action against that opponent with a +2 bonus. This does not provoke an attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Underfoot" title="Underfoot" groups="Combat" description="You slip under and around your larger foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Mobility, Small size or smaller.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +4 dodge bonus on Acrobatics checks to move past opponents without provoking attacks of opportunity, so long as they are larger than you. In addition, you gain a +2 dodge bonus to Armor Class against attacks of opportunity caused when you move out of or within a larger opponent&apos;s threatened area (this stacks with the +4 bonus provided by Mobility, for a total bonus of +6).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Underfoot Combat" title="Underfoot Combat" groups="Combat" description="You clamber in and around your enemies' personal space to devastating effect.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, swarming racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You are able to share a space with a hostile creature at least one size category larger than you. You gain a +2 shield bonus to your AC while occupying an opponent&apos;s space, as well as a +2 bonus on all attack rolls against the creature whose space you share. Creatures you share a square with take a -2 penalty on all concentration checks. Entering a space occupied by an opponent provokes an attack of opportunity. This ability does not stack with similar abilities providing a creature benefits for being in another creature&apos;s space, such as a mouser swashbuckler&apos;s underfoot attack deed.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat counts as the Disruptive feat for the purpose of qualifying for other feats that have Disruptive as a prerequisite.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Underhanded Teamwork" title="Underhanded Teamwork" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You and your allies know how to use coordinated maneuvers to set up an enemy with an unfair disadvantage.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Expertise, Improved Dirty Trick.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever an ally who also has this feat performs a dirty trick combat maneuver against a foe you both threaten, you can use an immediate action to increase the inflicted condition&apos;s duration by 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Undermining Exploit" title="Undermining Exploit" groups="" description="Your familiarity with earth and stone gives you a distinct advantage on rocky battlefields.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (dungeoneering) 4 ranks</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 insight bonus on combat maneuver checks against opponents occupying a square of rocky difficult terrain such as rubble, broken ground, or steep stairs.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Undersized Mount" title="Undersized Mount" groups="Combat" description="You've learned techniques that allow you to ride beasts of smaller sizes than normal.">
		<Prerequisites>Ride 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can ride creatures of your size category, although encumbrance or other factors might limit how you can use this ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Typically a mount suited for you is at least one size category larger than you.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unfair Grip" title="Unfair Grip" groups="Combat" description="You learned to fight in places that have no rules of engagement, such as back alleys or fighting pits, and you can grab foes in ways that are difficult to escape.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike, Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you perform a grapple combat maneuver, you gain a +1 bonus on checks to maintain your grapple, and your grappled foes take a -1 penalty on checks to escape your grapple.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unfettered Familiar" title="Unfettered Familiar" groups="" description="You can channel touch spells through your familiar without needing to be adjacent to it.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 5th, familiar class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can cast a touch spell without being in contact with your familiar and designate your familiar as the &#x201C;toucher.&#x201D; You do not require line of sight to your familiar to use this ability, but you must be within 30 feet of your familiar when you cast the spell, and if you can&apos;t see or hear your familiar, you must at least be able to speak with it.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you do, you gain another use of this feat, and the distance you can be from your familiar increases by 10 feet.</p>
		</Special>
		<Normal>
			<p>Your familiar must be in contact with you when a spell is cast in order for it to deliver the spell.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unfolding Wind Rush" title="Unfolding Wind Rush" groups="Combat" description="Thrown weapons fly from your hands as if blown by a gale, and you leave behind a wake of wind as you move.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Wis 13, Mobility, Perfect Style, Quick Draw, Unfolding Wind Strike, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 13th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Perfect Style and wielding thrown weapons, you can combine a full attack action with a single move action. You must forgo the attack at your highest bonus but may take the remaining attacks as normal at any point during your movement. You can spend 1 ki point as a swift action to create a path of wind along your path of movement that functions as wind wall for 1 round; this effect does not affect your ranged attacks.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points instead of 1 ki point when using Unfolding Wind Rush.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unfolding Wind Strike" title="Unfolding Wind Strike" groups="Combat" description="The wind through which your thrown weapons fly directs them to their target or back to your hand.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Wis 13, Perfect Style, Quick Draw, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Perfect Style, you double the range increment of any thrown weapon you wield. You can spend 1 ki point as a swift action to imbue a number of thrown weapons equal to your Wisdom bonus with the returning or seeking weapon special ability for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points instead of 1 ki point when using Unfolding Wind Strike.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unimpeachable Honor" title="Unimpeachable Honor" groups="" description="Your devotion to your principles and your allies makes acting against them unthinkable.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are under the effects of a charm or compulsion effect and would be compelled to take an action that violates your fundamental nature, explicitly violates the strictures of your religion, or would be an act of an alignment that directly opposes your own (for instance, a chaotic or evil act if you are lawful good), you gain a +4 bonus on any saving throw or opposed Charisma check to resist that command or break free from the effect.</p>
			<p>Whenever you are compelled to attack an ally, you take a &#x2013;4 penalty on your attack rolls and damage rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unsanctioned Detection" title="Unsanctioned Detection" groups="" description="You can focus your ability to detect evil for more practical or mundane purposes.">
		<Prerequisites>Detect evil class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can focus the clarity granted by your detect evil ability to heighten your awareness of other things. This gives you a +10 sacred bonus on Perception and Sense Motive checks for one round. This expends your use of the detect evil class ability for the next 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unsanctioned Knowledge" title="Unsanctioned Knowledge" groups="" description="You have searched though forbidden texts and are privy to powerful but proscribed magic.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, ability to cast 1st-level paladin spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Pick one 1st-level spell, one 2nd-level spell, one 3rd-level spell, and one 4th-level spell from the bard, cleric, inquisitor, or oracle spell lists. Add these spells to your paladin spell list as paladin spells of the appropriate level. Once chosen, these spells cannot be changed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unseat" title="Unseat" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at unseating your mounted opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Ride 1 rank, Mounted Combat, Power Attack, Improved Bull Rush, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When charging an opponent while mounted and wielding a lance, resolve the attack as normal. If it hits, you may immediately make a free bull rush attempt in addition to the normal damage. If successful, the target is knocked off his horse and lands prone in a space adjacent to his mount that is directly away from you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Untwisting Iron Skin" title="Untwisting Iron Skin" groups="Combat" description="Your training has tempered your flesh to resist blows as though it were forged iron.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Wis 13, Perfect Style, Toughness, Untwisting Iron Strength, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 13th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Perfect Style, you gain an amount of DR/adamantine equal to 1/3 your character level (maximum 6). Additionally, whenever you break an item with at least hardness 10, you gain DR 1/&#x2014; for a number of rounds equal to half the item&apos;s hit points (maximum 10 rounds); the value of this damage reduction increases by 1 for every 5 points of hardness above 10 the broken item possessed. You can spend 1 ki point as a swift action to double either of the damage reduction values granted by this feat for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points instead of 1 ki point when using Untwisting Iron Skin.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Untwisting Iron Strength" title="Untwisting Iron Strength" groups="Combat" description="You are a master at breaking through even the toughest of objects, as though your fists were adamantine hammers.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Wis 13, Perfect Style, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Perfect Style, you can ignore an amount of hardness equal to your character level. Additionally, you gain a +4 bonus on Strength checks to break objects. If you spend 1 ki point as a swift action, you also gain the benefits of Improved Sunder for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points instead of 1 ki point when using Untwisting Iron Strength.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unusual Origin" title="Unusual Origin" groups="Changeling" description="Your mother was part of a powerful hag coven, and it shows when you are near your kin.">
		<Prerequisites>Changeling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you are within 30 feet of at least two other changelings, you gain a +2 bonus on concentration checks and dispel checks. If at least two of these changelings also have this feat, these bonuses increase to +4.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This version of Unusual Origin is a teamwork feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unusual Origin - Gillman" title="Unusual Origin" groups="Gillmen" description="You have abilities supposedly tied to mysterious ancestors who still watch over you and your ilk.">
		<Prerequisites>Gillman.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your divination spells and spell-like abilities manifest at 1 caster level higher. In addition, once per day while fully immersed in water, you can cast augury as a spell-like ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Unyielding Ferocity" title="Unyielding Ferocity" groups="Combat" description="When near the brink of death, you fight ferociously until the bitter end.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 19, ferocity</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are reduced to 0 or fewer hit points, if you remain conscious from your ferocity monster ability, you can make a full attack on your next turn (or your current turn if you are reduced to 0 hit points on your own turn). If you do, you push your body to the point that your mind becomes more primitive, and you can no longer use any Charisma-, Dexterity-, or Intelligence-based skills except Acrobatics, Fly, Intimidate, or Ride, or any ability that requires patience or concentration (such as spellcasting) until your hit points are raised above 0.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When using the ferocity ability, you are staggered while you have fewer than 0 hit points and thus can&apos;t make a full attack.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Upsetting Shield Style" title="Upsetting Shield Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You can strike at weapons to upset enemy attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, proficiency with bucklers.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can shield bash with a buckler as if it were a light shield, and you can use the buckler in conjunction with any feats or abilities that normally apply to light shields. While using this style, whenever you successfully deal damage to an opponent with a shield bash using your buckler, that opponent takes a -2 penalty on all attack rolls made against you until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Upsetting Strike" title="Upsetting Strike" groups="Combat" description="You can turn the tables on disoriented opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Combat Reflexes, Improved Shield Bash, Upsetting Shield Style, proficiency with bucklers.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Upsetting Shield Style, if a foe is taking a penalty on attack rolls against you as a result of Upsetting Shield Style, and that foe makes a melee attack roll against you that misses your AC by 5 or more, that foe provokes an attack of opportunity from you.</p>
			<p>You can only make one attack of opportunity against an opponent in this manner each round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Upsetting Vengeance" title="Upsetting Vengeance" groups="Combat" description="You punish those who fail to press their attack.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Combat Reflexes, Improved Shield Bash, Upsetting Shield Style, Upsetting Strike, proficiency with bucklers.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Upsetting Shield Style, the penalty on attack rolls foes take for being hit by your shield bash attack applies to their attacks against any target. If an adjacent foe taking this penalty makes an attack roll against any target and misses the target&apos;s AC by 5 or more, that foe provokes an attack of opportunity from you. You can only make one attack of opportunity against an opponent as a result of this feat or Upsetting Strike each round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Urban Forager" title="Urban Forager" groups="" description="You are skilled at keeping yourself and others safe in the alleys, sewers, and underbellies of cities.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (Local) 4 ranks, Survival 4 ranks</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may use the Survival skill to forage and track in urban locations using the following table:</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Valiant Steed" title="Valiant Steed" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="Your courage is unnaturally strong.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal or magical beast.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 morale bonus on saves against fear and emotion effects. If you can serve as a mount, your rider gains a +4 morale bonus on Handle Animal, Ride, and wild empathy checks to force you within range of a creature with the unnatural aura universal monster rule. In addition, the DC to push you with the Handle Animal skill does not increase if you are wounded or have taken any nonlethal damage or ability score damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The DC to push an animal increases by 2 if the animal is wounded or has taken any nonlethal damage or ability score damage.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Valiant Vault" title="Valiant Vault" groups="Mythic" description="Your mount can make heroic leaps.">
		<Prerequisites>Mounted Combat, Ride-By Attack, Ride 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your mount is always considered to have a running start when using Acrobatics to jump. You can expend one use of mythic power to grant your mount a +10 bonus on an Acrobatics check, or a +20 bonus if the check is made to jump.</p>
			<p>When making a mounted charge, you can guide your mount to leap over a foe between your starting position and the target of your charge. You make a Ride check or your mount makes an Acrobatics check (whichever is lower) during the charge, using the rules for the leap task under the Ride skill. If the height you clear with that check exceeds the creature&apos;s height, you jump over it and continue your charge on the opposite side. This movement provokes attacks of opportunity. Alternatively, you can vault over your target while making a Ride-By Attack, allowing you to move over or through its space and continue moving on the opposite side of it. If your jump exceeds the target&apos;s height, you gain a +1 bonus on the attack roll for higher ground, and if any of your allies threatens the target, you treat the target as flanked for purposes of your Ride-By Attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vampiric Companion" title="Vampiric Companion" groups="" description="Just as your undead existence mocks nature, so too does your twisted companion reflect the vile nature of vampirism.">
		<Prerequisites>Dhampir or vampire, nongood alignment, 10th level in a class that grants a familiar or animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your animal companion or familiar&apos;s type changes to &apos;undead.&apos; The creature gains fast healing 5 as well as your vampire or dhampir weaknesses. If you are a vampire, the creature also gains the following abilities, depending on what type of vampire you are.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If your animal companion or familiar is destroyed, dismissed, or lost, you can apply the effects of this feat to the replacement creature. If you are destroyed, the creature retains its undead type but loses all other special abilities from this feat. If you have more than one animal companion or familiar, choose one of them when you select this feat and apply its effects to that creature.</p>
			<p>You can select this feat more than once. Each time you select the feat, it applies to a different animal companion or familiar.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vandal" title="Vandal" groups="Goblin" description="Even other goblins admire your talent for mindless destruction.">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin, sneak attack class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat unattended objects as if they were vulnerable to your sneak attack, but you only deal half as much damage as you would against an actual creature.</p>
			<p>For instance, if you rolled 12 extra damage from the sneak attack you would deal an extra 6 damage to the object. This only applies when attacking unattended objects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vanguard Hustle" title="Vanguard Hustle" groups="Combat" description="You are able to protect allies from a distance.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Bodyguard, Combat Patrol, Combat Reflexes, Mobility, Saving Shield, Vanguard Style, Vanguard Ward, proficiency with light or heavy shields.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Add half of your shield&apos;s enhancement bonus to the shield bonus to AC that you grant to an ally using the Saving Shield feat. While using Vanguard Style, whenever you increase your threatened area with Combat Patrol, your ward retains the bonuses of Vanguard Style as long as he remains within your threatened area, and you can use Bodyguard, Saving Shield, and Vanguard Style whenever an ally that is within this threatened area is the target of an attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vanguard Style" title="Vanguard Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You can bring your shield to bear against dangers that threaten your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Bodyguard, Combat Reflexes, proficiency with light or heavy shields.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, when an adjacent ally is required to make a Reflex saving throw, you can expend a use of an attack of opportunity to attempt the aid another action to improve your ally&apos;s Reflex save. Your ally gains a +2 bonus to all Reflex saves while adjacent to you until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vanguard Ward" title="Vanguard Ward" groups="Combat" description="You strongly defend your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Bodyguard, Combat Reflexes, Vanguard Style, proficiency with light or heavy shields.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Vanguard Style, when an adjacent ally is attacked or required to make a Reflex saving throw, you can expend a use of an attack of opportunity to use both Bodyguard and Vanguard Style to protect that ally.</p>
			<p>You can also lose your shield bonus to AC to grant your ally a shield bonus to AC of the same value for as long as that ally gains a bonus to Reflex saves from Vanguard Style.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Variant Prayer-Scroll" title="Variant Prayer-Scroll" groups="" description="You have learned the secret to changing the powers granted by your prayer scroll.">
		<Prerequisites>Jiang-shi</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the ability to create a different type of prayer scroll. You may create a prayer scroll with this ability by using any strip of parchment and a writing instrument, but doing so requires 10 minutes of uninterrupted work. Swapping your current prayer scroll for a different prepared one is a standard action. When wearing a different prayer scroll, you gain its special abilities, but lose your normal prayer scroll&apos;s immunity to spell completion and spell trigger magic items. Your prayer scrolls can be used only by you, and have no effect when used by other jiang-shis. When you choose this feat, select one of the following prayer scroll types.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You may select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, choose another ability granted by the feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vast Hatred" title="Vast Hatred" groups="Combat,Gnome" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Gnome, hatred racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select two creature types (and subtypes where appropriate) from the list of potential favored enemies from the ranger class ability. Your +1 attack bonus from the hatred racial trait applies to creatures of the selected types (and subtypes).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You may take this feat more than once. Its benefits do not stack. Each time you select this feat, you select two additional creature types to which your hatred racial trait applies.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vast Spell" title="Vast Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells cover targets across a larger area.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can alter a spell that targets a number of creatures no more than 30 feet apart, such as haste. The maximum distance apart of those you target with the spell increases to 60 feet.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a vast spell uses up a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Venomous Spray" title="Venomous Spray" groups="Combat" description="You can spit your poison into a nearby opponent's face.">
		<Prerequisites>Serpentfolk.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can spit venom as a secondary ranged attack with a range of 5 feet. This is a natural attack and doesn&apos;t provoke attacks of opportunity. A target struck by your venom must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = your poison DC) or be blinded for 1d4 rounds and suffer the normal effects of your poison. You can&apos;t use this attack during any round in which you make a bite attack (and vice versa). After spitting venom, you are unable to use your poisonous bite or to spit venom for 1d4 rounds.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Verdant Spell" title="Verdant Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your magical connection to nature allows you to entice, fool, and misdirect plants and fungi as though they were people.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Focus (enchantment), Knowledge (nature) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A verdant spell affects plant creatures (even mindless plant creatures) as if they weren&apos;t immune to mind-affecting effects, but it has no effect on other types of creatures. This feat works only on mind-affecting spells.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (a verdant spell uses up a spell slot 2 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)<Normal>
			</Normal></p><p>Creatures of the plant type are immune to mind-affecting effects.</p>
		<p></p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vermin Heart" title="Vermin Heart" groups="" description="You have a special bond with things that creep, crawl, skitter, and sting.">
		<Prerequisites>Wild empathy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may target vermin with spells and special abilities that only affect animals (although they are still affected by spells targeting vermin as well). You may use wild empathy to influence vermin as easily as you influence animals.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Versatile Channeler" title="Versatile Channeler" groups="" description="You can choose to channel positive and negative energy.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature, necromancer or neutrally aligned cleric (see below).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may make a choice whenever you use your channel energy class feature.</p>
			<p>If you normally channel positive energy, you may choose to channel negative energy as if your effective cleric level were 2 levels lower than normal.</p>
			<p>If you normally channel negative energy, you may choose to channel positive energy as if your effective cleric level were 2 levels lower than normal.</p>
			<p>Having this feat means you qualify for feats and abilities that have &#x201C;channel positive energy&#x201D; or &#x201C;channel negative energy&#x201D; as a prerequisite (for example, you qualify for the Command Undead feat and the Turn Undead feat).</p>
			<p>Note: This feat only applies to necromancers, neutral clerics who worship neutral deities, or neutral clerics who do not worship a deity &#x2014; characters who have the channel energy class ability and have to make a choice to channel positive or negative energy at 1st level. Clerics whose alignment or deity makes this choice for them cannot select this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Versatile Jinxer" title="Versatile Jinxer" groups="" description="Your jinx's power comes from a different source than most halflings.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will, Halfling Jinx alternate racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose either Intelligence or Wisdom. The DC of your jinx is based on this ability score instead of on Charisma.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vicious Stomp" title="Vicious Stomp" groups="Combat" description="You take advantage of the moment to brutally kick an enemy when he is down.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever an opponent falls prone adjacent to you, that opponent provokes an attack of opportunity from you. This attack must be an unarmed strike.</p>
			<p>Editor&apos;s Note</p>
			<p>The Greater Trip feat allows you to take an attack of opportunity against a foe that you trip. The Vicious Stomp feat allows you to take an attack of opportunity against a foe that falls prone adjacent to you. If you have both these feats and trip a foe, do you get to make two attacks of opportunity (assuming that you can)?</p>
			<p>Yes, the two triggering acts are similar here but they are different. One occurs when you trip a foe. The other occurs when a foe falls prone. It requires a large number of feats to accomplish, but you can really pile on the attacks with this combination.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vigilant Charger" title="Vigilant Charger" groups="Combat" description="You can ready yourself to spring an attack against your enemies at a moment's notice.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Dex 13, Combat Reflexes.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can ready an action to charge when an enemy enters a specific space you designate. You must be able to charge the square both when you ready the charge and when the readied action triggers, or you cannot attempt the readied action. When you make a readied charge, you can move only up to your speed.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can&apos;t ready an action to charge. Charging allows you to move up to twice your speed.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vigilant Eidolon" title="Vigilant Eidolon" groups="" description="Your eidolon is highly observant, and its link with you increases your own watchfulness.">
		<Prerequisites>Eidolon class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While your eidolon is within your reach, you gain a +4 bonus on Perception checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in Perception, this bonus increases to +8. This does not apply if your eidolon is helpless or unconscious.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vigilant Phantom" title="Vigilant Phantom" groups="" description="Your phantom is highly observant, and its link with you increases your own watchfulness.">
		<Prerequisites>Phantom class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While your phantom is within your reach, you gain a +4 bonus on Perception checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in Perception, this bonus increases to +8. This doesn&apos;t apply if your phantom is helpless or unconscious.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vim and Vigor" title="Vim and Vigor" groups="Combat" description="You rebound more quickly than normal when you draw upon your inner reserve to repair your wounds.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Combat Vigor, Endurance, character level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your vigor pool gains 1 vigor point. The fatigued condition that you gain from spending vigor points (as described by the Combat Vigor feat) lasts for 3 rounds instead of 1 minute. In addition, when you take this feat, you gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against effects that cause fatigue or exhaustion.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Violent Display" title="Violent Display" groups="Combat" description="You never miss an opportunity to cow foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you land a successful sneak attack or confirm a critical hit against a creature with a weapon with which you have Weapon Focus, you can use Dazzling Display as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat is available to weretigers, weretiger-kin and those who associate with these creatures.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Virulent Venom" title="Virulent Venom" groups="Combat" description="The poison that drips from your fangs is potent enough to burn through flesh and wood.">
		<Prerequisites>Spit Venom, nagaji.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your ability to spit poison granted by the Spit Venom feat deals 1d6 points of acid damage plus an additional 1d6 points of acid damage for every 3 Hit Dice you have, in addition to all other effects.</p>
			<p>This additional damage affects creatures even if they are immune to poison or succeed at their Fortitude saving throws. In addition, you gain one additional use per day of the ability to spit poison granted by the Spit Venom feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Visceral Threat" title="Visceral Threat" groups="Combat" description="Your ability to threaten foes is great enough to make them hesitate.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidating Prowess.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may use Intimidate, rather than Bluff, to attempt a feint against a creature within your melee reach.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Viscous Venom" title="Viscous Venom" groups="Combat" description="Your venom is abnormally thick and adhesive.">
		<Prerequisites>Spit Venom, nagaji.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you spit poison using the ability granted by the Spit Venom feat, you can spit a glob of venomous goo at an enemy within 30 feet. Once struck, the target is both exposed to your nagaji poison as normal and entangled. An entangled target can break free from the sticky goo with a successful DC 15 Strength or Escape Artist check as a full-round action or by dealing 15 points of damage to the gooey substance with a slashing weapon. In addition, you gain one additional use per day of the ability to spit poison granted by the Spit Venom feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vision Mastery" title="Vision Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can pierce invisibility with divination magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 2 ranks, base Fortitude save bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has a divination spell of 1st level or higher in its construction requirements to cast either darkvision or see invisibility.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day at base Fortitude save bonus +6, +8, +10, and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vital Strike" title="Vital Strike" groups="Combat" description="You make a single attack that deals significantly more damage than normal.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the attack action, you can make one attack at your highest base attack bonus that deals additional damage. Roll the weapon&apos;s damage dice for the attack twice and add the results together before adding bonuses from Strength, weapon abilities (such as flaming), precision-based damage, and other damage bonuses. These extra weapon damage dice are not multiplied on a critical hit, but are added to the total.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Voice of Beasts" title="Voice of Beasts" groups="" description="Your deep connection with nature allows you to speak with all manner of living creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Wild shape class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using wild shape, you gain the ability to communicate with all animals. This acts as speak with animals, though the effect is supernatural in nature and can&apos;t be dispelled.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Voice of the Sibyl" title="Voice of the Sibyl" groups="" description="Your voice is strangely compelling.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 15.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +1 bonus on all Bluff, Diplomacy, and Perform (oratory) skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +3 for that skill. You do not get these bonuses if you do not use your voice when using the skill (such as using Bluff to feint in combat).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Volley Fire" title="Volley Fire" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You have trained to work in ranks of archers to rain arrows down upon your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on ranged attack rolls for each ally with this feat who made a ranged attack since the end of your last turn against a target within 15 feet of your target, to a maximum of +4. These allies don&apos;t provide cover against your attacks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Vulpine Pounce" title="Vulpine Pounce" groups="Combat, Kitsune" description="You can change shape mid-charge and pounce on an opponent in the same round.">
		<Special>
			<p>A kitsune may select this feat any time she would gain a feat.</p>
		</Special>
		<Prerequisites>Swift Kitsune Shapechanger, base attack bonus +10, kitsune.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you change shape into your kitsune form and use the charge action in the same round, you can make a full attack against your opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Walking Sleight" title="Walking Sleight" groups="" description="You've developed your skills at picking up items while on the move.">
		<Prerequisites>Deft Hands, Sleight of Hand 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You no longer take the &#x2013;20 penalty for attempting a Sleight of Hand check as a move action. You can attempt a Sleight of Hand check as a standard action in the middle of your move action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can attempt a Sleight of Hand check as a move action only by taking a &#x2013;20 penalty on the check.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wall's Stance" title="Wall's Stance" groups="Combat" description="You can lock your armor and shield into an impenetrable barrier.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, proficiency with heavy armor and shields.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a move action when wearing heavy armor and using a heavy shield or tower shield, you increase the bonus to AC granted by your armor and your shield by 1 each until you move or are moved from your current square. You must be in contact with solid ground to gain this benefit. You can never increase an armor or shield bonus to AC by more than 1 each in this way.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wand Dancer" title="Wand Dancer" groups="" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Dodge, Mobility, Perform (dance) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using a spell trigger item, you can move both before and after triggering the item, as long as the total distance moved is not greater than your speed. Choose one creature potentially affected by your spell trigger item. Your movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity from that creature only. You must move at least 5 feet before and after using your spell trigger item to utilize this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="War Blessing" title="War Blessing" groups="" description="Your fervent call to your deity imbues you with a temporary blessing.">
		<Prerequisites>Mystery or domain class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose two warpriest blessings when you take this feat. Each of these blessings must be tied to a domain granted by your deity or to one of the two domains that represent your spiritual inclination and abilities. Twice per day, you can call upon the minor blessing from one or the other of your chosen blessings. This ability otherwise acts like the warpriest blessings class feature. Your effective warpriest level is the highest level that you have in the class that has the mystery or domain class feature.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="War Singer" title="War Singer" groups="" description="Your songs draw upon the savage chants and brutal ways of your people, inspiring those around you to new heights of violence and savagery.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, bardic performance class feature, half-orc or orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use bardic performance with audible components on a battlefield (any area where a combat involving a dozen or more combatants is taking place), the range or area of your chosen performance is doubled. In addition, the DC for saving throws against your bardic performance is increased by +2 for creatures of the orc subtype, regardless of where the performance occurs.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Warning Shot" title="Warning Shot" groups="Combat" description="An intentional near-miss demonstrates your frightening skill at range.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot, Weapon Focus, proficiency with the selected weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make a ranged touch attack using a ranged weapon with which you have Weapon Focus. If successful, instead of dealing damage or applying any other effects of the attack, you may attempt an Intimidate check to demoralize the target as a free action. The target doesn&apos;t need to be within 30 feet, nor does it need to be able to see or hear you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Warrior Priest" title="Warrior Priest" groups="" description="Your religion is both a shield and a weapon in battle.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast divine spells, domain or mystery class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on initiative checks and a +2 bonus on concentration checks made to cast a spell or use a spell-like ability when casting defensively or while grappled.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Water Skinned" title="Water Skinned" groups="Undine" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Undine.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can extinguish a small non-magical fire with a touch, affecting anything up to the size of a large campfire. This ability does not affect fires with a total area greater than 5 square feet. Touching the fire in this way does not harm you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Waterway Caster" title="Waterway Caster" groups="" description="You've learned to cast spells while on a watercraft or even while swimming in turbulent waters.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You automatically succeed at concentration checks required to cast a spell while being subjected to vigorous or violent motion while either swimming or on a ship. You gain a +4 bonus on concentration checks to cast spells underwater.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wave Strike" title="Wave Strike" groups="Combat" description="You present a serene facade until you unsheathe your weapon and strike in one fluid motion.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon expertise class feature or Quick Draw, Bluff 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If on your first turn of combat you draw a melee weapon to attack an opponent within your reach, you can spend a swift action to make a Bluff check to feint against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon Adept" title="Weapon Adept" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at using customized weaponry.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a weapon modification (such as jagged hooks). You treat weapons with that modification as being of their normal category (simple, martial, or exotic).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A modified weapon is treated as one category more difficult to wield.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times, choosing a different weapon modification each time.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon Evoker Mastery" title="Weapon Evoker Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You rack opponents with eldritch power coursing from your magic weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 2 ranks, base Fortitude saving throw bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action while wielding a magic weapon with a weapon special ability that deals extra acid, cold, fire, electricity, or sonic damage on a hit, you deal an additional 1d4 points of damage of the same type with each hit you make with that weapon for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon Finesse" title="Weapon Finesse" groups="Combat" description="You are trained in using your agility in melee combat, as opposed to brute strength.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>With a light weapon, elven curve blade, rapier, whip, or spiked chain made for a creature of your size category, you may use your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier on attack rolls. If you carry a shield, its armor check penalty applies to your attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Natural weapons are considered light weapons.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon Focus" title="Weapon Focus" groups="Combat" description="Choose one type of weapon. You can also choose unarmed strike or grapple (or ray, if you are a spellcaster) as your weapon for the purposes of this feat.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficiency with selected weapon, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on all attack rolls you make using the selected weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of weapon.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon Specialization" title="Weapon Specialization" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at dealing damage with one weapon. Choose one type of weapon (including unarmed strike or grapple) for which you have already selected the Weapon Focus feat. You deal extra damage when using this weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficiency with selected weapon, Weapon Focus with selected weapon, fighter level 4th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on all damage rolls you make using the selected weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of weapon.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon Trick" title="Weapon Trick" groups="Combat" description="">
			<p>Choose one weapon trick option (one-handed weapon, polearm, ranged, two-handed weapon, two-weapon, or weapon and shield).</p>
			<p>You can perform weapon tricks in combat when armed appropriately for that option.</p>
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1. In addition to the prerequisites (listed in parentheses) for each weapon trick, you must be proficient with any weapon or shield used in the trick and have the Weapon Trick feat with the appropriate option.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use any weapon tricks relating to the chosen weapon option if you meet the trick&apos;s prerequisites and are proficient with any weapon or shield that you use as part of the trick.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain Weapon Trick multiple times. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new weapon trick option.</p>
			<hr>
			<p>You can use these tricks only while wearing light or no armor, wielding a light or one-handed manufactured weapon in one hand, and holding nothing in your off hand.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Base attack bonus +6</p>
			<p>As a full-round action, you can make a single attack with your weapon and attempt to perform a dirty trick, disarm, drag, reposition, or steal combat maneuver with your free hand, taking no penalties for two-weapon fighting. The combat maneuver provokes attacks of opportunities as normal, unless you have an appropriate ability or feat. You are not considered unarmed for this maneuver, but can&apos;t apply any benefits of your weapon to the combat maneuver check.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MAH</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Improved Grapple, base attack bonus +6)</p>
			<p>As a standard action, you can initiate a grapple with your free hand (taking the usual -4 penalty for not having two hands free). If the attempt is successful, you can immediately follow up with an attack using your light or one-handed weapon as a free action. If you do so, you can&apos;t use any other abilities that are triggered by a successful grapple combat maneuver check (such as constrict). The grapple attempt provokes attacks of opportunity as normal unless you have an ability or feat that prevents this.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Dodge</p>
			<p>As an immediate action, you can gain a +4 dodge bonus to your AC against a single of which attack you are aware. You must make this decision before the attack roll is revealed. You are staggered on your next turn.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Improved Disarm, base attack bonus +6</p>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make a single attack with your weapon and attempt to perform a disarm combat maneuver with your free hand, taking no penalties for two-weapon fighting.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Combat Reflexes, base attack bonus +4</p>
			<p>When your AC exceeds the result of a foe&apos;s melee attack against you by 5 or more, that foe provokes an attack of opportunity from you. Once you make such an attack of opportunity against a foe, you can&apos;t again use this trick against the foe that day.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MAH</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Improved Feint)</p>
			<p>As a free action, you can pass a light or one-handed weapon you are wielding to your free hand. If you attempt a feint during the same round, you gain a +2 bonus on your Bluff check. Once you have used this weapon trick against a target, you can&apos;t gain the bonus against the same creature until 24 hours have passed.</p>
			<hr>
			<p>You can use these tricks only while wielding a weapon from the polearm weapon group.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Acrobatics 1 rank, Climb 1 rank</p>
			<p>You can take a -2 penalty on attack rolls and damage rolls until the beginning of your next turn in order to choke up on and wield a two-handed polearm sized for you in one hand, as long as you do not make attacks with your other hand.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Improved Bull Rush, Improved Reposition, or Improved Trip</p>
			<p>You can attempt a bull rush, reposition, or trip combat maneuver check one for which you have the matching prerequisite feat) against an adjacent foe, even if wielding a weapon with the reach quality.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Weapon Focus</p>
			<p>You can accept a -2 penalty on attack rolls with a reach polearm for which you have Weapon Focus in order to treat the weapon as if it lacked the reach quality until the start of your next turn. If you do, the polearm functions as a club. Any qualities such as trip) or special abilities such as keen) of the weapon that a club could not have, and any feats or abilities you can&apos;t apply to a club, don&apos;t apply to attacks with the weapon during this time.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Acrobatics 10 ranks</p>
			<p>You can use a polearm to improve your balance. Any round in which you do not make a melee attack, you can take 10 on an Acrobatics check even when distraction would normally prevent you from doing so.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MAH</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Acrobatics 3 ranks)</p>
			<p>You gain a +4 bonus on Acrobatics checks to jump, and you count as having a running start if you move at least 5 feet before jumping.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Base attack bonus +6</p>
			<p>While taking a full-attack action with a polearm with brace, you can ready an attack with the polearm in place of your final attack. The readied attack uses the attack bonus of the attack you used to ready it.</p>
			<hr>
			<p>You can use these tricks while wielding a ranged weapon.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Precise Shot, Snap Shot</p>
			<p>You can distract a foe at a crucial moment, making it vulnerable to your allies&apos; abilities.</p>
			<p>You can ready an action to make a ranged attack against a foe when an ally forces the foe to attempt a saving throw. If your attack hits the foe and deals damage, the foe takes a -4 penalty on the saving throw that triggered your readied action.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Far Shot, Precise Shot</p>
			<p>You can cover an ally&apos;s momentary vulnerability.</p>
			<p>You can ready an action to make a ranged attack against a foe when it makes an attack of opportunity. If your attack hits and damages the foe, the foe&apos;s attack of opportunity automatically misses its target.</p>
			<hr>
			<p>You can use these tricks while wielding any two-handed weapon.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Cleave, Improved Vital Strike, Power Attack</p>
			<p>When you use Cleave, you can add the additional damage from Vital Strike to both your initial and your secondary attacks. If you also have the Greater Vital Strike feat, you can instead add the damage from Improved Vital Strike to both your initial and your secondary attacks.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Improved Sunder, Power Attack</p>
			<p>When you deal damage to a foe&apos;s armor with a successful sunder combat maneuver check while using a two-handed weapon, the foe must succeed at a Fortitude save DC = 10 + 1/2 your base attack bonus + your Strength modifier) or be fatigued for 1 round. If the armor has the broken condition after you damage it, the foe must continue making this save every round until he removes the armor or the armor loses the broken condition. If the armor is destroyed by your sunder attempt, the foe is automatically fatigued for 1 round. The foe cannot become exhausted this way.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MAH</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): base attack bonus +6)</p>
			<p>As a standard action, you can release one of your hands holding a two-handed weapon and make a melee attack with the weapon, increasing your reach by 5 feet for the duration of the attack.</p>
			<p>If the attack hits, you deal damage as if using a one-handed weapon, adding only your Strength bonus to damage if you are using your primary hand or half your Strength bonus if you are using your off hand, instead of 1-1/2 times your Strength bonus. Otherwise, you take no penalty for using the weapon one-handed.</p>
			<p>The extra reach doesn&apos;t stack with the Lunge feat or other effects that extend your melee reach beyond that granted by your size category.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Intimidate 5 ranks</p>
			<p>Capitalizing on the fear inspired by massive weapons, you can take 10 on Intimidate checks even when distracted or in combat.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Combat Expertise</p>
			<p>While you are using the total defense action, fighting defensively, or using Combat Expertise, you gain a +1 shield bonus to AC.</p>
			<hr>
			<p>You can use these tricks only while wielding two weapons.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Two-Weapon Defense, Two-Weapon Fighting</p>
			<p>You can attempt a combat maneuver check to disarm a foe even if the foe has no weapons. This functions as the disarm combat maneuver. If you succeed and the foe has no weapon, you ensnare an arm of your choice, preventing your foe from using that limb until the end of your next turn. A foe can take a standard action to free its arm.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Double Slice, Improved Vital Strike</p>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make two attacks, one with each weapon you&apos;re wielding, applying the normal penalties for two-weapon fighting to each.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Combat Reflexes</p>
			<p>You can make one additional attack of opportunity each round with your off-hand weapon.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Climb 8 ranks</p>
			<p>You can use piercing weapons to climb as if your hands were free. You take a -4 penalty on Stealth checks while doing so.</p>
			<p>You can take 10 on such Climb checks even while distracted or endangered.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MAH</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Two-Weapon Fighting)</p>
			<p>You can draw a weapon even while wielding two weapons. Doing so takes the same type of action as drawing that weapon normally would. As part of the action to draw the weapon, you must sheathe one of the two weapons you were wielding.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MAH</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Two-Weapon Fighting)</p>
			<p>You can ready a standard action to block an attack with your shield, making an attack roll as though you were making a shield bash and using the result as your AC against that attack. If you successfully block the attack, you can attack that opponent with the weapon in your other hand as an immediate action.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Bluff 5 ranks</p>
			<p>You can always take 10 on Bluff checks to feint in combat.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Improved Feint, Improved Two-Weapon Fighting, Bluff 10 ranks</p>
			<p>When you feint successfully against a foe you threaten with your shield, that foe provokes an attack of opportunity from you.</p>
			<p>You can only perform a shield bash with this attack of opportunity.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MAH</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Shield Focus, Double Slice, base attack bonus +11)</p>
			<p>When you make a charge attack, you can attack twice&#x2014;once with your shield and once with the weapon you are wielding in your other hand, applying the normal penalties for fighting with two weapons to each.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Knowledge [dungeoneering] 1 rank</p>
			<p>When you avert your eyes to avoid a gaze attack, you have an 80% chance to avoid having to attempt a saving throw against the gaze.</p>
			<p>Additional Prerequisite(s): Dodge</p>
			<p>As a swift action, you can choose a foe you can see.</p>
			<p>You can pass through that foe&apos;s threatened area without provoking attacks of opportunity from that foe this round. Once you target a foe with this trick, you can&apos;t target it again that day.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon Versatility" title="Weapon Versatility" groups="Combat" description="You can use your favored weapons in unconventional ways.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus, base attack bonus +1</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a weapon with which you have Weapon Focus, you can shift your grip as a swift action so that your weapon deals bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage instead of the damage type normally dealt by that weapon. You may switch back to the weapon&apos;s normal damage type or another damage type as a swift action.</p>
			<p>If your base attack bonus is +5 or higher, using this feat is a free action instead.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weapon of the Chosen" title="Weapon of the Chosen" groups="Combat" description="The influence of your deity guides your favored weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with deity&apos;s favored weapon, must worship and receive spells from a deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can call upon your deity to guide an attack you make with your deity&apos;s favored weapon. On your next attack in that round with that weapon, your weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction or striking an incorporeal creature. If your attack misses because of concealment, you can reroll your miss chance one time to see whether you actually hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Weathered Warrior" title="Weathered Warrior" groups="Combat" description="You have a steady hand in any weather.">
		<Prerequisites>Endurance.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>In areas of strong or severe wind or when affected by wind effects or spells that penalize ranged attacks, you take only half the ranged attack penalty. You can make ranged attacks in windstorm-level winds at a -4 penalty.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Strong and severe winds impose -2 and -4 penalties on ranged attack rolls, respectively. Making ranged attacks in windstorms is impossible.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Welcome Pain" title="Welcome Pain" groups="" description="Your appreciation of pain grants you great stamina.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will, worshiper of an evil god.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you would be reduced to 0 or fewer hit points because of an ongoing or repeating damage effect (such as bleed), you may make a last-ditch effort to shed the condition. If you succeed at a DC 25 Will save, you ignore the damage that would reduce you to 0 or fewer hit points that turn. The DC of each subsequent save made in this manner increases by 1. In addition, spells or abilities that have the pain descriptor deal only half damage to you (if any).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Well-Prepared" title="Well-Prepared" groups="" description="Somehow, you always seem to have the right tools or supplies close at hand.">
		<Prerequisites>Halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, when confronted with a situation that calls for a particular mundane item of equipment, you may make a Sleight of Hand check with a DC of 10 plus the item&apos;s cost in gold pieces to &#x201C;happen&#x201D; to have such an item on your person. For example, having a crowbar would be DC 12, whereas a flask of acid would be DC 20. The item must be something you can easily carry&#x2014;if you are on foot and have only a backpack, for example, you could not have a large iron cauldron. You cannot have magical items using this feat, nor can you have specific items, such as the key to a particular door. If you are stripped of your equipment or possessions, you lose the benefits of this feat until you have at least a day to resupply and &#x201C;acquire&#x201D; new items. You must pay for these items normally.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Well-Trained" title="Well-Trained" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="This horse knows more tricks and is more loyal to its rider than most mounts.">
		<Prerequisites>Horse.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>This horse automatically knows the tricks included in the combat riding trick (attack, come, defend, down, guard, and heel), and these tricks do not count against the normal maximum number of tricks the horse can learn. The Handle Animal DC to get the horse to perform a trick is reduced by 5, and the DC to teach the horse new tricks is reduced by 5.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wheeling Charge" title="Wheeling Charge" groups="Combat, Local" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Mounted Combat, Ride-By Attack, Ride 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are mounted and use the charge action, your mount can make one turn of up to 90 degrees as part of the move, as long as each part of the move is at least 10 feet. You may make an attack during any part of this move. Your total movement for the round can&apos;t exceed double your mounted speed. Allied creatures do not impede your charge, though you cannot attack from or end your move in an ally&apos;s space.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You cannot turn when making a charge.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Whip Crack" title="Whip Crack" groups="Combat" description="You move an opponent and use his momentum to send him reeling across the battlefield.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Reposition, base attack bonus +3 or monk level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully reposition an opponent, its movement need not remain within your reach, though once the opponent leaves your reach, its remaining movement must be in a straight line. This movement doesn&apos;t provoke attacks of opportunity unless you have the Greater Reposition feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The target of a reposition combat maneuver must remain within your reach at all times during its movement, except for the final 5 feet of movement, which can be to a space adjacent to your reach.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Whip Mastery" title="Whip Mastery" groups="Combat" description="Your superior expertise with this weapon does not provoke attacks of opportunity from your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus (whip), base attack bonus +2.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You no longer provoke attacks of opportunity when attacking with a whip. You can deal lethal damage with a whip, although you can still deal nonlethal damage when you want. Further, you can deal damage with a whip despite a creature&apos;s armor bonus or natural armor bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Attacking with a whip provokes attacks of opportunity as if you used a ranged weapon. A whip deals no damage to a creature that has an armor bonus of +1 or natural armor bonus of +3.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Whip-Slinger" title="Whip-Slinger" groups="Combat" description="You can use your sling as a sap to make attacks of opportunity.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficient with sling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a sling, double sling, or halfling sling staff, you threaten areas around you as normal and can make attacks of opportunity with the sling into these threatened areas. The sling deals 1d4 nonlethal bludgeoning damage (1d6 for a Medium wielder), threatens a critical hit on a 20, and deals &#xD7;2 damage on a critical hit. If the sling isn&apos;t loaded with ammunition when you make an attack of opportunity, you take a -4 penalty on the attack roll.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Slings and double slings are ranged weapons, do not threaten areas, and cannot make attacks of opportunity. A halfling sling staff can be used as a simple melee weapon that deals bludgeoning damage equal to that of a club its size; as a melee weapon, it threatens areas normally and its wielder can make attacks of opportunity with it.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Whirling Hold" title="Whirling Hold" groups="Combat" description="You lift your grappled foe from the ground and violently spin and disorient him.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you succeed at a combat maneuver check to maintain a grapple, instead of choosing to damage, move, pin, or tie up your opponent, you can lift and rapidly spin your opponent. At the end of the spin, you can place the opponent in any square adjacent to you. The opponent is sickened for a number of rounds equal to your Strength or Dexterity modifier, whichever is higher.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Whirlwind Attack" title="Whirlwind Attack" groups="Combat" description="You can strike out at every foe within reach.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Int 13, Combat Expertise, Dodge, Mobility, Spring Attack, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the full-attack action, you can give up your regular attacks and instead make one melee attack at your highest base attack bonus against each opponent within reach. You must make a separate attack roll against each opponent.</p>
			<p>When you use the Whirlwind Attack feat, you also forfeit any bonus or extra attacks granted by other feats, spells, or abilities.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wicked Valor" title="Wicked Valor" groups="" description="The fiendish blood that courses through your body causes your wounds to heal faster than usual.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 15, Diehard, Endurance, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you regain hit points by resting, you heal double the normal amount of damage. This feat does not stack with items or effects that also affect the amount of damage you recover from while resting. This feat only functions with a full night&apos;s rest; complete bed rest is not affected by this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Widen Spell" title="Widen Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can cast your spells so that they occupy a larger space.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can alter a burst, emanation, or spread-shaped spell to increase its area. Any numeric measurements of the spell&apos;s area increase by 100%.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +3 (a widened spell uses up a spell slot three levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
			<p>Spells that do not have an area of one of these four sorts are not affected by this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wild Growth Channel" title="Wild Growth Channel" groups="" description="When you channel positive energy, you cause vines to grow and ensnare enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel positive energy class feature, Plant domain.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>By expending two additional uses when you channel energy, you cause the ground in the area of effect to erupt in a growth of vines. You create a number of vine growths (AC 10, 5 hp) equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). Each growth of vines occupies 1 5-foot square of your choosing. As an immediate action when you use this ability, and again as a free action at the start of your turn, you can command the vines to wrap around the legs of a creature occupying the square. The creature must succeed at a Reflex save (DC = 10 + half your class level + your Charisma modifier) or become rooted to the spot. The vines last a number of rounds equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). The ground must be composed of a material able to support plant life (such as soil).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wild Growth Hex" title="Wild Growth Hex" groups="" description="Hexing your enemies causes them to be ensnared in tangling vines.">
		<Prerequisites>Hex class feature; summer, thorns, or woodlands patron.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you gain this feat, choose one hex that you can use to affect no more than one opponent. If the target of your hex fails its saving throw to resist your hex, the square it occupies becomes overgrown with thorny plants that count as difficult terrain. A creature moving in or out of the square must succeed at a Reflex save or Acrobatics check (DC = 10 + half your level + your Charisma modifier) or take 1d6 points of piercing damage and immediately end its movement. For every 5 by which the target fails its save against your hex, you can create 1 additional square of difficult terrain adjacent to any square the target occupies. The difficult terrain lasts a number of rounds equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). The ground must be composed of a material able to support plant life (such as soil).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wild Speech" title="Wild Speech" groups="" description="You speak with the tongue of men and beasts.">
		<Prerequisites>Druid level 6th, wild shape class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using wild shape to take the form in which you cannot speak (such as an animal), you are able to speak normally in any language you know. This allows you to cast spells with verbal components, speak command words, and activate spell completion and spell trigger items. However, it does not give you the ability to cast spells requiring somatic components unless you also have the Natural Spell feat, or cast spells with material components merged into your form.</p>
			<p>When using wild shape to take the form of an animal, you may use speak with animals to communicate with animals of your assumed form. This is a spell-like ability with a caster level equal to your druid level, and you may use it for a number of minutes per day equal to your druid level. These minutes do not have to be consecutive, but must be used in one-minute increments.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wild Vigor" title="Wild Vigor" groups="" description="The forces of nature bolster your vitality when you use wild shape.">
		<Prerequisites>Wild shape class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A number of times per day equal to your Wisdom bonus (minimum 1), when you use wild shape, you can gain a number of temporary hit points equal to your base attack bonus. These temporary hit points last for the duration of the wild shape or until they are lost.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wilding" title="Wilding" groups="" description="You were touched by nature at an early age and share a kinship with wild creatures. Your body might bear animalistic features, such as bestial ears or a tail, or your presence may be subtly unlike that of others.">
		<Prerequisites>Any neutral alignment, must be taken at 1st level.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the druid&apos;s wild empathy ability, using your character level as your druid level. If you have one or more levels in a class that grants wild empathy, you gain an additional +3 bonus on wild empathy checks. You are treated as an animal for the purpose of harmful mind-affecting effects that target animals (such as charm animal).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A character who has this feat can select the Animal Soul or Aspect of the Beast feats without meeting the prerequisites.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wilding Mind" title="Wilding Mind" groups="" description="You can repress your conscious mind in favor of a primal state that helps you resist mental influence.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Wilding.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you fail a saving throw against a fear or mind-affecting effect, you can take 1d3 points of Intelligence damage as an immediate action and reroll the saving throw. This damage cannot be reduced or avoided in any way. You must take the new result, even if it is worse.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wilding Senses" title="Wilding Senses" groups="" description="The wilderness speaks to you, giving you a preternatural sense of approaching danger.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Wilding.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Perception checks; this bonus increases to +4 when determining if you can act during a surprise round. If you have 10 or more ranks in Perception, this bonus increases to +4 (or +8 when determining whether you can act during a surprise round). This bonus does not stack with that granted by the Alertness feat, though Wilding Senses counts as the Alertness feat for the purpose of fulfilling feat prerequisites and prestige class requirements.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wilding Stride" title="Wilding Stride" groups="" description="Your wild-hearted drive and honed physique allow you to move with great swiftness.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Wilding.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your base speed increases by 10 feet. This does not stack with the fast movement class feature or similar effects, unless that class feature or effect provides an enhancement bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wilding Strike" title="Wilding Strike" groups="Combat" description="Filled with the might of nature, you need no weapons of steel or wood. Your fists and feet are as potent as any creation of the forge.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, Wilding.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The damage die of your unarmed strikes increases to 1d6 (or 1d4 if you are Small). This does not stack with any other effects that increase the damage die of your unarmed strikes, including levels in classes such as monk. Increases to your actual size category (such as enlarge person) still increase your damage die as normal.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Willing Accomplice" title="Willing Accomplice" groups="" description="Your well-placed support can aid friends and allies in maintaining their most precious secrets.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Bluff 3 ranks, Sense Motive 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can attempt a Bluff check to aid another&apos;s Disguise check. In addition, when attempting such a check to aid a vigilante ally in maintaining that ally&apos;s social identity, a successful check grants that ally a +5 bonus instead of the normal +2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wind Stance" title="Wind Stance" groups="Combat" description="Your erratic movements make it difficult for enemies to pinpoint your location.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Dodge, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you move more than 5 feet this turn, you gain 20% concealment for 1 round against ranged attacks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wingclipper" title="Wingclipper" groups="Combat" description="Your attacks can prevent winged opponents from flying.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you confirm a critical hit against an opponent that uses wings to fly, you can forgo the extra critical damage to instead prevent it from flying for a number of rounds equal to twice the critical multiplier of your attack. Opponents that are flying at the time of the critical effect must succeed at a DC 20 Fly check to avoid taking falling damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wings of Air" title="Wings of Air" groups="Sylph" description="The winds lift you, carrying you where you want to go.">
		<Prerequisites>Airy Step, character level 9th, sylph.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your bonus on saves against effects with the air or electricity descriptors and effects that deal electricity damage increases to +4. In addition, you gain a supernatural fly speed equal to your base speed (good maneuverability). You may only fly with this ability when wearing light armor or no armor.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wings of the Androsphinx" title="Wings of the Androsphinx" groups="Combat" description="Hammer-masters developed a fighting style based on certain attributes of sphinxes, focusing particularly on how these creatures can stand steadfast even in the face of imminent onslaught or make their own deadly assaults at a moment's notice.">
You can reshape the kinetic energy of foes&apos; charges.
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Reposition, base attack bonus +1 or monk level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to AC against charge attacks.</p>
			<p>If a creature charges you and fails its attack roll, as an immediate action you can attempt a reposition combat maneuver to reposition that foe. If you use a readied action to attack a creature charging you, you can roll to attack and then attempt to reposition that creature as a free action before it resolves its charge attack.</p>
			<p>Note: A monk can take any of these feats as bonus feats at the indicated levels. To benefit from the feats, monks must have both hands free and capable of delivering an unarmed strike.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Winter's Strike" title="Winter's Strike" groups="Combat" description="Your attacks afflict your foes with the relentless fatigue of a winter storm.">
		<Prerequisites>Nature Magic or the ability to cast druid or ranger spells; Vital Strike, Knowledge (nature) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A number of times per day equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1), when you use Vital Strike (or Improved Vital Strike or Greater Vital Strike), your strike saps the strength of your opponent. The creature hit must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier) or become fatigued for a number of rounds equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1). You can choose to use this ability as a free action after you hit the target with the attack. This is a supernatural ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Witch Knife" title="Witch Knife" groups="" description="You empower your witch spells by incorporating the use of a special ceremonial knife during your castings.">
		<Prerequisites>Witch class.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Each day, when you prepare your spells, you can select a masterwork or magical dagger, transforming it into a witch knife, which serves as an additional focus component for witch patron spells. Add +1 to the DC of all your patron spells.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Witchbreaker" title="Witchbreaker" groups="Combat" description="You are trained to be resilient to and disrupt the magic of hags and witches.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against the hexes, spells, spell-like abilities, and supernatural abilities of hags and witches. In addition, whenever you confirm a critical hit against a hag or a witch, any of your allies affected by a mind-affecting effect from that creature can attempt a new saving throw against the effect as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Witty Feint" title="Witty Feint" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, weapon training class feature, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully feint against an opponent in combat, instead of denying the opponent his Dexterity bonus, you may gain a dodge bonus to your AC against his attacks. This bonus is equal to your weapon training bonus for your current weapon. The bonus lasts until combat ends, you switch opponents, or you switch to a different weapon, whichever comes first.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wolf Rider" title="Wolf Rider" groups="" description="Others can keep their horses. You know that wolves are better mounts.">
		<Prerequisites>Undersized Mount or effective level 7th in the class that grants the mount or divine bond (mount) class feature; Knowledge (nature) 1 rank; mount or divine bond (mount) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can select a wolf in place of the normal mount available via your mount or divine bond (mount) class feature. In addition, Knowledge (nature) is always a class skill for you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wolf Savage" title="Wolf Savage" groups="Combat" description="You savage your foes so badly that they can become supernaturally disfigured.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 17, Improved Unarmed Strike, Wolf Style, Wolf Trip, Knowledge (nature) 9 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Wolf Style, when you deal at least 10 points of damage to a prone opponent with a natural weapon or an unarmed strike, as a swift action you can savage that creature. When you do, your opponent must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + half your character level + your Wisdom modifier). If the target fails the saving throw, it takes either 1d4 Charisma damage or 1d4 Constitution damage, or it becomes fatigued (your choice). Ability score damage dealt with this ability cannot equal or exceed the victim&apos;s actual ability score total.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wolf Style" title="Wolf Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="While in this style, you hamper foes that turn their backs on you.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, Knowledge (nature) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, whenever you deal at least 10 points of damage to a foe with an attack of opportunity, that foe&apos;s base speed decreases by 5 feet until the end of its next turn. For every 10 points of damage your attack deals beyond 10, the foe&apos;s base speed decreases by an additional 5 feet. If the penalty meets or exceeds the total base speed of the foe, you can attempt to trip the foe as a free action after the attack of opportunity is resolved.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wolf Trip" title="Wolf Trip" groups="Combat" description="You have studied the manner in which wolves bring down their prey.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 15, Improved Unarmed Strike, Wolf Style, Knowledge (nature) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Wolf Style, you gain a +2 bonus when you attempt a trip combat maneuver as part of an attack of opportunity. Whenever you successfully trip a creature, as a free action you can choose an available space that is both adjacent to you and the creature&apos;s original space for the tripped creature to land prone in.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wood Crafter" title="Wood Crafter" groups="" description="Eschewing the use of metals in your craft, you excel at crafting armor from wood.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (armor) 3 ranks, Knowledge (nature) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 bonus on Craft (armor) checks to create armor and shields from wood or special materials containing wood (such as darkwood). If you succeed at the check by 5 or more, you decrease the cost to make the item by 10%.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Woodland Wraith" title="Woodland Wraith" groups="Combat" description="You put the terrain between yourself and your opponents to avoid attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Dodge, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you take two actions to move or a withdrawal action in a turn while starting or ending your movement in either naturally occurring difficult terrain (bushes, brambles, etc.) or a space with a natural object providing at least partial cover (a tree, rock, etc.), you gain concealment until you attack, until you move out of that space, or until the end of your next turn, whichever occurs first.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Word of Healing" title="Word of Healing" groups="" description="Using the same divine energy as your lay on hands ability, you can heal others at a distance.">
		<Prerequisites>Lay on hands class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may use your lay on hands to heal another creature at a range of 30 feet as a standard action that does not provoke an attack of opportunity. You must be able to speak and have a free hand to use this ability. The target heals half the amount they would have healed if you had touched them, but gains the benefits of your mercies as normal.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Worst Case Jinx" title="Worst Case Jinx" groups="" description="Your jinxes hinder beneficial spells.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (arcana) 5 ranks, Halfling Jinx alternate racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Beneficial variable effects on a jinxed target (such as aid, cure spells, false life, the variable ability damage cured by lesser restoration, and so on) always result in the minimum possible amount for the effect. For example, a 5th-level cleric casting cure serious wounds on the target only heals 8 hit points (the minimum for 3d8+5).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wounded Paw Gambit" title="Wounded Paw Gambit" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="Your enemy sees you as an easy mark, but doesn't notice your allies poised to shoot.">
		<Prerequisites>Broken Wing Gambit, Bluff 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use Broken Wing Gambit and an opponent attacks you as a result, each ally who has this feat and is within 30 feet of that opponent can attempt a ranged attack against it as an immediate action. The ally&apos;s ranged weapon must be in hand, loaded, and ready to be fired or thrown in order to make this attack possible.</p>
			<p>An ally who has this feat and Broken Wing Gambit can instead use Broken Wing Gambit to attempt an attack of opportunity against the foe, but cannot attempt both that attack of opportunity and this ranged attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wrest Charge" title="Wrest Charge" groups="" description="You can extract a charge from otherwise depleted technology.">
		<Prerequisites>Disable Device 5 ranks, Knowledge (engineering) 5 ranks</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With a successful DC 20 Disable Device check, you can jury-rig a depleted (but not destroyed) battery so it provides 1 more charge. Using this charge or failing your check by 5 or more permanently depletes the battery. You can attempt the same check to add 1 last charge to a discharged piece of timeworn technology. Regardless of the outcome, no other attempts can be made, even by another person. Using this feat takes 1 minute. You can attempt to wrest a charge as a move action by taking a &#x2013;10 penalty on your check. This feat does not stack with the charge cycling deed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wrist Grab" title="Wrist Grab" groups="Combat" description="When an enemy overextends to attack you, you quickly catch its arm and knock its weapon loose.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Int 13, Combat Expertise, Combat Reflexes, Improved Disarm, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When an opponent&apos;s attack misses you by 5 or more, you can attempt a disarm combat maneuver check against that foe as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wyvern Fury Style" title="Wyvern Fury Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You can combine sweeping attacks with a whip and quick stabs with a blade, imitating a wyvern's powerful bite and tail tipped with a stinger.">
		<Prerequisites>Exotic Weapon Proficiency (whip), Acrobatics 3 ranks, brawler&apos;s flurry class feature or flurry of blows class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you can make attacks with a dagger, punching dagger, scorpion whip, spiked gauntlet, or whip when using a flurry of blows or brawler&apos;s flurry. Only one of these attacks can be made with a whip or scorpion whip.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can make a flurry of blows attack using unarmed strikes and monk weapons, and you can make a brawler&apos;s flurry attack using unarmed strikes, weapons from the close fighter weapon group, and monk weapons.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wyvern Sting" title="Wyvern Sting" groups="Combat" description="You can use your whip like a wyvern's sting, forcing foes to give it their undivided attention.">
		<Prerequisites>Exotic Weapon Proficiency (whip), Wyvern Fury Style, Acrobatics 6 ranks, brawler&apos;s flurry class feature or flurry of blows class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Wyvern Fury Style, if you successfully attack a foe with a whip or scorpion whip, as a swift action you can choose one ally. Until the beginning of your next turn, that ally can leave spaces threatened by that foe without provoking an attack of opportunity from the foe.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Wyvern Wing" title="Wyvern Wing" groups="Combat" description="Like a wyvern on the wing, you command a fluid style that enables you to make attacks while moving.">
		<Prerequisites>Exotic Weapon Proficiency (whip), Wyvern Fury Style, Wyvern Sting, Acrobatics 10 ranks, brawler&apos;s flurry class feature or flurry of blows class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using the Wyvern Fury Style feat, if you use flurry of blows or brawler&apos;s flurry and take a 5-foot step, you can take an additional 5-foot step. You can take this extra 5-foot step only between two attacks in your flurry, but you can take both your 5-foot steps consecutively without making an attack between them.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When you take a 5-foot step, you are allowed to move only once.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Xenoglossy" title="Xenoglossy" groups="" description="People everywhere share a common tongue; they just don't always remember it.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Linguistics 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With a successful DC 25 Linguistics check, you can speak with a single individual with whom you share no common languages. You cannot take 10 on this check, nor can anyone aid you. You believe you are speaking your native language, and the listener believes you are speaking its native language; however, to everyone else able to hear you, you sound like you are speaking gibberish. Creatures that have truespeech or that are under the effects of tongues can understand Xenoglossy, and other creatures who succeed at a DC 25 Linguistics check can pick up the gist of what you are saying.</p>
			<p>Xenoglossy lasts for the length of the conversation or for 1 minute per level, whichever is shorter. You can use Xenoglossy again to continue a longer conversation, and you gain a +2 on Linguistics checks to use Xenoglossy to communicate with someone with whom you previously communicated using this feat. If you fail a Xenoglossy check, you can&apos;t use the Xenoglossy feat to attempt further communication with that creature until you gain additional ranks in Linguistics.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Yai-Mimic Spell" title="Yai-Mimic Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You have studied the magical nature of giant oni and can use your spells to imitate their esoteric features.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 15, Still Spell.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can modify a ray spell to issue from the center of your forehead, where the third eye would be on a yai. This spell doesn&apos;t require somatic components.</p>
			<p>When the spell is cast, you gain regeneration 1 for a number of rounds equal to the original level of the spell. This regeneration can&apos;t regrow lost body parts or reattach severed limbs. Fire or acid damage suppresses this regeneration for 1 round, which counts against the total duration of the regeneration effect.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +3 (a yai-mimic spell uses up a spell slot 3 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.) </p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Zealous Mind" title="Zealous Mind" groups="" description="You are so steadfast in the principles of your alignment, even magic has difficult swaying you.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will, Unimpeachable Honor, lawful alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are under the effect of a charm or compulsion effect cast by or coming from a source with a chaotic alignment or an alignment on the good and evil axis opposite of your alignment (evil if you are good, and good if you are evil) you gain a +2 on any saving throw or opposed Charisma check to break free from the effect. This bonus stacks with itself and with the bonus granted by Unimpeachable Honor.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
</Bundles>
