<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Bundles>
	<Bundle id="Fabulist" title="Fabulist" groups="Grit" description="You enjoy telling tall tales and gain confidence when others believe them.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Gunslinger feat or grit class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on Perform (act, comedy, oratory, and sing) skill checks, and Perform is a class skill for you. In addition, each time you make a successful Bluff check to convince someone of a far-fetched or impossible story, you regain 1 grit point. Successfully lying to a friendly or helpful creature, or a creature that has fewer Hit Dice than half your character level, doesn&apos;t restore grit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fabulous Figments" title="Fabulous Figments" groups="Mythic" description="Your illusions are astonishingly realistic.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Focus (illusion).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Non-mythic creatures can&apos;t identify your illusion spells with Spellcraft, including checks attempted as part of arcane sight, detect magic, or similar effects. When mythic creatures attempt to identify your illusions, add your tier to the DC of those Spellcraft checks. Mythic creatures informed by their allies that one of your illusions isn&apos;t real gain only a +2 bonus on their Will saves to disbelieve. Non-mythic creatures gain no bonus to disbelieve.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Faerie's Strike" title="Faerie's Strike" groups="Combat" description="Ephemeral wisps of nature spirits dance about those you strike.">
		<Prerequisites>Nature Magic or the ability to cast druid or ranger spells; Vital Strike, Knowledge (nature) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Vital Strike (or Improved Vital Strike or Greater Vital Strike), the creature you hit with the attack must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier) or be illuminated as if by faerie fire for 1 minute. You can use this benefit a number of times per day equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Falling Water Gambit" title="Falling Water Gambit" groups="Combat" description="You have integrated both the Roaring Falls and Shrouded Lake techniques of swordplay into a seamless union.">
		<Prerequisites>Dueling Disciple, Duelist of the Falls, Duelist of the Shroud, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword), base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When attacking a creature denied its Dexterity bonus to AC because of your successful feint, you increase the threat range of your dueling sword by 1 (typically to 18-20/x2), and gain a +2 bonus on attack rolls to confirm critical hits. After you make a dueling dodge or succeed at a dueling parry during a duel, you can make an attack of opportunity against the foe who attacked you if that foe is shaken, frightened, or panicked. To gain these benefits, you must be wielding only a dueling sword (not using a shield, an off-hand weapon, armor spikes, unarmed strikes, or natural weapons).</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: By spending 4 stamina points, you gain the ability to attempt a dueling dodge or a dueling parry against attacks made by a shaken, frightened, or panicked opponent, even if you aren&apos;t participating in a duel.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="False Opening" title="False Opening" groups="Combat" description="When you make a ranged attack while threatened, you can fool your opponent into thinking he has an opening.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Dodge, Close Quarters Thrower or Point-Blank Master, Weapon Focus with selected ranged weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a ranged weapon or a thrown weapon. When you make a ranged attack using that weapon, you can choose to provoke an attack of opportunity from one or more opponents who threaten you. You gain a +4 dodge bonus against such attacks. An opponent that makes such an attack and misses you loses his Dexterity bonus to AC against you until the end of your turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="False Trail" title="False Trail" groups="" description="You create a false trail to throw off pursuers, enabling you to increase your lead on those following you or make them lose your trail entirely.">
		<Prerequisites>Survival 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create a false trail in the wilderness via a combination of misleading footprints, discarded items, torn scraps of clothing, and other signs. When you create a false trail, you determine the direction it leads. A creature tracking you must succeed at a Perception or Survival check (DC = 10 + half your character level + your Wisdom modifier) to determine the trail is fake when first encountering it. On a success, the creature can continue to track you as normal. The effect of a failure to identify the trail as false depends on the time and effort spent making it.</p>
			<p>Quick: A quick false trail takes 10 minutes to complete. A creature that fails to identify the trail as false follows it for 1d4&#xD7;1,000 feet.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A normal false trail takes 1 hour to complete. A creature that fails to identify the trail as false follows it for 1d4 miles.</p>
			<p>Elaborate: An elaborate false trail takes 4 hours to complete. A creature that fails to identify the trail as false follows it for 2d6 miles.</p>
			<p>After a creature that fails to identify a false trail follows it for the determined distance, it can attempt another Perception or Survival check with a +5 bonus. On a success, the creature realizes it&apos;s following a false trail and can continue to track you as normal after backtracking to the start of the false trail (or wherever you diverged from the false trail). On a failure, the creature continues to move in the direction of the false trail for an additional mile. After each mile, it can attempt a new check with a cumulative +5 bonus.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Familiar Bond" title="Familiar Bond" groups="" description="You have learned a ritual that allows you to gain a familiar.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a familiar, as the wizard arcane bond class feature. You do not gain the special ability the familiar normally grants its master, and the familiar does not gain the deliver touch spells, scry on familiar, share spells, speak with animals of its kind, or spell resistance special abilities. Otherwise, your total Hit Dice are used as your wizard level for determining the familiar&apos;s abilities.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have (or later gain) levels in a class that grants a familiar, whenever you select a familiar, you can either base your familiar&apos;s abilities on your total Hit Dice per this feat (including the restrictions on its special abilities), or choose to apply only your levels in classes that grant a familiar (and thus gain all the special abilities that familiar would grant based on those class levels). You can never have more than one familiar.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Familiar Focus" title="Familiar Focus" groups="" description="You are closely connected to your master's powers.">
		<Prerequisites>Familiar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever your master targets you with a harmless spell or spell-like ability, your master&apos;s effective caster level for the effect is increased by 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Feats that are meant for familiars can be switched out for a familiar&apos;s default feats (as listed in the familiar&apos;s statistics) if the familiar meets the prerequisites. Such feat replacements must be made when the PC first acquires a new familiar, and-like all new feats from supplemental sources-the new feats should be approved by the GM before being integrated into play.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Familiar Spell" title="Familiar Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can imbue your familiar with a spell.">
		<Prerequisites>Spellcaster with familiar class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can transfer a prepared spell to your familiar, allowing the familiar to cast that spell at a later time. Variables that rely on caster level function according to your caster level, not your familiar&apos;s Hit Dice, though your familiar&apos;s Intelligence may influence how precisely it can follow your instructions on how to use these spells.</p>
			<p>Your familiar must be able to speak to cast spells with a verbal component (the ability to speak with its master or creatures of its kind is insufficient). Your familiar must be carrying any material or focus components necessary, unless the materials cost less than 1 gp and the spell is prepared with Eschew Materials. Attack rolls use your familiar&apos;s ability scores. A familiar spell counts against the number of spells you may prepare for as long as your familiar retains the spell. Once your familiar casts a retained spell, you can prepare a new spell in that slot the next time you prepare spells.</p>
			<p>A familiar spell uses up a spell slot 3 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level. Your familiar can store a number of spell levels (including this modifier) equal to your caster level, but no spell&apos;s adjusted level can exceed half your caster level.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are a spontaneous caster, you must select a specific spell with which to imbue your familiar; you cannot imbue your familiar with an open spell slot.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Famine Tolerance" title="Famine Tolerance" groups="" description="You can abide much longer periods without feeding, and enjoy increased benefits from a meal.">
		<Prerequisites>Moroi or nosferatu.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can go without feeding for a number of days equal to twice your Hit Dice before having to make hunger saves. When you use your blood drain ability, you gain twice the normal amount of temporary hit points for each feeding.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat is only for campaigns using the optional undead hunger rules from Pathfinder Player Companion: Blood of Night.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Far Shot" title="Far Shot" groups="Combat" description="You are more accurate at longer ranges.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You only suffer a -1 penalty per full range increment between you and your target when using a ranged weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You suffer a -2 penalty per full range increment between you and your target.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Far-Roaming Familiar" title="Far-Roaming Familiar" groups="" description="Distance can't sever the bond between you and your familiar.">
		<Prerequisites>Intelligence 13, must have a familiar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You retain your empathic link to your familiar regardless of distance, though lead blocks the link at distances greater than 1 mile (similar to the way lead blocks detect magic effects).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fascination Jinx" title="Fascination Jinx" groups="" description="If you jinx an already fascinated creature, it doesn't fully recover until the jinx ends.">
		<Prerequisites>Bardic performance class feature, Halfling Jinx alternate racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you jinx a creature under the effect of a bard&apos;s fascinate ability, it also takes a &#x2013;10 penalty on initiative checks while affected by the jinx. A creature under the effect of your fascinate ability has a &#x2013;2 penalty on its save against your jinx.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fast Crawl" title="Fast Crawl" groups="" description="You are skilled at moving while prone.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>While prone, you can move at half speed. This movement provokes attacks of opportunity as normal. You can take a 5-foot step while crawling. This benefit does not stack with the rogue crawl talent.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can crawl 5 feet as a move action. You cannot take a 5-foot step while crawling.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fast Drinker" title="Fast Drinker" groups="" description="You swiftly guzzle spirits to draw forth ki.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 18, drunken ki class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Drinking strong alcohol to gain temporary ki, takes a swift action rather than a standard action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fast Empathy" title="Fast Empathy" groups="" description="Your empathic attunement to nature connects you swiftly with bestial minds.">
		<Prerequisites>Handle Animal 5 ranks, wild empathy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Using wild empathy is a standard action for you.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Using wild empathy requires 1 minute.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fast Healer" title="Fast Healer" groups="" description="You benefit greatly from your healing, be it from spells or natural healing.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Diehard, Endurance.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you regain hit points by resting or through magical healing, you recover additional hit points equal to half your Constitution modifier (minimum +1).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fast Learner" title="Fast Learner" groups="Human" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you gain a level in a favored class, you gain both +1 hit point and +1 skill rank instead of choosing either one or the other benefit or you can choose an alternate class reward.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fatiguing Stare" title="Fatiguing Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your painful stare fatigues your opponent.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 7th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When a target takes damage from your painful stare, it must succeed at a Fortitude saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or become fatigued for 1 round. This can&apos;t cause the target to become exhausted, even if the target is already fatigued.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Favored Animal Focus" title="Favored Animal Focus" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="Your companion is unusually comfortable wearing another (metaphorical) skin.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion class feature, animal focus class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one animal focus. When you apply that animal focus to your animal companion, the benefits increase by one step. For example, if you are 6th level and choose the bear animal focus, then when you apply the animal focus to your animal companion, it gains a +4 enhancement bonus to Constitution instead of +2.</p>
			<p>If you are 15th level or higher, when you apply your chosen animal focus to your companion, it gains the corresponding ability listed below.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Each time you take this feat, you must select a new animal focus.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Favored Defense" title="Favored Defense" groups="" description="Your cunning is your shield against your quarry's attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of your favored enemy types. You add half your favored enemy bonus to your CMD and as a dodge bonus to AC when attacked by a favored enemy.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take this feat, it applies to a new favored enemy type.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Favored Enemy Spellcasting" title="Favored Enemy Spellcasting" groups="" description="Your spells are more effective against creatures that you especially abhor.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you select this feat, choose a creature type or a humanoid subtype from the ranger favored enemies table. When creatures of the chosen type attempt saving throws against your spells, they treat the spells&apos; DCs as 1 higher. If you also have the favored enemy class feature and the chosen type is already a favored enemy of yours, such creatures treat your spells&apos; DCs as 2 higher.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you do, it applies to a different creature type.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Favored Judgment" title="Favored Judgment" groups="" description="Your judgment against a particular type of creature is particularly harsh.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, judgment class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select a favored race from the ranger&apos;s favored enemies chart. Any sacred or profane bonus you gain from a judgment is 1 higher for attacks you make against or take from creatures that match the selected favored enemy.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a different favored enemy.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fear Eater" title="Fear Eater" groups="" description="You eat the fear of others, freeing them from its effects.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Iron Will, have no immunity to fear effects.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can remove a fear effect from another creature by touching it. The fear effect is transferred from that creature to you, with the same remaining duration. If the fear effect has varying effects depending on the target (such as the effects of cause fear depending on the target&apos;s Hit Dice), it has the effect it had on the original creature or the effect it would have on you, whichever is more severe. When you choose to accept another creature&apos;s fear, you don&apos;t receive any saving throw, spell resistance, or other defenses you would normally have against the fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fearless Aura" title="Fearless Aura" groups="" description="Your aura of courage becomes more potent, as your steadfast resolve is also manifested by your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Aura of courage class feature, caster level 8th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your aura of courage expands to a 20-foot-radius emanation. Allies within the aura are immune to fear effects. </p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The aura of courage affects each ally within 10 feet, and grants a +4 morale bonus on saving throws against fear effects.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fearless Curiosity" title="Fearless Curiosity" groups="Human" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on saving throws against effects with the emotion descriptor. In addition, for any round in which you begin your turn affected by a fear effect, you gain a new save at the beginning of your turn to reduce the severity of the fear effect, from panicked to frightened, frightened to shaken, and shaken to unaffected.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fearsome Finish" title="Fearsome Finish" groups="Combat" description="When you slay enemies, you frighten other opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidating Prowess, worshiper of an evil deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Upon reducing an enemy to 0 or fewer hit points, for the remaining duration of the combat encounter, you gain a +4 bonus on any Intimidate checks made to demoralize opponents who can see both you and the opponent you dropped.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fearsome Spell" title="Fearsome Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells inspire great fear in those harmed by them.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When a creature takes damage from a fearsome spell, if that creature failed its save against the spell, it becomes shaken for a number of rounds equal to the spell&apos;s original level. If the spell doesn&apos;t allow a save, creatures harmed by it can attempt a Will save (against the same DC the spell would have if it did allow a save) to negate the shaken effect. If the spell effect already causes creatures to become shaken, on a failed save, add the duration of this metamagic effect to the duration of the shaken condition imposed by the spell. A fearsome spell can&apos;t cause a creature to become frightened, even if that creature is already shaken.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (a fearsome spell uses up a spell slot 2 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feign Curse" title="Feign Curse" groups="" description="You can fool others into believing you have ensorcelled them.">
		<Prerequisites>Deceitful, Bluff 5 ranks, Spellcraft 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can feign placing a curse on a target. The target must attempt a Sense Motive or Spellcraft check (whichever skill that target has a higher bonus with) against a DC equal to 15 + your number of ranks in Bluff + your Charisma modifier, with a bonus on his skill check equal to any conditional bonus he has on saving throws against hexes or curses (like from the spell hex ward). If he fails, he becomes plagued by self-doubt and second-guesses himself. For his next two attack rolls, saving throws, skill checks, or ability checks, he rolls twice and takes the lower result; for every 5 ranks of Bluff you possess beyond 5, this ability affects an additional roll. This is a mind-affecting effect, and it doesn&apos;t work if the target is immune to curses.</p>
			<p>Once you attempt to feign putting a curse on a creature, you cannot do so again against the same creature for 24 hours, and if the target succeeds at detecting your ruse, he gains a +10 bonus against future attempts.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feint Partner" title="Feint Partner" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="A little diversion is all you need to slip through your foe's defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever an ally who also has this feat successfully feints an opponent, that opponent also loses his Dexterity bonus to AC against the next attack you make against him before the end of the feinting ally&apos;s next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feinting Flurry" title="Feinting Flurry" groups="Combat" description="Your subtle flourishes mislead your enemy, tricking it into changing its footing.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, flurry of blows class feature, Combat Expertise.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using flurry of blows to make melee attacks, you can forgo your first attack to make a Bluff check to feint.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feline Grace" title="Feline Grace" groups="Catfolk" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Dexterity 13, catfolk.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to your CMD against bull rush, grapple, overrun, repositioning, and trip combat maneuvers.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Felling Escape" title="Felling Escape" groups="Combat" description="Through the use of fluid contortions and manipulations of leverage, you can throw your opponent to the ground after escaping a grapple.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Trip.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you break an opponent&apos;s grapple with a combat maneuver check or Escape Artist check, you can spend a swift action to make a trip attempt against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Felling Smash" title="Felling Smash" groups="Combat" description="You commit all your focus to a devastating blow, trying to crush your opponent to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Str 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Trip, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you use the attack action to make a single melee attack at your highest base attack bonus while using Power Attack and you hit an opponent, you can spend a swift action to attempt a trip combat maneuver against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fencing Grace" title="Fencing Grace" groups="Combat" description="Your dashing style and fluid rapier forms allow you to use agility rather than brute force to fell your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (rapier).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a rapier one-handed, you can add your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier to that weapon&apos;s damage. The rapier must be one appropriate for your size. You do not gain this benefit while fighting with two weapons or using flurry of blows, or anytime another hand is otherwise occupied.</p>
			<p>In addition, if you have the panache class feature, you gain a +2 bonus to your CMD against attempts to disarm you of your rapier while you have at least 1 panache point.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feral Combat Training" title="Feral Combat Training" groups="Combat" description="You were taught a style of martial arts that relies on the natural weapons from your racial ability or class feature.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Weapon Focus with selected natural weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of your natural weapons. While using the selected natural weapon, you can apply the effects of feats that have Improved Unarmed Strike as a prerequisite.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are a monk, you can use the selected natural weapon with your flurry of blows class feature.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feral Grace" title="Feral Grace" groups="Animal Companion Feat; Combat" description="The animal's grace and agility are honed for battle, making it a deadly combatant.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Finesse, base attack bonus +3, animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of the animal companion&apos;s natural attack. When the animal companion makes a melee attack with the chosen natural attack using its Dexterity bonus on attack rolls and its Strength bonus on damage rolls, it adds 1/4 of its Hit Dice as a bonus on damage rolls. This bonus damage doesn&apos;t increase or decrease based upon whether the natural attack is a primary or secondary natural attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can select this feat multiple times. Its effects don&apos;t stack. Each time you select this feat, choose a different natural attack to apply its benefit to.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Action" title="Ferocious Action" groups="Orc" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Ferocity racial trait, orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you fall to 0 hit points or fewer, you lose 2 hit points each round, but you are not staggered. If you are in a rage (such as that caused by the barbarian rage class feature), you instead only lose 1 hit point per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Beast" title="Ferocious Beast" groups="Animal Companion Feat; Combat" description="Through training or natural ability, the animal is skilled at unnerving its enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidate 1 rank, animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The animal companion uses half its master&apos;s class level (minimum 1) in place of its Charisma bonus on Intimidate checks to demoralize an opponent, as well as on Intimidate checks to use the Antagonize feat. In addition, the animal companion can use Intimidate to demoralize an opponent as a move action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>An animal companion can&apos;t take both Ferocious Beast and Intimidating Prowess.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Feint" title="Ferocious Feint" groups="Animal Companion Feat; Combat" description="Through training or inborn ability, the animal is naturally skilled at feinting against its foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The animal companion uses half its master&apos;s class level (minimum 1) in place of its Charisma bonus on Bluff checks to feint an opponent. In addition, the animal companion can use Bluff to feint an opponent as a move action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Horde" title="Ferocious Horde" groups="Teamwork" description="Seeing a fellow orc bleed makes you fight harder.">
		<Prerequisites>Orc, ferocity racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are at or below half of your full hit points and an orc ally within 30 feet who also has this feat is at or below half of her full hit points, you gain a +2 morale bonus on attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Resolve" title="Ferocious Resolve" groups="Orc/Half-Orc" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, half-orc, orc ferocity racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the ferocity universal monster ability, allowing you to continue fighting at negative hit points. When using this ability, you gain a +2 bonus on Intimidate checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A half-orc with the orc ferocity racial trait can fight for 1 more round after he is brought below 0 hit points.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Summons" title="Ferocious Summons" groups="Orc/Half-Orc" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Augment Summoning, Spell Focus (conjuration), half-orc or orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Creatures you summon gain the ferocity universal monster ability.</p>
			<p>How does this ability work if a summoned creature disappears when it reaches 0 hp?</p>
			<p>The summoned creature does not disappear at 0 hp, instead it disappears when killed (when its current hp get to a negative amount equal to its Constitution score).</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Tenacity" title="Ferocious Tenacity" groups="Combat, Orc/Half-Orc" description="You spit in the face of death.">
		<Prerequisites>Ferocity racial trait, half-orc or orc, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day when raging, if you are hit by an attack that would deal enough hit points of damage to kill you (negative hit points equal to your Constitution score), as an immediate action you may expend 1 or more rounds of rage to negate some of this damage and keep yourself alive. Each round of rage you spend reduces the attack&apos;s damage by 1 point, but cannot reduce the damage taken below 1 hit point.</p>
			<p>For example, if you are raging, have a raging Constitution score of 18, are currently at 2 hit points, and take 20 hit points of damage from a hit (which is enough to bring you to &#x2013;18 hit points, thereby killing you), you may spend 1 round of rage to reduce the damage by 1 hit point (leaving you perilously close to death at &#x2013;17 hit points); if you spend 17 rounds of rage, you reduce the damage to 1 (the minimum), leaving you with 1 hit point.Note: If this damage still makes you fall unconscious, your rage ends just like it normally would, lowering your Constitution to its normal value and reducing your hit point total as normal. Therefore, it is possible to use this feat to prevent yourself from instantly dying, yet you still die because your negative hit points exceed your normal Constitution score&#x2014;take your normal Constitution into account when deciding how many rounds of rage to spend with this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fey Foundling" title="Fey Foundling" groups="" description="You were found in the wilds as a child.">
		<Prerequisites>You may only select this feat at 1st level.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you receive magical healing, you heal an additional 2 points per die rolled. You gain a +2 bonus on all saving throws against death effects. Unfortunately, you also suffer +1 point of damage from cold iron weapons (although you can wield cold iron weapons without significant discomfort).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fey Insight" title="Fey Insight" groups="" description="You have insight into the weird, alien minds of fey and can use this knowledge to more handily negotiate with or manipulate the capricious creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13; Knowledge (nature) or Knowledge (planes) 2 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Bluff, Diplomacy, and Sense Motive skill checks when interacting with creatures of the fey type. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus gained when interacting with creatures of the fey type increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fey Performance" title="Fey Performance" groups="" description="The wind, trees, earth, and local wildlife join in on your bardic performances.">
		<Prerequisites>Bardic performance class ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can enhance your performance with nature&apos;s sights and sounds by expending an extra round of bardic performance at the start of the performance. The range of the performance increases by 30 feet. Furthermore, for the purposes of affecting blind and deaf creatures, this performance counts as having both audible and visible components. This feat doesn&apos;t function in environments devoid of animal and plant life.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fey Spell Lore" title="Fey Spell Lore" groups="" description="You have learned the treacherous spells employed by the fey.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Spellcraft 1 rank, ability to cast druid spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Add the following spells to your druid spell list at the indicated levels: 0&#x2014;dancing lights, 1st&#x2014;lesser confusion, 2nd&#x2014;charm person, 3rd&#x2014;invisibility, 4th&#x2014;bestow curse, 5th&#x2014;charm monster, 6th&#x2014;major curse, 7th&#x2014;cloak of dreams, 8th&#x2014;insanity, 9th&#x2014;irresistible dance.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fey Spell Versatility" title="Fey Spell Versatility" groups="" description="You have learned magical secrets from the fey.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Spellcraft 1 rank, ability to cast ranger spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a 1st-level spell, a 2nd-level spell, a 3rd-level spell, and a 4th-level spell from the bard, sorcerer/wizard, or witch spell list that is either from the enchantment or illusion school or a spell with the curse descriptor. Add those spells to your ranger spell list. Once chosen, these spells cannot be changed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fey-Guarded" title="Fey-Guarded" groups="" description="You have trained your mind to resist fey magicâ€”both that cast by fey creatures and that cast by other denizens of the Fey World.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (nature) or Knowledge (planes) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 morale bonus on saving throws against enchantment and illusion spells and spell-like abilities cast by creatures of the fey type.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Field Repair" title="Field Repair" groups="" description="You can repair your broken weapon or armor to serviceability even without the benefits of artisan tools.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft 4 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you are trained in a Craft skill appropriate to a broken item, you can repair that item with no raw material cost and no penalty on your Craft skill check for using improvised tools. If you spend a day, the item regains 1 hit point plus one-quarter of its original hit points. Alternatively, if the item gained the broken condition because it is a firearm that has misfired or a siege engine that suffered a mishap, or has the broken condition because it has the fragile weapon quality (or some similar quality), you can make a Craft check with the DC it takes to craft that item (see Table 2&#x2013;2, below). If the check succeeds, the item loses the broken condition.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Improvised tools impose a &#x2013;2 penalty on Craft checks. Items require raw materials to repair.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fiend Sight" title="Fiend Sight" groups="Tiefling" description="Your eyes develop keener sight in dim light and darkness.">
		<Prerequisites>Darkvision 60 ft., tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain low-light vision and your darkvision improves to 120 ft.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat twice. When you take it a second time, you gain the see in darkness universal monster ability.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fiendish Darkness" title="Fiendish Darkness" groups="" description="You can use your darkness spell-like ability more often.">
		<Prerequisites>Darkness spell-like ability, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use darkness three times per day as a spell-like ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Tieflings can use darkness once per day as a spell-like ability.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fiendish Facade" title="Fiendish Facade" groups="" description="You are easily mistaken for a member of another race. Your fiendish physical traits are normally hidden by clothing or appear to be markings of another race.">
		<Prerequisites>Must be taken at 1st level, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +5 racial bonus on Disguise checks when attempting to impersonate a particular race. You must select the race you are able to impersonate when you select this feat, and thereafter you cannot change the race you have chosen. That race must be Medium size.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fiendish Heritage" title="Fiendish Heritage" groups="" description="You possess a strong tie to your fiendish ancestors, granting you favorable abilities.">
		<Prerequisites>Tiefling, must be taken at 1st level.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your fiendish bloodline proves particularly strong, being tied to a specific race of fiends. Rather than taking a tiefling&apos;s usual racial ability modifiers, choose one of the tiefling heritages presented on Table: Variant Tiefling Heritages.</p>
			<p>In addition, you may roll on Table: Variant Tiefling Abilities three times and choose the most favorable ability.</p>
			<p>Most tieflings possess a fixed variety of ability scores to reflect their fiendish heritages, regardless of the actual source of their foul traits. GMs might grant their tiefling NPCs or players variant ability modifiers based on their foul ancestries. At the GM&apos;s choice, such heritages might be determined deliberately or randomly, and may come with their own distinctive abilities or traits selected from the following charts.</p>
			<p>Some tieflings are blessed or cursed with unusual abilities. A GM may customize his tiefling NPCs or allow PCs to do so by rolling on the following chart.</p>
			<p>The abilities presented here replace a tiefling&apos;s darkness spell-like ability, with a caster level equals to its class level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fiendish Resilience" title="Fiendish Resilience" groups="" description="You dodge energy attacks with amazing agility.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, evasion class feature, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of the following energy types that you have resistance to: cold, electricity, or fire. Anytime you make a Reflex saving throw against an attack that deals the selected type of energy damage and is subject to your evasion class feature, you gain a +4 competence bonus on the save.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you take it, you select a different qualifying energy type.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fight On" title="Fight On" groups="" description="You can keep fighting even after you should be dead.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13; dwarf, half-orc, or orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can gain a number of temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier. You can activate this feat as an immediate action when reduced to 0 or fewer hit points. You can use this feat to prevent yourself from dying. These temporary hit points last for 1 minute. If your hit points drop below 0 due to the loss of these temporary hit points, you fall unconscious and are dying as normal. If you also have the ferocity racial trait, you can use that once you have lost the temporary hit points from this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fighting Frenzy" title="Fighting Frenzy" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You feed off the rage of your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are in a rage and an ally with this feat within 60 feet is in a rage, you don&apos;t take the normal &#x2013;2 penalty to AC for being in a rage. If you would take a larger penalty to AC for being in a rage, reduce that penalty by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Filthy Weapons" title="Filthy Weapons" groups="Combat" description="You spread contagion with your weapons by covering their business ends in virulent muck and sewage.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (dungeoneering) 1 rank, Knowledge (nature) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can take a standard action to cover a weapon in decomposing waste, slimy filth, or other virulent agent.</p>
			<p>The next attack with that weapon that succeeds against a foe exposes the target to filth fever. If the attack is a critical hit, the filth fever has an onset time of 1 round, and a save DC equal to 10 + 1/2 your base attack bonus + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Final Embrace" title="Final Embrace" groups="Combat" description="Your coils are particularly deadly, allowing you to constrict opponents of your size or smaller.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Int 3; naga, serpentfolk, or creature that has the constrict special attack as a racial ability; base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the constrict and grab special attacks. Your constrict attack deals damage equal to your unarmed strike or primary natural weapon melee attack. Further, you can grab and constrict opponents up to your size.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can grab and constrict creatures one size smaller than you.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Final Embrace Horror" title="Final Embrace Horror" groups="Combat" description="Your constricting attack has become stronger and more lethal.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Int 3; naga, serpentfolk, or creature that has the constrict special attack; Final Embrace; base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A creature that takes damage from your constrict attack is also shaken until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Final Embrace Master" title="Final Embrace Master" groups="Combat" description="Few creatures can survive the crushing horror of your Final Embrace.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 17, Int 3; naga, serpentfolk, or creature that has the constrict special attack; Ability Focus (constrict); Final Embrace; Final Embrace Horror; base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Double the number of damage dice for your constrict special attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Finishing Cascade" title="Finishing Cascade" groups="Combat, Combination" description="Your blows set up your opponents for a devastating finish.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +11 or monk level 11th; at least one combination feat.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The first time in a round you use a combination feat to apply a reduction or penalty to yourself or an enemy, you can double the feat&apos;s numerical modifier. For example, you can double the reduction granted by Combat Rhythm to -2. This does not double any other effects of combination feats, such as damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fire God's Blessing" title="Fire God's Blessing" groups="" description="The Fire God rewards you for killing enemies with flame.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc or orc, worshiper of a god of fire</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When in combat, if you deal fire damage to an enemy, you heal 1 hit point. You can only benefit from this healing once per round. Attacks that cause a target to catch on fire heal you each round the target takes fire damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fire Hand" title="Fire Hand" groups="Combat,Goblin" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can wield a torch as a weapon without taking the nonproficient penalty and gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls with melee weapons that deal fire damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fire Music" title="Fire Music" groups="" description="Your ability to command fire and bardic music has created a strange blend of both magics.">
		<Prerequisites>Spellcraft 5 ranks, ability to cast bard spells, ability to cast an arcane fire spell from some other spellcasting class.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast a bard spell that deals damage, you may replace the spell&apos;s normal damage with fire damage or split the spell&apos;s damage so that half of it is the normal damage type and half is fire damage.</p>
			<p>If you cast a summon monster spell as a bard spell, you may choose to give the summoned creature a fiery appearance, which gives it fire resistance 5 and adds +1 fire damage to all of its natural attacks. The creature sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius. This aspect of the feat has no effect if the creature already has the fire subtype.</p>
			<p>When you use this feat, the affected spell gains the fire descriptor. </p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fire Tamer" title="Fire Tamer" groups="Goblin" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on saves against spells with the fire descriptor. Additionally, your scars mark you as a talented fire tamer, granting you a +2 circumstance bonus on Diplomacy and Intimidate checks when dealing with other goblins.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Firebrand" title="Firebrand" groups="Combat" description="You can make use of a torch as a deadly, macelike weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Worshiper of Asmodeus</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat a torch as a light weapon that deals bludgeoning damage equal to that of a light mace of its size, plus 1 point of fire damage, and you do not incur penalties as you would for using it as an improvised weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A torch used in combat is treated as a one-handed improvised weapon that deals bludgeoning damage equal to that of a gauntlet of its size, plus 1 point of fire damage.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Firesight" title="Firesight" groups="Ifrit" description="Fire no longer blinds you, and smoke conceals nothing from your gaze.">
		<Prerequisites>Ifrit.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can see through fire and smoke without penalty, ignoring any cover or concealment bonuses from fire and smoke. This does not allow you to see anything you could not otherwise see (for example, invisible creatures are still invisible). You are immune to the dazzled condition.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flagbearer" title="Flagbearer" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 15.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you hold your clan, house, or party&apos;s flag, members of that allegiance within 30 feet who can see the flag (including yourself ) gain a +1 morale bonus on attack rolls, weapon damage rolls, and saving throws against fear and charm effects. You must hold the flag in one hand in order to grant this bonus. If the standard is taken by the enemy or destroyed, this bonus becomes a penalty, affecting all creatures that the bonus previously affected for 1 hour (or until you reclaim the lost flag).</p>
			<p>A flag is a colorful banner that bears the heraldry or symbol of a nation or organization. A character with the Flagbearer feat who bears a flag can grant additional combat bonuses to nearby allies. Carrying a flag in combat requires a free hand.</p>
			<p>Cost: 10 gp Weight 3 lbs.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: Whenever you can see your flag but aren&apos;t holding it, you can spend 1 stamina point to gain the benefits of Flagbearer for 1 minute as if you were holding it.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flame Blade Dervish Combat" title="Flame Blade Dervish Combat" groups="Combat" description="You move effortlessly when wielding a flame blade.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast flame blade as a spell or spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast flame blade, you gain a +10 enhancement bonus to your base speed as long as the spell persists, along with a +4 competence bonus on all Acrobatics checks. You add your Charisma modifier to damage rolls with your flame blade, and ignore the first 10 points of fire resistance possessed by a creature you hit with the flame blade for the purposes of determining the damage dealt by the flame blade. Against undead foes, you ignore the first 30 points of fire resistance. Immunity to fire still completely protects against damage from your flame blade.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flame Heart" title="Flame Heart" groups="Goblin" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Fire Tamer, character level 5th, goblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain fire resistance 5. When casting spells with the fire descriptor or throwing alchemist bombs that deal fire damage, treat your caster level or alchemist level as if you were 1 level higher.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flanking Foil" title="Flanking Foil" groups="Combat" description="Fighting multiple foes is easy for you.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you hit an adjacent opponent with a melee attack, until the start of your next turn, that opponent does not gain any flanking bonus on attack rolls while it is flanking you and cannot deal sneak attack damage to you. It can still provide a flank for its allies.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flaring Spell" title="Flaring Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You dazzle creatures when you affect them with a spell that has the fire, light, or electricity descriptor.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>The electricity, fire, or light effects of the affected spell create a flaring that dazzles creatures that take damage from the spell. A flare spell causes a creature that takes fire or electricity damage from the affected spell to become dazzled for a number of rounds equal to the actual level of the spell. A flaring spell only affects spells with a fire, light, or electricity descriptor.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a flaring spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flaying Critical" title="Flaying Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits weaken your opponents' defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit, your opponent takes a -1 penalty to its natural armor bonus for the duration of the encounter. This penalty is cumulative, but cannot reduce an opponent&apos;s natural armor bonus below 0.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fleet" title="Fleet" groups="" description="You are faster than most.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are wearing light or no armor, your base speed increases by 5 feet. You lose the benefits of this feat if you carry a medium or heavy load.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. The effects stack. </p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fleeting Spell" title="Fleeting Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells vanish with unusual speed.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>A fleeting spell&apos;s duration becomes dismissible, if it is not already. You can dismiss your own fleeting spell as a swift action. When you dismiss a fleeting spell, its lingering aura cannot be detected by magic unless the caster succeeds at a caster level check against a DC equal to 11 + your caster level. The DC of dispel checks to counter a fleeting spell is reduced by 2, and once active, dispel magic removes a fleeting spell without a caster level check. A fleeting spell has half its normal duration (with an extended fleeting spell, these duration adjustments cancel out). Only spells with a duration of at least 2 rounds can be made fleeting, and instantaneous or permanent spells cannot be fleeting spells.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>It is a standard action to dismiss a dismissible spell, and only spells whose Duration entry is marked with a D are dismissible.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +0 (a fleeting spell does not use up a higher-level spell slot than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flensing Strike" title="Flensing Strike" groups="" description="Your slashing sneak attacks tend to slice away swaths of skin and natural armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Sneak attack +3d6, bleeding sneak attack rogue trick or bleed universal monster ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully inflict sneak attack damage on a foe with a slashing weapon, your attack doesn&apos;t go particularly deep, but you do carve away a significant portion of skin and flesh. If this sneak attack inflicts bleed damage, the victim of the sneak attack is sickened by the pain and has its natural armor bonus (if any) reduced by a number of points equal to the number of sneak attack dice you possess. These penalties persist as long as the bleed damage persists. Multiple strikes on the same foe do not stack the bleed damage, but the penalty to natural armor does stack, to a maximum penalty equal to the target&apos;s normal full natural armor score.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fleshwarper" title="Fleshwarper" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create creatures through an abominable alchemical process.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (alchemy) 5 ranks, Heal 5 ranks, evil alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create fleshwarped creatures and fleshcraft grafts. A newly created fleshwarped creature has average hit points for its Hit Dice.</p>
			<p>A creature with the Fleshwarper feat can also create fleshcraft elixirs. Doing so requires an alchemy lab worth at least 1,000 gp as well as 1 pound of living tissue per 1,000 gp value of the elixir, just like creating a graft, but the components are distilled into the elixir. Creating a fleshcraft elixir is like creating a magic item and requires 1 day of crafting time per 1,000 gp of the graft&apos;s value. These potionlike concoctions can bestow the effect of an individual fleshcraft graft (a creature can&apos;t benefit from more than one at a time), but for a limited period of time. Imbibing a fleshcraft elixir works similarly to imbibing other potions or elixirs, except that it&apos;s slow acting, taking effect the round after it is imbibed (as if the imbiber were casting a 1-round casting time spell). Fleshcraft elixirs are foul and potentially dangerous.</p>
			<p>A fleshcraft elixir is keyed to a specific type of fleshcraft, and each elixir provides a Fortitude save that the imbiber must succeed at in order to gain that graft&apos;s effect for the limited duration.</p>
			<p>On a failed saving throw, the imbiber gains only the graft&apos;s penalty for its duration, and if the imbiber fails the saving throw by 5 or more, the imbiber also takes 1d6 points of Constitution damage. While not strictly magical (and not applicable for reuse with alchemical allocation), they count as both transmutation and poison effects that affect only living creatures for the purposes of saving throws and resistances.</p>
			<p>Below are some examples of fleshcrafts. In addition to the name, slot, and effect, each fleshcraft presents information for both the elixir and the graft versions. Each category of information is explained below.</p>
			<p>Temporary Duration: This is the length of time the fleshcraft lasts if the recipient is merely imbibing a fleshcraft elixir for its limited effects. This does not apply to a permanent fleshcraft such as a graft. If the graft has a limited number of uses per day, a creature affected by its corresponding elixir can use the ability the same number of times during the elixir&apos;s duration.</p>
			<p>Saving Throw: This is the DC of the Fortitude saving throw the imbiber must succeed at to gain the benefits rather than just the penalties of the fleshcraft when imbibing a fleshcraft elixir. A creature imbibing a corresponding elixir that fails this saving throw by 5 or more also takes 1d6 points of Constitution damage.</p>
			<p>Penalty This is the penalty that a creature takes while benefiting from a fleshcraft graft or elixir, or takes if it fails the saving throw after imbibing a fleshcraft elixir.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flexible Hex" title="Flexible Hex" groups="" description="Your wandering hex shifts at your command.">
		<Prerequisites>Wandering hex class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day as a swift action, you can change your wandering hex. When you change your hex, the new hex must be associated with the wandering spirit with which you are currently bonded. At 12th level, you can change either or both of your wandering hexes with the feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Shamans select their hexes every day when they prepare their spells and cannot change them.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flexible Shadow Jump" title="Flexible Shadow Jump" groups="" description="You have refined your ability to leap through the shadows.">
		<Prerequisites>Shadow jump shadowdancer class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you travel between shadows using the shadow jump ability, the minimum increment that you can jump is 5 feet, allowing you to split your shadow jumps into 5-foot increments instead of 10-foot increments. In addition, your shadow jump ability counts as the ability to cast dimension door for the purpose of meeting the prerequisites of the Dimensional Agility feat as well as any feat that lists that feat as a prerequisite, and your shadow jump benefits from such feats as if you were casting dimension door.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Each shadow jump, no matter how small, counts as a 10-foot increment.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flexible Wizardry" title="Flexible Wizardry" groups="" description="You have learned a trick that makes your spellcasting more flexible.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Mastery, wizard level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you prepare your spells each day, you can choose to keep a number of spell slots equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1) flexibly prepared. Instead of preparing a single spell within each of these slots, you can partially prepare two spells. Anytime after you prepare these flexible slots, you can spend a full-round action to finalize one slot, choosing one of the two spells to be finished and fully prepared in that slot.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flight Mastery" title="Flight Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can coax the magic of flight from transmutation magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude save bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has a transmutation spell of 2nd level or higher listed in its construction requirements to cast fly. If the item is a suit of armor you are wearing, you can use the item&apos;s enhancement bonus in place of your Dexterity modifier on Fly skill checks while the spell lasts.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day at base Fortitude save bonus +9 and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flinging Charge" title="Flinging Charge" groups="Combat" description="You hurl a weapon during your charge before drawing a new one to strike, enabling you to make another attack at the expense of the latter attack's accuracy.">
		<Prerequisites>Quick Draw, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you have a thrown weapon in hand when you begin charging, you can make a ranged attack with that weapon against the target of your charge at any point during your charge. You gain the +2 bonus for charging on the attack roll for this ranged attack. You can then immediately draw a melee weapon during your charge. You take a -5 penalty on the melee attack made at the end of the charge. When charging this way, you cannot use any effect that would grant you more than one attack at the end of your charge (such as pounce), nor can you use abilities that grant you other ranged attacks on a charge, such as the hurling charge rage power.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flow of Elements" title="Flow of Elements" groups="Teamwork" description="You can spontaneously channel your ally's elemental essence, be it burning fire, freezing ice, crackling lightning, or searing acid.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast spells; ifrit, oread, sylph, or undine.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you&apos;re adjacent to an ifrit, oread, sylph, or undine ally who also has this feat, you can spontaneously replace or split a spell&apos;s damage when casting it, as though the spell were affected by Elemental Spell (without using a higher-level spell slot). The type of energy damage depends on your ally&apos;s race: acid for oread, electricity for sylph, fire for ifrit, or cold for undine.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Aberration Expertise" title="Focused Aberration Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You hold strong against aberrations.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (aberration) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose either Fortitude saves against transformation effects (including transmutation spells and spell-like abilities) or Will saves against mind-affecting effects. You gain a bonus on the selected saving throw equal to half your favored enemy (aberration) bonus. Against aberrations&apos; spells and abilities, you gain this bonus on Fortitude saves against transmutation effects and on Will saves against mind-affecting effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Animal Expertise" title="Focused Animal Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You're skilled at patiently hiding from your favored enemies, particularly animals.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (animal) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on Stealth checks equal to half your favored enemy (animal) bonus. Against animals, this bonus is equal to your full favored enemy bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Construct Expertise" title="Focused Construct Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at breaking the defenses of constructs and other creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (construct) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your weapon attacks ignore a number of points of damage reduction or hardness equal to half your favored enemy (construct) bonus. This feat allows you to only ignore damage reduction that is normally bypassed by adamantine, bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing weapons. Against constructs, the amount of damage reduction and hardness you ignore is equal to your full favored enemy bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Disbelief" title="Focused Disbelief" groups="" description="So certain is your disbelief in the authority of the gods that you can brush aside their spells without effort.">
		<Prerequisites>Divine Defiance</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain spell resistance equal to 11 + your character level. This spell resistance applies only against spells and spell-like abilities covered by the Divine Defiance feat. You can lower this resistance for 1 round as a standard action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Discipline" title="Focused Discipline" groups="Combat" description="Familiarity with the military traditions of your homeland inspires uncommon valor in you.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on all saving throws against fear effects. Whenever a fear effect targets you and fails to affect you (either because of a successful saving throw or because of immunity to fear), you gain a +2 morale bonus on attack rolls, weapon damage rolls, and CMB checks against the creature that attempted to use the fear affect on you for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points in order to gain the benefit of Focused Discipline for 1 round as if you had been targeted by a fear effect that failed to affect you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Dragon Expertise" title="Focused Dragon Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your understanding of dragons helps you to easily avoid breath weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (dragon) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on saving throws against breath weapons and fear effects equal to half your favored enemy (dragon) bonus. Whenever you succeed at a Reflex saving throw against a dragon&apos;s extraordinary or supernatural ability that would deal half damage, you instead take no damage. If you already have the evasion class feature, you instead gain an inquisitor&apos;s stalwart ability against dragons&apos; extraordinary and supernatural abilities.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Eidolon" title="Focused Eidolon" groups="" description="Your bond with your eidolon helps to focus your concentration.">
		<Prerequisites>Shield ally class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are adjacent to your eidolon, you receive a +4 bonus on concentration checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Fey Expertise" title="Focused Fey Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your attacks strike true against capricious targets like fey.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (fey) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on attack rolls to confirm critical hits equal to half your favored enemy (fey) bonus. You treat your weapon attacks against fey as cold iron for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction and regeneration.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Inspiration" title="Focused Inspiration" groups="" description="Two of your skills gain a bit more from your inspiration than others.">
		<Prerequisites>Inspiration class feature, keen recollection class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose two skills that you either are trained in or can otherwise use untrained. You must be able to use inspiration on these skills. When you use inspiration with those skills, roll a d8 instead of a d6, or a d10 if you would normally roll a d8. If you have the true inspiration class feature, you roll twice as many such dice (2d8 or 2d10) as normal.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Magical Beast Expertise" title="Focused Magical Beast Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You move in ways that confound creatures that would strike you repeatedly.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (magical beast) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If a creature makes three or more attacks with natural weapons against you during its turn, you gain partial cover against the third and subsequent natural attacks from that creature. If the creature makes five or more attacks against you with natural weapons, you gain cover (instead of partial cover) against the fifth and subsequent natural attacks. If the attacker is a magical beast, reduce by one the number of natural attacks it must make in order for you to gain cover or partial cover.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Ooze Expertise" title="Focused Ooze Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You've learned to avoid and overcome the engulfing attacks of your studied prey.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (ooze) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus to your CMD equal to half your favored enemy (ooze) bonus. You also gain acid resistance equal to half your favored enemy (ooze) bonus. Against oozes, you instead apply your full favored enemy (ooze) bonus for both benefits.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Outsider Expertise" title="Focused Outsider Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You've learned to attack in a way that stymies the natural resistances common in outsiders.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (outsider) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your weapon attacks ignore a number of points of damage reduction equal to half your favored enemy (outsider [any one]) bonus. This feat allows you to ignore only damage reduction that is normally bypassed by chaotic-, evil-, good-, or lawful-aligned weapons. Against outsiders that match your favored enemy subtype, the amount of damage reduction and hardness you ignore is equal to your full favored class bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Phantom" title="Focused Phantom" groups="" description="Your close bond with your phantom helps you to focus your concentration .">
		<Prerequisites>Spiritual interference class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are adjacent to your phantom or your phantom is within your consciousness, you receive a +4 bonus on concentration checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Plant Expertise" title="Focused Plant Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You are quick to dodge and slash anything that would ensnare you.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (plant) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus equal to half your favored enemy (plant) bonus on Reflex saves to avoid being entangled and to your CMD whenever an opponent attempts to grapple you. Your weapons&apos; critical hit multipliers increase by one against creatures with the plant type.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Shot" title="Focused Shot" groups="Combat" description="Your anatomical insight adds deadliness to your shots.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Point Blank Shot, Precise Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you may make an attack with a bow or crossbow and add your Intelligence modifier on the damage roll. You must be within 30 feet of your target to deal this extra damage. Creatures immune to critical hits and sneak attacks are immune to this extra damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Starting at 2nd level, a ranger with the archery combat style may select Focused Shot as a combat style feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Spell" title="Focused Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="When you cast a spell that affects more than one creature, one opponent finds it more difficult to resist.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When casting a spell that affects or targets more than one creature, you can choose one target or creature within the spell effect. That creature&apos;s saving throw DC to resist the spell is increased by +2. You must choose which target to focus the spell on before casting the spell.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a focused spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
			<p>Spells that do not require a saving throw to resist or lessen the spell&apos;s effect do not benefit from this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Target" title="Focused Target" groups="Combat" description="You pour your entire focus into slaying your chosen target.">
		<Prerequisites>Studied target class feature (second studied target).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you study a target, you can reduce the number of additional targets you can maintain as a studied target. For each target reduced in this way, you increase your studied target bonus by 1 for either attack rolls, damage rolls, skill checks, or the DCs of your abilities. Each such increase must be applied to a different category (attack rolls, damage rolls, skill checks, or DCs). You can end the effects of this feat as a free action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Undead Expertise" title="Focused Undead Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your knowledge of the undead makes you especially effective when fighting them.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (undead) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus equal to half your favored enemy (undead) bonus on saving throws against ability damage, ability drain, energy drain, and negative energy effects. Once per day, when an undead creature&apos;s natural attack against you deals ability damage, deals ability drain, or bestows 1 or more negative levels, you can negate the damage, drain, or negative levels as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Vermin Expertise" title="Focused Vermin Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your experience with vermin resists the attacks of swarms.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (vermin) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain DR/&#x2014; equal to half your favored enemy (vermin) bonus against vermin and creatures with the swarm subtype. When attempting Fortitude saves against a swarm&apos;s distraction ability, you gain a bonus on the save equal to the damage prevented by this feat. Against vermin with the swarm subtype, the amount of damage reduction is equal to your full favored enemy (vermin) bonus. This damage reduction does not stack with that from other sources.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focusing Blow" title="Focusing Blow" groups="Teamwork,Hobgoblin" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Hobgoblin Discipline, hobgoblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>An ally who also has this feat can deal damage to you in order to break an ongoing mind-affecting effect that allows a saving throw. The ally must cause at least 5 points of damage to you with an attack, spell, or other ability. You then reroll your saving throw, with a +1 bonus for every 5 additional points of damage the attack caused. If your save is successful, the mind-affecting effect ends. Only damage actually dealt counts for purposes of this feat; nonlethal damage and damage reduced or eliminated by damage reduction, resistances, and so on does not qualify.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Foebane Magic" title="Foebane Magic" groups="" description="The spells you cast are particularly effective against your favored enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast 1st-level spells, favored enemy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your favored enemies take a &#x2013;1 penalty on saving throws against spells you cast. Furthermore, you gain your favored enemy bonus on Spellcraft checks to identify spells cast by favored enemies.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Follow-Up Strike" title="Follow-Up Strike" groups="Combat" description="You bat away an opponent's weapon, creating an opening for a punch or kick.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Disarm, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6 or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you succeed at a combat maneuver check to disarm an opponent, you can spend a swift action to make an unarmed strike attack at your highest base attack bonus against the target you disarmed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Following Step" title="Following Step" groups="Combat" description="You can repeatedly close the distance when foes try to move away, without impeding your normal movement.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Step Up.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using the Step Up feat to follow an adjacent foe, you may move up to 10 feet. You may still take a 5-foot step during your next turn, and any movement you make using this feat does not subtract any distance from your movement during your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only take a 5-foot step to follow an opponent using Step Up.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Foment the Blood" title="Foment the Blood" groups="Channeling; Orc" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature, orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you channel energy, instead of creating its normal effect, you can give orcs a bonus on weapon damage and critical hit confirmation rolls until your next turn. This bonus is equal to the number of dice your channeled energy normally heals or harms. Your channel has its normal effect on other creatures in the area.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fool Magic" title="Fool Magic" groups="" description="You can mislead magic items by virtue of your disguise.">
		<Prerequisites>Deceitful, Disguise 1 rank, Use Magic Device 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are in disguise as a member of a particular race or a person of a particular alignment, you can use your Disguise bonus instead of your Use Magic Device bonus to emulate that race and alignment for the purpose of attempting to activate a magic item.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Footslasher" title="Footslasher" groups="Combat" description="You are trained to strike at a large foe's feet to impede its movement and cause great pain.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you damage a foe that is of a larger size category than you with a weapon that does piercing or slashing damage, you can attempt to damage the creature&apos;s feet in a way that impedes its movement. Attacking a foe in this way is a standard action&#x2014;you cannot use Footslasher as part of a full-attack action. When you use Footslasher, you take a -2 penalty on your attack roll, but if you hit and deal at least 1 point of damage to the target, it is affected as if by caltrops&#x2014;its speed is reduced by half. This penalty lasts for 24 hours, or until the creature is successfully treated with a DC 15 Heal check or receives at least 1 point of magical healing. Footslasher does not stack with itself&#x2014;once a foe has been wounded by this attack, its speed cannot be further reduced by additional attacks (or by damage from caltrops).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Force Dash" title="Force Dash" groups="" description="You can absorb the magic in your force spells to give you a concentrated burst of speed.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +4, ability to cast 2nd-level arcane spells, ability to cast at least one arcane force spell.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can sacrifice a prepared arcane force spell (or if you are a spontaneous caster, a spell slot of the same level as an arcane force spell you know) to give yourself an enhancement bonus to speed. The bonus gained is equal to 10 feet &#xD7; the level of the spell sacrificed. The bonus applies to all forms of movement, and it lasts 1 round. If you charge while this bonus is in effect, you do not take the normal &#x2013;2 penalty to AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Force Shield Mastery" title="Force Shield Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can create barriers of force with abjuration magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude saving throw bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher listed in its construction requirements to create a magical effect that functions like shield, except the shield bonus to AC gained is equal to 1/3 your base Fortitude save bonus (minimum +1). You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day when your base Fortitude save bonus reaches +6, +9, and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Forceful Charge" title="Forceful Charge" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="This animal's charges move its enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per round when this animal companion hits an opponent with a charge attack, it can initiate a bull rush against that target as a free action. If it moves its full speed as part of the charge, it gains a +4 bonus on its combat maneuver check to resolve this bull rush.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Forge Ring" title="Forge Ring" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create magic rings.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create magic rings. Crafting a ring takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a ring, you must use up raw materials costing half of the base price.</p>
			<p>You can also mend a broken ring if it is one that you could make. Doing so costs half the raw materials and half the time it would take to forge that ring in the first place.See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Formula Recollection" title="Formula Recollection" groups="" description="You are able to record and recall even the complex and intricate details of spellcasting.">
		<Prerequisites>Spellcraft 5 ranks, keen recollection class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can record the formula for a spell that you saw being cast and identified with Spellcraft in the past 24 hours. This spell must be on the alchemist formula list.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fortified Armor Training" title="Fortified Armor Training" groups="Combat" description="You have learned to let your armor bear the brunt of the worst attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficient with armor or shield.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If an opponent scores a critical hit against you, you can turn the critical hit into a normal hit. If you do, either your armor or your shield gains the broken condition (your choice).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fortuitous Vigor" title="Fortuitous Vigor" groups="Combat" description="Your determination and enthusiasm help you shake off the most grievous wounds and soldier on against your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Combat Vigor, character level 4th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your vigor pool gains 1 vigor point.</p>
			<p>Whenever you roll a natural 20 on an ability check, attack roll, saving throw, or skill check, and whenever you threaten a critical hit with an attack, you can spend 1 or more vigor points as a swift action to regain hit points as described in the Combat Vigor feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fortunate One" title="Fortunate One" groups="Halfling" description="You have an even greater knack than most halflings for adaptable luck.">
		<Prerequisites>Adaptable luck racial trait, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The number of times per day you can use the adaptable luck racial trait increases by 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fortune Teller" title="Fortune Teller" groups="" description="As a result of being raised in a land steeped in tradition and superstition, you are skilled at communicating with the spirit world.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast divination spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Upon taking this feat, choose a focus item for your divination magic&#x2014;a crystal ball, runes, a harrow deck, or some such item. Whenever you cast a spell from the divination school, you may use this focus item instead of the spell&apos;s material component, as long as the cost of the material component is no more than 1,000 gp. If you choose to perform the spell using your focus item and the spell&apos;s normal material component (regardless of that component&apos;s cost), you cast the spell at +1 caster level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Insight" title="Fox Insight" groups="Combat" description="Your foxlike movements protect you from your opponents' attempts to manipulate you.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Fox Style.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Fox Style, you can use your base attack bonus in place of your ranks in Sense Motive to determine your Sense Motive skill bonus when foes attempt to feint against you, and creatures attempting to demoralize you don&apos;t gain a bonus for being bigger than you (though they still take a penalty for being smaller). If your Intelligence score is at least 19, the DC to demoralize or feint you increases by 4.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Shape" title="Fox Shape" groups="Kitsune" description="You can change into a fox in addition to your other forms.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, base attack bonus +3, kitsune.</Prerequisites>
		<Special>
			<p>A kitsune may select this feat any time she would gain a feat.</p>
		</Special>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can take the form of a fox whose appearance is static and cannot be changed each time you assume this form. Your bite attack&apos;s damage is reduced to 1d3 points of damage on a hit, but you gain a +10 racial bonus on Disguise checks made to appear as a fox. Changing from kitsune to fox shape is a standard action. This ability otherwise functions as beast shape II, and your ability scores change accordingly.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Style" title="Fox Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your martial training helps you manipulate foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you can use your base attack bonus in place of your ranks in Bluff on Bluff checks to feint in combat and to create a distraction to hide. If your Intelligence is at least 19, you gain a +4 bonus on such Bluff checks when adding your Charisma modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Trickery" title="Fox Trickery" groups="Combat" description="Whenever a foes drops his guard, you can make him suffer with a dirty trick.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Fox Insight, Fox Style, Improved Dirty Trick.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Fox Style, you can perform dirty trick combat maneuvers as attacks of opportunity. If your Intelligence is at least 19, you gain a +4 bonus on dirty trick combat maneuver checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Free Spirit" title="Free Spirit" groups="" description="Your strong belief in the value of freedom protects you from mental and physical shackles.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, any chaotic alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 morale bonus on saving throws made against mind-affecting effects and on all Escape Artist or grapple checks made to escape a grapple or to escape from bonds.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Freeze in Place" title="Freeze in Place" groups="Combat" description="You become an expert of hiding in plain sight.">
		<Prerequisites>Stealth 5 ranks, wyrwood.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the freeze universal monster ability, allowing you to appear as an ordinary statue. If you attack a creature unaware of you while using this ability, you double your critical threat range.</p>
			<p>This effect doesn&apos;t stack with any other effect that expands the threat range of your attacks or weapons.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Friendly Face" title="Friendly Face" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="Other animals of your species adore you. No matter how territorial, ill-tempered, wounded, or hungry they are, they see you as a friend, not an enemy. They'll give your two-legged friend the benefit of the doubt as well.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Other animals of roughly the same kind as you (cats to felines, eagles to raptors, frogs to amphibians, etc.) have their starting attitudes toward you improved by two steps. Their attitudes towards your master are likewise improved by one step.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If your master has the animal focus class feature, this feat also applies to any animals of roughly the same kind as your active animal focus.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Friendly Fire Maneuvers" title="Friendly Fire Maneuvers" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You and your teammates can anticipate one another's ranged attacks and stay out of each others' way.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Allies who also have this feat cannot provide soft cover to enemies, allowing you to make attacks of opportunity against an enemy even if those allies grant you soft cover against that foe&apos;s attacks. If an ally who also has this feat casts a spell that targets the area you are in as it allows a Reflex saving throw to avoid the effect (such as fireball), you gain a +4 dodge bonus on that saving throw.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Friendly Rivalry" title="Friendly Rivalry" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You fight harder when you're trying to score a quick kill in single combat before your ally does.">
		<Prerequisites>Human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you&apos;re the only one threatening a foe and an ally within 30 feet who also has this feat is the only creature threatening a different foe, you gain a +2 morale bonus on your melee attack rolls against the foe that only you are threatening. You gain the bonus only if neither of the qualifying opponents is flat-footed, helpless or otherwise unable to act. You must be able to see your ally to gain the benefit of this feat. If another ally who is not threatening your chosen foe makes any sort of attack against that foe (such as a ranged attack or a spell), you lose this feat&apos;s benefit for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Friendly Switch" title="Friendly Switch" groups="" description="You elbow an ally out of the way, and take his place on the battlefield.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As part of your movement or as a 5-foot-step, you can move into the space occupied by an ally of your size or smaller, which displaces the ally into the space you just left. Your ally must be willing and able to move and able to occupy the space you were in. This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity. This does not count toward your ally&apos;s movement on his next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Frightening Ambush" title="Frightening Ambush" groups="Combat" description="You are able to leap from hiding and strike great fear in your opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidate 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a free action, you can attempt an Intimidate check to demoralize a flat-footed opponent you attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Frightful Shape" title="Frightful Shape" groups="" description="Your wild shape form strikes fear into your opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 19, base attack bonus +9, wild shape class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use wild shape, it is supernaturally ferocious and disquieting in appearance, such that when you attack a creature, you can use this ferocity to frighten observers. Opponents within 30 feet of you when you attack must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + half your character level + your Charisma modifier) to resist being affected by your frightful shape. On a failed save, creatures with fewer Hit Dice than you become shaken, or panicked if they have 4 Hit Dice or fewer; in either case, the effect lasts for a number of rounds equal to your character level. An opponent that succeeds at its saving throw is immune to your frightful shape for 24 hours. This is a mind-affecting fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Furious Finish" title="Furious Finish" groups="" description="You channel all of your rage into one massive blow to crush your enemy.">
		<Prerequisites>Rage class feature, Vital Strike, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While raging, when you use the Vital Strike feat, you can choose not to roll your damage dice and instead deal damage equal to the maximum roll possible on those damage dice. If you do, your rage immediately ends, and you are fatigued (even if you would not normally be).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Furious Focus" title="Furious Focus" groups="Combat" description="Even in the midst of fierce and furious blows, you can find focus in the carnage and your seemingly wild blows strike home.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are wielding a two-handed weapon or a one-handed weapon with two hands, and using the Power Attack feat, you do not suffer Power Attack&apos;s penalty on melee attack rolls on the first attack you make each turn. You still suffer the penalty on any additional attacks, including attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Furious Spell" title="Furious Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells seethe with the ferocious intensity of your blood-red rage.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>A furious spell that deals hit point damage adds twice the spell&apos;s original level to the amount of damage dealt by the spell. Spells that affect multiple targets deal the extra damage once to each target, regardless of whether the spell deals its damage all at once or in multiple hits (in the latter case, add the extra damage to the first hit against each target). In addition, a furious spell can be cast while the caster is enraged, including during a barbarian rage or while affected by a rage spell. Even a furious spell that requires an emotion component can be cast while enraged. The caster gains a +2 circumstance bonus on concentration checks and caster level checks related to casting a furious spell if she is enraged.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a furious spell uses up a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fury of the Tainted" title="Fury of the Tainted" groups="Combat" description="The unstoppable anger you feel toward do-gooders and self-proclaimed saints makes you a force to be reckoned with.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, rage class feature, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While raging, you gain a +4 competence bonus on saving throws made against spells and effects with the [good] descriptor.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fury's Fall" title="Fury's Fall" groups="Combat" description="You can use strength and agility to send foes crashing to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Trip.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When making a trip attack, add your Dexterity bonus to your CMB.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fury's Snare" title="Fury's Snare" groups="Combat" description="You entangle your foe in your weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Fury&apos;s Fall, Improved Trip.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you successfully use a whip to trip a foe, you can choose to drop your whip. Your tripped target gains the entangled condition. The target can break free of the whip by making a DC 10 Strength check or a DC 15 Escape Artist check (add the enhancement bonus of the whip to these DCs), or by using a full-round action to disentangle himself. Escaping the whip by making a Strength check means the whip gains the broken condition. If the whip has a magical quality such as flaming, apply this quality&apos;s damage to the target every round on your turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Galley Slave" title="Galley Slave" groups="" description=" Your experience as a galley slave has given you some unique insight into the world of sailing and piracy. ">
		<Prerequisites>Profession (sailor) 1 rank, current or former galley slave </Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 circumstance bonus on Profession (sailor) made while aboard a ship with oars and rowers. When fighting on a ship, your first hit each battle gets a +2 damage bonus. </p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gang Up" title="Gang Up" groups="Combat" description="You are adept at using greater numbers against foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You are considered to be flanking an opponent if at least two of your allies are threatening that opponent, regardless of your actual positioning.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You must be positioned opposite an ally to flank an opponent.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gate Breaker" title="Gate Breaker" groups="Combat" description="Your strikes against objects are especially vicious.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Sunder, Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you would deal damage to an object, you deal normal damage plus an additional amount equal to your Strength modifier. This applies to both unattended objects and those you damage as part of a successful sunder combat maneuver check.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gaze Reflection" title="Gaze Reflection" groups="" description="The power of your psychic stare wards you from the potent gazes of your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Spellcraft 10 ranks, bold stare and mesmerist tricks class features.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you avert your eyes from a creature with a gaze attack (including one produced by a spell like eyebite or burning gaze or by a magic item), you can roll twice and select the better result when checking to see whether you are exposed to that gaze attack and when rolling your miss chance on attacks made against that creature (the latter doesn&apos;t stack with Blind-Fight). In addition, as a swift action, you can expend one mesmerist trick to make yourself immune to that creature&apos;s gaze until the beginning of your next turn. If you expend two mesmerist tricks instead, you gain immunity to that creature&apos;s gaze and also reflect its gaze back at it, affecting it with its own gaze.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A mesmerist&apos;s hypnotic stare, a witch&apos;s or hag&apos;s evil eye, and a vampire&apos;s dominate ability are treated as gaze attacks for the purpose of this feat, as are abilities that are triggered when looking at a creature, such as a nymph&apos;s blinding beauty or a sea hag&apos;s horrific appearance.</p>
			<p>Spending two mesmerist tricks on this feat does not bypass any immunity the creature might have to its own gaze, such as a vampire&apos;s immunity to mind-affecting effects or the fact that the nymph&apos;s blinding beauty works only on humanoids.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ghostslayer" title="Ghostslayer" groups="Combat" description="Your blade is keen enough to hew incorporeal creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, Knowledge (religion) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can imbue a weapon you wield with spiritual energies for 1 round. An imbued weapon damages incorporeal creatures as though it were magical. If the imbued weapon has an enhancement bonus of +2 or greater, it functions as a ghost touch weapon.</p>
			<p>A weapon imbued in this way can deal precision damage (such as sneak attack damage) to incorporeal creatures.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Giant Killer" title="Giant Killer" groups="Combat,Dwarf" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Cleave, Goblin Cleaver, Orc Hewer, Power Attack, Strike Back, base attack bonus +11, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>This functions as Goblin Cleaver, but your additional attacks can be made against creatures one size category larger than you or smaller. In addition, any such attacks made against humanoids (giant) gain a +2 circumstance bonus on attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Giant Steps" title="Giant Steps" groups="Duergar" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Duergar, slow and steady racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When your size increases to Large or larger, your base speed increases by 20 feet. This increase applies only if the effect that changed your size does not alter your speed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Giant-Killer Stance" title="Giant-Killer Stance" groups="Combat" description="You can prepare a crippling strike against larger foes that rush into your weapon's reach.">
		<Prerequisites>Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can treat any reach weapon you wield as having the brace property against creatures that are Large or larger. If your readied attack hits, the creature takes a -2 penalty on melee attack rolls for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Giantslaying Team" title="Giantslaying Team" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="When a giant attempts to hit your ally, that giant unwittingly reveals an opening in her defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Dodge, Mobility, base attack bonus +4, defensive training racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever a foe with the giant subtype you threaten misses with an attack of opportunity against an ally with this feat, you can make a melee attack against that giant as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gliding Steps" title="Gliding Steps" groups="" description="You skate across the surface of the earth as if gliding on ice.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Mobility, Nimble Moves, ki pool.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you have at least one ki point in your ki pool, when you move you do not provoke attacks of opportunity when leaving the first square of that movement. You can spend 1 ki point to avoid provoking attacks of opportunity during that entire move.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gloom Sight" title="Gloom Sight" groups="Fetchling" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Fetchling</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain darkvision 90 ft., but gain the light sensitivity weakness.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gloom Strike" title="Gloom Strike" groups="Combat,Fetchling" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Blind-Fight, fetchling</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are within an area of dim light or darkness, you gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls against enemies that are also within dim light or darkness.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gloomstorm" title="Gloomstorm" groups="Combat, Conduit" description="An inexhaustible arsenal lies in the Shadow Plane, waiting to be unleashed.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (planes) 4 ranks, shadow weapon class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can thin the barriers between yourself and the Shadow Plane, allowing you to create shadow weapons more easily. While this effect is active, you can create new shadow weapons as a free action.</p>
			<p>This does not increase the number of shadow weapons you can maintain at a single time.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat&apos;s benefit for a number of rounds per day equal to your ranks in Knowledge (planes). These rounds need not be consecutive.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Glorious Heat" title="Glorious Heat" groups="" description="When you cast divine fire spells, their heat empowers nearby allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast divine spells, caster level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast a divine spell with the [fire] descriptor, choose a single ally within 30 feet that you can see. That ally heals a number of hit points equal to the level of the spell cast and gains a +1 morale bonus on attack rolls until the end of its next turn (see Editor&apos;s Note at right.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gnome Trickster" title="Gnome Trickster" groups="" description="Your arcane talents go beyond the illusory.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, gnome, gnome magic racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>In addition to your normal gnome spell-like abilities, you also gain the following spell-like abilities: 1/day&#x2014;mage hand and prestidigitation.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gnome Weapon Focus" title="Gnome Weapon Focus" groups="Combat,Gnome" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, gnome, proficient with all martial weapons.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls with gnome weapons (weapons with &#x201C;gnome&#x201D; in the title).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Go Unnoticed" title="Go Unnoticed" groups="" description="Your small size lets you quickly duck out of sight.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Small size or smaller.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>During the first round of combat, flat-footed opponents are considered not to have noticed you yet for the purposes of Stealth skill checks, allowing you to make a Stealth check that round to hide from them.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Goblin Cleaver" title="Goblin Cleaver" groups="Combat, Dwarf" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Cleave, Power Attack, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Cleave or Great Cleave, if your initial attack hits, you may take your additional attacks against any creature smaller than you that you threaten; your targets need not be adjacent to one another. Additional attacks you make against humanoids (goblinoid) gain a +2 circumstance bonus on attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Goblin Gunslinger" title="Goblin Gunslinger" groups="Combat,Goblin" description="You have learned how to fire the big guns.">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can wield Medium firearms without taking the penalty for an inappropriately sized weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You take a &#x2013;2 penalty when using an inappropriately sized weapon.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Godless Healing" title="Godless Healing" groups="" description="You have mastered a specialized and complex technique to ignore pain by focusing your belief on the self rather than relying on faith.">
		<Prerequisites>Cannot have a patron deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day when you have half your total hit points or fewer, you may heal yourself of an amount of damage equal to 1d8 plus your total Hit Dice as a move action. This is a supernatural ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat more than once. Each time you do, you may heal yourself one additional time per day.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gore Fiend" title="Gore Fiend" groups="Orc/Half-Orc, Combat" description="Horrible wounds, whether on yourself or your enemies, make your blood sing.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc or orc, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are raging and you confirm a critical hit with a melee weapon or a critical hit is confirmed on you (whether by a melee weapon, spell, or ranged weapon), you regain 1 round of rage (up to your maximum for the day). You can only gain this benefit once per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gorgon's Fist" title="Gorgon's Fist" groups="Combat" description="With one well-placed blow, you leave your target reeling.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Scorpion Style, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, make a single unarmed melee attack against a foe whose speed is reduced (such as from Scorpion Style). If the attack hits, you deal damage normally and the target is staggered until the end of your next turn unless it makes a Fortitude saving throw (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wis modifier). This feat has no effect on targets that are staggered.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gory Finish" title="Gory Finish" groups="Combat" description="By drawing upon wells of savagery, you can slay your foe in creative and horrifyingly gruesome manners, intimidating nearby foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the attack action, you can use a weapon with which you have Weapon Focus to make a single attack at your highest base attack bonus. If you reduce your target to negative hit points, you can spend a swift action to make an Intimidate check to demoralize all foes within 30 feet who could see your attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Got Your Back" title="Got Your Back" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You protect an ally from attacks he doesn't see coming.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you successfully use the aid another action to give an ally who also has this feat a +2 bonus to AC against an opponent&apos;s next attack, the ally is also not considered flanked or flat-footed against that opponent until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can use aid another to grant an ally a +2 bonus to AC against the next attack from an adjacent foe.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grab and Go" title="Grab and Go" groups="Combat" description="You can snatch up an item to use as a weapon in the blink of an eye.">
		<Prerequisites>Catch Off-Guard or Throw Anything, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a free action, you can pick up an unattended item as part of a movement. Picking up the item does not provoke an attack of opportunity. If you have Throw Anything, you can pick up a number of closely gathered items that could be held in one hand (such as dishes from a stack of plates) equal to your Dexterity modifier (minimum 1). You must have a hand free to use this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grabbing Drag" title="Grabbing Drag" groups="Combat" description="You can move easily with a grappled enemy in tow.">
		<Prerequisites>Grabbing Style, Improved Grapple; base attack bonus +8, brawler level 4th, or monk level 4th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are using Grabbing Style, if you use the move grapple action, you can move both yourself and a single target that you&apos;re grappling your full speed instead of half your speed. After you have done so, you can use a move action to move yourself and the target of your grapple half your speed without needing to attempt an additional combat maneuver check. You cannot use this feat if you are grappling two targets.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grabbing Master" title="Grabbing Master" groups="Combat" description="You can grapple two foes as easily as one.">
		<Prerequisites>Grabbing Drag, Grabbing Style, Improved Grapple; base attack bonus +12, brawler level 8th, or monk level 8th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are grabbing two opponents while using Grabbing Style, you can use your grapple to move or damage one or both opponents you are grappling, instead of just one.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grabbing Style" title="Grabbing Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You are adept at the one-handed grab.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Grapple; base attack bonus +6, brawler&apos;s flurry class feature, or flurry of blows class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use this style, you do not take a -4 penalty on combat maneuver checks to grapple a foe with only one hand. Additionally, you do not lose your Dexterity bonus to AC while pinning an opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Without two hands free, you take a -4 penalty on the combat maneuver roll to grapple a foe. While pinning a foe, you lose your Dexterity bonus to AC.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Graceful Steal" title="Graceful Steal" groups="Combat" description="You can steal with surprising subtlety.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Agile Maneuvers, Improved Steal, Sleight of Hand 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When attempting Sleight of Hand checks to lift or palm objects, you can use your Combat Maneuver Bonus for a steal combat maneuver in place of your Sleight of Hand modifier, though if you do so, you must use your Dexterity modifier and not your Strength modifier. You can steal items with the steal combat maneuver even if they are hidden in a bag or pack (provided you can reach the item within), but the opponent gains at least a +5 bonus to its CMD (as for a fastened object) in this case.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grant Initiative" title="Grant Initiative" groups="" description="Not only are you a master at taking the initiative, but you can also grant it to someone else.">
		<Prerequisites>Cunning initiative class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>At the start of each encounter, you can either choose to keep the bonus granted to you by your Wisdom modifier on initiative checks or choose to give that bonus to one of your allies that you can see. You must make this choice before you or the ally you are granting the bonus to makes the initiative check.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grappled Caster" title="Grappled Caster" groups="" description="You have trained to cast spells while wrestling an opponent.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Casting.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 bonus on concentration checks to cast spells while grappled. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Combat Casting.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grasping Strike" title="Grasping Strike" groups="Combat" description="The surrounding foliage lurches forth at your enemies in concert with your strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Nature Magic or the ability to cast druid or ranger spells; Vital Strike, Knowledge (nature) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Vital Strike (or Improved Vital Strike or Greater Vital Strike), you cause the foliage in the area to reach out and entangle your foe (as the condition) if it fails a Reflex save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier). The effect lasts for 1 minute or until the enemy breaks free with a successful Strength check or an Escape Artist check (DC = the effect&apos;s saving throw DC), whichever comes first.</p>
			<p>You can use this benefit a number of times per day equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1). You can choose to use this ability as a free action after you hit the enemy with the attack. This is a supernatural ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grasping Tail" title="Grasping Tail" groups="Tiefling" description="Your tail becomes more useful.">
		<Prerequisites>Tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use your tail to grab stowed items. While you cannot wield weapons with your tail, you can use it to retrieve small, stowed objects carried on your person as a swift action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the prehensile tail racial trait, you can use your tail to grab unattended items within 5 feet as a swift action as well as to grab stowed objects carried on your person; you can hold such objects with your tail, though you cannot manipulate them with your tail (other than to put them in your hand).</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gravitational Vital Strike" title="Gravitational Vital Strike" groups="Combat" description="You use unusual gravities to adjust your vital strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Vital Strike; Heavy Gravity Acclimation or Light Gravity Acclimation.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using any Vital Strike feat in an area of light or heavy gravity, roll the weapon&apos;s damage dice for the attack one additional time. For example, if using Improved Vital Strike, you would roll the weapon&apos;s damage dice for the attack four times before adding other damage bonuses, instead of three times. You must have the appropriate prerequisite feat associated with the plane&apos;s gravity trait to gain this benefit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Great Cleave" title="Great Cleave" groups="Combat" description="You can strike many adjacent foes with a single blow.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Cleave, Power Attack, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make a single attack at your full base attack bonus against a foe within reach. If you hit, you deal damage normally and can make an additional attack (using your full base attack bonus) against a foe that is adjacent to the previous foe and also within reach. If you hit, you can continue to make attacks against foes adjacent to the previous foe, so long as they are within your reach. You cannot attack an individual foe more than once during this attack action. When you use this feat, you take a -2 penalty to your Armor Class until your next turn.</p>
			<p>Editor&apos;s Note</p>
			<p>Can I use Cleave or Great Cleave to cleave to or from an image created by a mirror image spell?</p>
			<p>No. If your initial attack hit the caster, you can&apos;t cleave to an image as if it were an actual creature. If your initial attack hit an image, you failed to hit your intended target (the caster), and therefore can&apos;t cleave. As you can&apos;t specifically target an image (because you can&apos;t tell the images from the actual caster), you likewise can&apos;t aim for an image and try to cleave to another image.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
			<p>Can I take a 5-foot step in the middle of my attempt to use the Cleave feat, to bring another foe within reach?</p>
			<p>No. Cleave is a special action and the conditions for that action are checked at the moment you begin your action. At that moment, all of the available targets are checked to make sure they adjacent to each other and within reach. You cannot take a 5-foot step in the middle of the action and check conditions again. If you do not have two targets within reach, adjacent to each other at the start of the attack, you could not even attempt to make an attack using Cleave.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
			<p>Great Rend&quot; title=&quot;[Source]</p>
			<p>Can I take a 5-foot step in the middle of my attempt to use the Cleave feat, to bring another foe within reach?</p>
			<p>No. Cleave is a special action and the conditions for that action are checked at the moment you begin your action. At that moment, all of the available targets are checked to make sure they adjacent to each other and within reach. You cannot take a 5-foot step in the middle of the action and check conditions again. If you do not have two targets within reach, adjacent to each other at the start of the attack, you could not even attempt to make an attack using Cleave.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Great Fortitude" title="Great Fortitude" groups="" description="You are resistant to poisons, diseases, and other maladies.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on all Fortitude saving throws.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Great Hatred" title="Great Hatred" groups="Combat, Gnome" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Gnome, hatred racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain an additional +1 bonus on melee and thrown weapon attacks against targets of your hatred racial trait.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Great Rend" title="Great Rend" groups="Combat" description="You use your teeth and claws to rip your foes to shreds.">
		<Prerequisites>Bite attack, rend, troll.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you are able to use your rend ability on the same turn that you also succeed at a bite attack, your rend deals an amount of additional damage equal to half your Strength modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Balor Whip" title="Greater Balor Whip" groups="Combat" description="You can pull in foes with your whip and then attack them with your sword.">
		<Prerequisites>Balor Whip, Improved Balor Whip, Weapon Focus (whip), Whip Mastery, base attack bonus +16.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Improved Balor Whip to make a single attack at your highest attack bonus, your critical threat range increases to 19-20 and you gain a +4 bonus on critical confirmation rolls if you threaten a critical hit with that attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Beast Hunter" title="Greater Beast Hunter" groups="Combat" description="You are an apex hunter.">
		<Prerequisites>Beast Hunter; Improved Beast Hunter; base attack bonus +6; Knowledge (nature) or Survival 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you are surprised by an animal native to the terrain you have chosen for Beast Hunter, you can act normally in the surprise round, though you are still considered flat-footed until it is your turn to act. You also gain a +4 bonus to confirm critical threats against animals native to the terrain you have chosen.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have selected Beast Hunter multiple times, you gain the benefits of this feat for all of the terrains you have chosen for those feats.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Bless Equipment" title="Greater Bless Equipment" groups="" description="Your blessings are longer lasting, and you can bless more than one item at a time.">
		<Prerequisites>Bless Equipment, Improved Bless Equipment, caster level 12th, channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The duration of your equipment blessings doubles. In addition, as a standard action you may bless up to two pieces of equipment within range with a single blessing, expending uses of channeled energy as if you had only blessed one item.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Blighted Critical" title="Greater Blighted Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hit from a spell or spell-like ability afflicts the target with a major spellblight.">
		<Prerequisites>Blighted Critical, caster level 12th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you confirm a critical hit with a touch spell, ranged touch spell, or spell-like ability against an opponent, the victim gains a random major spellblight.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Blind-Fight" title="Greater Blind-Fight" groups="Combat" description="Your enemies cannot hide from you.">
		<Prerequisites>Perception 15 ranks, Improved Blind-Fight.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your melee attacks ignore the miss chance for less than total concealment, and you treat opponents with total concealment as if they had normal concealment (20% miss chance instead of 50%). You may still reroll a miss chance percentile roll as normal.</p>
			<p>If you successfully pinpoint an invisible or hidden attacker, that attacker gets no advantages related to hitting you with ranged attacks, regardless of the range. That is, you don&apos;t lose your Dexterity bonus to Armor Class, and the attacker doesn&apos;t get the usual +2 bonus for being invisible.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>The Greater Blind-Fight feat is of no use against a character who is the subject of a blink spell.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Bull Rush" title="Greater Bull Rush" groups="Combat" description="Your bull rush attacks throw enemies off balance.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6, Str 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to bull rush a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Bull Rush. Whenever you bull rush an opponent, his movement provokes attacks of opportunity from all of your allies (but not you).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Creatures moved by bull rush do not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Called Shot" title="Greater Called Shot" groups="Combat" description="You can make multiple called shots where others could land but one.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Called Shot, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you make an attack, you can choose to replace that attack with a called shot. You can make multiple called shots in a single round. Each additional called shot after the first made in the same round takes a -5 penalty. In addition, a called shot that deals half the creature&apos;s hit points of damage (minimum 40) is a debilitating blow.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can make only one called shot in a round as a full-round action. A called shot that deals 50 points of damage is a debilitating blow.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Channel Force" title="Greater Channel Force" groups="Channeling; Aasimar" description="Your eruptions of divine power move your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel Force, Improved Channel Force, Aasimar, channel energy 6d6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Improved Channel Force, you can affect all creatures in a 30-foot-radius burst.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Channel Smite" title="Greater Channel Smite" groups="" description="You empower your weapon with the might of your deity, which you discharge as you strike your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature, Channel Smite, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Before making any melee attacks on your turn, you can use a swift action to expend one daily use of your channel energy class feature. The dice from your channel energy feature form a pool of damage dice you can access to further damage creatures normally harmed by the energy you are channeling&#x2014;undead for positive energy, living creatures for negative energy. Prior to making each melee attack, allocate dice from the pool to be used as extra damage dice if you hit. Your target can make a Will save, as normal, to halve this extra damage. This extra damage is not multiplied when you score a critical hit. If you miss, the extra damage dice remain in your pool, but any dice left unexpended at the end of your turn are wasted.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Dirge of Doom" title="Greater Dirge of Doom" groups="" description="The haunting sound of sepulchral intonations chills the most stalwart adversary to its very core.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Dirge of Doom, ability to perform dirge of doom.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The effect of your dirge of doom lingers with a target for 2 rounds after the creature leaves the dirge&apos;s area of effect. If you use your dirge on a creature that is shaken, it becomes frightened. If you use it on a creature that is frightened, it becomes panicked. Once affected by this feat, a creature cannot be affected by it again for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Fear effects on a creature end immediately once it leaves the area of dirge of doom. A fear effect cannot be made more extreme by dirge of doom and can be changed only to the frightened condition by the Improved Dirge of Doom feat.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Dirty Trick" title="Greater Dirty Trick" groups="Combat" description="When you pull a dirty trick, your foe is truly hindered.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Dirty Trick, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to attempt a dirty trick. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Dirty Trick. Whenever you successfully perform a dirty trick, the penalty lasts for 1d4 rounds, plus 1 round for every 5 by which your attack exceeds the target&apos;s CMD. In addition, removing the condition requires the target to spend a standard action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The condition imposed by a dirty trick lasts for 1 round plus 1 round for every 5 by which your attack exceeds the target&apos;s CMD. Removing the condition requires the target to spend a move action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Disarm" title="Greater Disarm" groups="Combat" description="You can knock weapons far from an enemy's grasp.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Expertise, Improved Disarm, base attack bonus +6, Int 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on combat maneuver checks made to disarm a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Disarm. Whenever you successfully disarm an opponent, the weapon lands 15 feet away from its previous wielder, in a random direction.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Disarmed weapons and gear land at the feet of the disarmed creature.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Drag" title="Greater Drag" groups="Combat" description="Foes that you drag are thrown out of balance.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Drag, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to drag a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Drag. Whenever you drag a foe, his movement provokes attacks of opportunity from all of your allies (but not you).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Creatures moved by drag do not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Drow Nobility" title="Greater Drow Nobility" groups="Drow" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Drow Nobility, Improved Drow Nobility, able to use drow spell-like abilities, drow.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your detect magic spell-like ability is now constant. You may use your dancing lights, deeper darkness, faerie fire, feather fall, and levitate spell-like abilities at will.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Eldritch Heritage" title="Greater Eldritch Heritage" groups="" description="Your discovered bloodline power reaches its zenith.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 17, Eldritch Heritage, Improved Eldritch Heritage, character level 17th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain an additional power from the bloodline you selected with the Eldritch Heritage feat. You gain a 15th-level (or lower) sorcerer bloodline power that you do not already have. For purposes of using that power, treat your character level as your sorcerer level for all your sorcerer bloodline powers granted by this feat, Eldritch Heritage, and Improved Eldritch Heritage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Elemental Focus" title="Greater Elemental Focus" groups="" description="Choose an energy type to which you have already applied the Elemental Focus feat. Any spells you cast of this energy type are very hard to resist.">
		<Prerequisites>Elemental Focus.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Add +1 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws against spells that deal damage of the energy type you select. This bonus stacks with the bonus from Elemental Focus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take this feat, it applies to a new energy type to which you have already applied the</p>
			<p>Elemental Focus feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Feint" title="Greater Feint" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at making foes overreact to your attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Expertise, Improved Feint, base attack bonus +6, Int 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use feint to cause an opponent to lose his Dexterity bonus, he loses that bonus until the beginning of your next turn, in addition to losing his Dexterity bonus against your next attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A creature you feint loses its Dexterity bonus against your next attack.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Grapple" title="Greater Grapple" groups="Combat" description="Maintaining a grapple is second nature to you.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6, Dex 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to grapple a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Grapple. Once you have grappled a creature, maintaining the grapple is a move action. This feat allows you to make two grapple checks each round (to move, harm, or pin your opponent), but you are not required to make two checks. You only need to succeed at one of these checks to maintain the grapple.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Maintaining a grapple is a standard action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Hunter's Bond" title="Greater Hunter's Bond" groups="Combat" description="Your allies can target additional foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Hunter&apos;s Bond, hunter&apos;s bond (hunting companions) class feature, ranger level 12th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you activate hunter&apos;s bond, you can select a number of targets equal to your Wisdom modifier as long as they all count as your favored enemy.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You select one target against which your allies receive your favored enemy bonus.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Mercy" title="Greater Mercy" groups="" description="Your mercy has incredible recuperative properties.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, lay on hands class feature, mercy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use your lay on hands ability and the target of that ability does not have any conditions your mercies can remove, it instead heals an additional +1d6 points of damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Mesmerizing Feint" title="Greater Mesmerizing Feint" groups="Combat" description="You can feint against nearly any creature.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerizing Feint, Bluff 10 ranks, hypnotic stare class feature, psychic inception bold stare.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can feint against mindless creatures at a &#x2013;4 penalty. Such a creature must be a subject of your hypnotic stare, and the creature has a 50% chance of ignoring the effects of your feint.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Feinting against a creature that is mindless is impossible.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Overrun" title="Greater Overrun" groups="Combat" description="Enemies must dive to avoid your dangerous move.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Overrun, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6, Str 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to overrun a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Overrun. Whenever you overrun opponents, they provoke attacks of opportunity if they are knocked prone by your overrun.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Creatures knocked prone by your overrun do not provoke an attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Penetrating Strike" title="Greater Penetrating Strike" groups="Combat" description="Your attacks penetrate the defenses of most foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Penetrating Strike, Weapon Focus, 16th-level fighter.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your attacks made with weapons selected with Weapon Focus ignore up to 10 points of damage reduction. This amount is reduced to 5 points for damage reduction without a type (such as DR 10/&#x2014;).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Rending Fury" title="Greater Rending Fury" groups="Combat" description="When your claws latch on to an opponent, the effect is bloody and horrific.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Rending Fury, Rending Fury, base attack bonus +12, rend special attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you rend an opponent, you deal 1d6 bleed damage to that opponent. This is an addition to the effects of the rend.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Reposition" title="Greater Reposition" groups="Combat" description="When you reposition foes, they are left vulnerable to the attacks of your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Reposition, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to reposition a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Reposition. Whenever you reposition a foe, his movement provokes attacks of opportunity from all of your allies (but not you).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Creatures moved by reposition do not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Serpent Lash" title="Greater Serpent Lash" groups="Combat" description="Your ability to disarm and pull foes off balance with your whip is impressive.">
		<Prerequisites>Serpent Lash, base attack bonus +4</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you make a successful disarm or trip maneuver using the Serpent Lash feat, you can make your additional disarm or trip attempt against any target within your whip&apos;s reach. With a reposition maneuver, you can move the target creature to any point within your whip&apos;s reach.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Shield Focus" title="Greater Shield Focus" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at deflecting blows with your shield.">
		<Prerequisites>Shield Focus, Shield Proficiency, base attack bonus +1, 8th-level fighter.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Increase the AC bonus granted by any shield you are using by 1. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Shield Focus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Shield Specialization" title="Greater Shield Specialization" groups="Combat" description="Your masterful shieldwork provides even greater protection to your vital areas.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficiency with selected shield, Greater Shield Focus, Shield Focus, Shield Specialization with selected shield, fighter level 12th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one type of shield (buckler, light, heavy, or tower shield) for which you possess the Shield Specialization feat. With the selected shield, you gain a +2 bonus to your Armor Class against critical hit confirmation rolls (this bonus stacks with that from Shield Specialization). In addition, once per day you may negate a critical hit, and damage is instead rolled normally.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of shield.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Skald's Vigor" title="Greater Skald's Vigor" groups="" description="Your song and your enthusiasm invigorate your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Skald&apos;s Vigor, Perform (song) 10 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your allies share in the fast healing granted by your Skald&apos;s Vigor, starting in the round when you begin your performance. They must be able to hear the performance. If you stop maintaining the song, the fast healing ends immediately, even if other effects of your song linger.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Snap Shot" title="Greater Snap Shot" groups="Combat" description="You can prey on any gap in your foe's guard with impunity, and with even greater range.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 17, Improved Snap Shot, Point-Blank Shot, Rapid Shot, Snap Shot, base attack bonus +12.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you make an attack of opportunity using a ranged weapon and hit, you gain a +2 bonus on the damage roll and a +2 bonus on rolls to confirm a critical hit with that attack. These bonuses increase to +4 when you have base attack bonus +16, and to +6 when you have base attack bonus +20.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Spell Focus" title="Greater Spell Focus" groups="" description="Choose a school of magic to which you have already applied the Spell Focus feat. Any spells you cast of this school are very hard to resist. ">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Focus.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Add +1 to the Difficulty Class for all saving throws against spells from the school of magic you select. This bonus stacks with the bonus from Spell Focus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new school to which you already have applied the Spell Focus feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Spell Penetration" title="Greater Spell Penetration" groups="" description="Your spells break through spell resistance much more easily than most.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Penetration.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on caster level checks (1d20 + caster level) made to overcome a creature&apos;s spell resistance. This bonus stacks with the one from Spell Penetration.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Spell Specialization" title="Greater Spell Specialization" groups="" description="You can sacrifice a prepared spell in order to spontaneously cast your specialized spell.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Spell Focus, Spell Specialization, able to prepare 5th-level spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>By sacrificing a prepared spell of the same or higher level than your specialized spell, you may spontaneously cast your specialized spell. The specialized spell is treated as its normal level, regardless of the spell slot used to cast it. You may add a metamagic feat to the spell by increasing the spell slot and casting time, just like a cleric spontaneously casting a cure or inflict spell with a metamagic feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Spring Attack" title="Greater Spring Attack" groups="Combat" description="You are a scything wind cutting through the battlefield as you topple your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 17, Acrobatic Steps, Dodge, Improved Spring Attack, Mobility, Nimble Moves, Spring Attack, base attack bonus +16.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Spring Attack, you can select three targets to attack during your movement instead of one. The second attack made this way is made at your full base attack bonus - 5, and the third attack made this way is made at your full base attack bonus - 10. All restrictions of Spring Attack apply to each target, and your movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity from any of your targets. You can&apos;t target the same creature more than once.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk of at least 18th level can select this feat as a monk bonus feat, but only if he has Improved Spring attack and Spring Attack.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Steal" title="Greater Steal" groups="Combat" description="You have a knack for snatching items from your opponents in combat.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Steal, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to steal an item from a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Steal. If you successfully steal an item from a foe during combat, it does not notice the theft until after combat is over or if it attempts to use the missing item.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Creatures automatically notice items taken from them through the steal combat maneuver.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Subjective Slam" title="Greater Subjective Slam" groups="Combat" description="Your gravitational impact is meteoric, and your ability to use the act of falling devastating.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 15; Wis 15; Subjective Mobility; Subjective Slam; base attack bonus +8 or monk level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Subjective Slam, you take only a &#x2013;1 penalty on the combat maneuver check for every 100 feet of falling speed, and the maximum damage for such a slam increases to 12d6.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Sunder" title="Greater Sunder" groups="Combat" description="Your devastating strikes cleave through weapons and armor and into their wielders, damaging both item and wielder alike in a single terrific strike.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Sunder, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6, Str 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to sunder an item. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Sunder. Whenever you sunder to destroy a weapon, shield, or suit of armor, any excess damage is applied to the item&apos;s wielder. No damage is transferred if you decide to leave the item with 1 hit point.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Tenacious Hunter" title="Greater Tenacious Hunter" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="The animal is capable of savaging hidden foes when they least expect it.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes, Tenacious Hunter, Perception 3 ranks, Stealth 3 ranks, animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The animal companion can attempt a Perception check as a swift action to intentionally search for a stimulus. When using Perception to attempt to pinpoint an invisible foe, the animal companion&apos;s bonus from the Tenacious Hunter feat increases to +20. In addition, whenever the animal companion successfully uses Perception to oppose a Stealth check or to pinpoint an invisible creature&apos;s location, that foe is denied its Dexterity bonus to AC against all attacks that the animal companion makes before the start of the animal companion&apos;s next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Using Perception to intentionally search for a stimulus is a move action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Trip" title="Greater Trip" groups="Combat" description="You can make free attacks on foes that you knock down.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Expertise, Improved Trip, base attack bonus +6, Int 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on checks made to trip a foe. This bonus stacks with the bonus granted by Improved Trip. Whenever you successfully trip an opponent, that opponent provokes attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Creatures do not provoke attacks of opportunity from being tripped.</p>
			<p>FAQ</p>
			<p>The Greater Trip feat allows you to take an attack of opportunity against a foe that you trip. The Vicious Stomp feat allows you to take an attack of opportunity against a foe that falls prone adjacent to you. If you have both these feats and trip a foe, do you get to make two attacks of opportunity (assuming that you can)?</p>
			<p>Yes, the two triggering acts are similar here but they are different. One occurs when you trip a foe. The other occurs when a foe falls prone. It requires a large number of feats to accomplish, but you can really pile on the attacks with this combination.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Two-Weapon Fighting" title="Greater Two-Weapon Fighting" groups="Combat" description="You are incredibly skilled at fighting with two weapons at the same time.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 19, Improved Two-Weapon Fighting, Two-Weapon Fighting, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a third attack with your off-hand weapon, albeit at a -10 penalty.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Vital Strike" title="Greater Vital Strike" groups="Combat" description="You can make a single attack that deals incredible damage.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Vital Strike, Vital Strike, base attack bonus +16.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the attack action, you can make one attack at your highest base attack bonus that deals additional damage. Roll the weapon&apos;s damage dice for the attack four times and add the results together before adding bonuses from Strength, weapon abilities (such as flaming), precision based damage, and other damage bonuses. These extra weapon damage dice are not multiplied on a critical hit, but are added to the total.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Weapon Focus" title="Greater Weapon Focus" groups="Combat" description="Choose one type of weapon (including unarmed strike or grapple) for which you have already selected Weapon Focus. You are a master at your chosen weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficiency with selected weapon, Weapon Focus with selected weapon, base attack bonus +1, 8th-level fighter.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls you make using the selected weapon. This bonus stacks with other bonuses on attack rolls, including those from Weapon Focus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain Greater Weapon Focus multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of weapon.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Weapon Specialization" title="Greater Weapon Specialization" groups="Combat" description="Choose one type of weapon (including unarmed strike or grapple) for which you possess the Weapon Specialization feat. Your attacks with the chosen weapon are more devastating than normal.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficiency with selected weapon, Greater Weapon Focus with selected weapon, Weapon Focus with selected weapon, Weapon Specialization with selected weapon, 12th-level fighter.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on all damage rolls you make using the selected weapon. This bonus to damage stacks with other damage roll bonuses, including any you gain from Weapon Specialization.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain Greater Weapon Specialization multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of weapon.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Weapon of the Chosen" title="Greater Weapon of the Chosen" groups="Combat" description="Your deity guides your hand when you fight with her favored weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Weapon of the Chosen, Weapon Focus with deity&apos;s favored weapon, Weapon of the Chosen, worship and receive spells from a deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use your deity&apos;s favored weapon to attempt a single attack with the attack action, you roll two dice for your attack roll and take the higher result. You do not need to use your Weapon of the Chosen feat to gain this feat&apos;s benefit. As usual, the reroll does not apply to any confirmation rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Whip Mastery" title="Greater Whip Mastery" groups="Combat" description="You can use a whip to make combat maneuvers with ease.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Whip Mastery, Weapon Focus (whip), Whip Mastery, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You are so quick with your whip that you never drop it due to a failed disarm or trip combat maneuver attempt. Further, you gain the ability to grapple using your whip. To do so, use the normal grapple rules with the following changes.</p>
			<p>Attack: You cannot use your whip to attack while you are using it to grapple an opponent.</p>
			<p>Damage: When dealing damage to your grappled opponent, you deal your whip&apos;s weapon damage rather than your unarmed strike damage.</p>
			<p>Free Hands: You take no penalty on your combat maneuver check for having fewer than two hands free when you use your whip to grapple.</p>
			<p>Reach: Rather than pulling your grappled opponent adjacent to you when you successfully grapple and when you move the grapple, you must keep him within your whip&apos;s reach minus his own reach to maintain the grapple. If the difference in reach is less than 0, such as is the case for a Medium whip wielder and a Gargantuan creature, you cannot grapple that opponent with your whip. If you have to pull a creature adjacent to you to grapple it with your whip, you still provoke an attack of opportunity from that opponent unless you have the Improved Grapple feat.</p>
			<p>Tie Up: While adjacent to your opponent, you can attempt to use your whip to tie him up. If you do so to an opponent you have grappled rather than pinned, you take only a -5 penalty on the combat maneuver check rather than the normal -10.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Wild Empathy" title="Greater Wild Empathy" groups="" description="Your natural empathy stretches across the world of nature.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (nature) 5 ranks, wild empathy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 insight bonus on wild empathy checks, and you may use wild empathy to duplicate an Intimidate check rather than a Diplomacy check. In addition, choose one of the following kinds of creatures: elementals, fey, lycanthropes, plants, or vermin. You may influence creatures of that type with wild empathy, if their Intelligence score is 1 or 2, or they do not possess an Intelligence score. Once you choose the type of creature, it cannot be changed.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You may select this feat more than once. Each time, you may choose an additional creature type to influence.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Greater Wilding Strike" title="Greater Wilding Strike" groups="Combat" description="You reach the pinnacle of your wilding strike abilities.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 18, Improved Unarmed Strike, Improved Wilding Strike, Wilding, Wilding Strike, base attack bonus +16.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The damage die of your unarmed strikes increases to 1d10 (or 1d8 if you are Small). This does not stack with any other effects that increase the damage die of your unarmed strikes, including levels in classes such as monk. Increases to your actual size category (such as enlarge person) still increase your damage die as normal.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Green Faith Acolyte" title="Green Faith Acolyte" groups="" description="You have trained to channel your magical energies in ways that do not harm the natural world around you.">
		<Prerequisites>Follower of the Green Faith.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Spells you cast that deal damage, channel negative energy, or otherwise harm life do not hurt normal or magical plants. In addition, whenever you cast a spell that utilizes, heals, or enhances normal or magical plants (such as entangle or plant growth), you cast the spell at +1 caster level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grisly Ornament" title="Grisly Ornament" groups="Item Creation" description="You adorn your gear with mementos from your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Harvest Parts.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can attempt a Craft or Heal check to craft a special type of trophy called an ornament from part of a creature that&apos;s been dead for less than an hour. You take a &#x2013;4 penalty on this check if you or an ally didn&apos;t slay the creature. You can craft one ornament per character level per day. Each corpse provides enough material for one ornament plus one additional ornament per size category above Medium. You can wear one ornament in each magic item slot not already occupied by another item. When you craft an ornament, you choose whether it affects Armor Class, attack rolls, CMB, CMD, saving throws, or skill checks. The ornament provides a morale bonus equal to the monster&apos;s CR divided by 4 (round down, minimum 1) to the selected statistic against creatures of the same creature type as the source of the ornament. This bonus increases by 1 against creatures of the exact same variety (so a red dragon&apos;s talon provides the increased bonus against red dragons but not all dragons). An ornament remains effective for 1 day, plus 1 additional day for every 5 by which you exceed the DC to craft it. You can give ornaments to others, but gifted ornaments have a morale bonus equal to the monster&apos;s CR divided by 6 (round down, minimum 0) and remain effective for only 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ground-Grabber" title="Ground-Grabber" groups="Combat" description="When pressed by big opponents, you hunker down to more easily keep your feet.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 competence bonus to your Combat Maneuver Defense against awesome blow, bull rush, drag, reposition, or trip combat maneuvers from opponents larger than you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Groundling" title="Groundling" groups="" description="You can speak with burrowing animals.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, gnome, gnome magic racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use speak with animals as a spell-like ability at will, but only to communicate with burrowing animals like gophers, moles, and the like. You can still use your gnome speak with animals ability once per day to speak with any animal, as usual.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Group Deliver Touch Spells" title="Group Deliver Touch Spells" groups="Teamwork" description="You and your teammates can deliver touch spells through each other's familiars.">
		<Prerequisites>Group Shared Spells, must have a familiar with the share spells and deliver touch spells abilities.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You and any allies with this feat can cast spells through one another&apos;s familiars as though each ally had the share spells ability with each other familiar. This feat otherwise functions as the share spells ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Group Shared Spells" title="Group Shared Spells" groups="Teamwork" description="You and your allies can cast spells through each other's familiars as if they were your own.">
		<Prerequisites>Familiar with the share spells ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You and any of your allies with this feat can cast spells with a target of &#x201C;you&#x201D; on each other&apos;s familiars as touch spells. Both the target familiar and that familiar&apos;s master must be willing for the spell to take effect. You can cast spells on each other&apos;s familiars even if the spells would not normally affect creatures of the targeted familiar&apos;s type.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grow Plant Creature" title="Grow Plant Creature" groups="Item Creation" description="Through careful study and communion with nature, you have learned how to cultivate and raise plant creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Train Plants, Handle Animal 5 ranks, Knowledge (nature) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can grow plants and perform rituals to invest them with animating spirits, becoming assassin vines, treants, or viper vines. Each plant creature has a list of additional prerequisites, costs, and skill checks required to grow them (see Growing Plant Creatures below). At the GM&apos;s discretion, characters with this feat may grow other plant creatures as well.</p>
			<p>The process of growing a plant companion is very similar to the process of growing a leshy. The creator begins by growing an array of especially verdant plants, and then performs rituals to have a spirit of nature inhabit it. Typically, the creator is a powerful druid, but anyone capable of making the required Knowledge checks and casting the required spells may attempt the process.Cultivated minions closely resemble more familiar plant creatures&#x2014; and share the same stat blocks&#x2014;but are approximated copies woven from horticulture and magic.An &apos;assassin vine&apos; cultivated by a druid using the Grow Plant Creature feat isn&apos;t a true assassin vine, and the seeds it produces would sprout into mundane ivy, grape vines, or similar vines originally used to construct it. At the GM&apos;s discretion, this may allow druids to grow plant minions with special abilities, such as a peach treant who produces fruit or a viper vine woven from stinging nettles whose touch causes burning welts. Such adjustments should always increase the cost to create a plant creature, and should adjust their challenge rating if they greatly expand the minion&apos;s combat abilities or utility.Growing a plant creature takes 2 weeks per Hit Die, during which the creator must fertilize, water, and protect the growth. During this period, the creator must use certain rare nutrients and fertilizer to prime the transformation from a normal plant into a plant creature&#x2014;the cost of these components varies according to the type, but is never less than 1,000 gp per Hit Die.The cultivator must succeed at a Knowledge (nature) check at this time in order to properly form the plant body&#x2014;the exact check as well as the required DC varies according to the creature. If the check fails, the plant withers and dies and the cultivator must begin anew.If the skill check is successful, the cultivator must then perform a 24-hour awakening ritual. During this ritual, the cultivator must cast the spells detailed in each individual creature&apos;s entry. At the awakening ritual&apos;s climax, there is a flat 50% chance that the attempt to create the creature succeeds&#x2014;if this final check fails, no appropriate spirit is close enough to answer the call. The plant body becomes dormant, and remains so for 3 months. After this time, another awakening ritual can be performed (requiring another 1,000 gp of materials); this new ritual also has a flat 50% chance of success. At the GM&apos;s discretion, the awakening ritual&apos;s chance for success might increase to 75% or even 100% in natural and unspoiled environments appropriate to the individual creature. Discovering such a rare and magical site should be the focus of its own adventure. If the awakening ritual is successful, the creature awakens fully formed. A freshly created plant creature is under no particular compulsion to obey its creator, but most regard their makers as friends and allies.Plant creatures are particularly adept at growing other plant creatures of the same type. Sentient creatures of the plant type gain a +5 racial bonus on their Knowledge (nature) checks to cultivate other plant creatures, halve the time required to grow the creature, and reduce the materials cost by 25%. A plant creature improves the success chance of any awakening ritual it personally performs by 5% per Hit Die it possesses.At the GM&apos;s discretion, it may be possible to create plant creatures with more Hit Dice than normal. Each additional Hit Die adds 2,250 gp to the cost of creating it (and thus 4,500 gp to the overall price), increases the DC of the Knowledge check by 2, and requires an additional 2 weeks of growth.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Grudge Fighter" title="Grudge Fighter" groups="Combat,Orc" description="You feel great anger at anyone who dares to attack you, and this fury makes your own attacks that much stronger.">
		<Prerequisites>Orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 morale bonus on attack and damage rolls made against any creature that attacked you in the current combat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gruesome Slaughter" title="Gruesome Slaughter" groups="Combat" description="You can inspire extreme revulsion when you slaughter your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidating Prowess, Killing Flourish, Intimidate 11 ranks, slayer level 11th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Creatures you demoralize by using the Killing Flourish feat must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + the higher of your Strength or Dexterity modifier) or become sickened for 1 minute.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Guardian of the Wild" title="Guardian of the Wild" groups="Elf" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Attuned to the Wild, elf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are in a terrain type you have selected the Attuned to the Wild feat for, you gain a +2 dodge bonus to Armor Class. If you are in an area that qualifies as more than one kind of terrain, these bonuses do not stack; you receive the bonus for only one of the terrain types.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Guided Hand" title="Guided Hand" groups="" description="Your deity blesses any strike you make with that deity's favored weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature, Channel Smite, proficiency with your deity&apos;s favored weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With your deity&apos;s favored weapon, you can use your Wisdom modifier instead of your Strength or Dexterity modifier on attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Guided Star Combat" title="Guided Star Combat" groups="Combat" description="The grace of the associated deity guides your starknife to its target and back to your hand.">
Note This is associated with a specific deity.
		<Prerequisites>Starry Grace, worshiper of the associated deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can empower a starknife with magical power once per day per character level as a swift action.</p>
			<p>Until the end of your turn, add your Wisdom modifier to your damage rolls with the starknife in addition to any other modifiers you normally add. If you throw the starknife during that time, it returns to you at the beginning of your next turn (as per the returning weapon special ability).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Guild Partner" title="Guild Partner" groups="" description="You have earned the attention of your guild and can call in favors when necessary.">
		<Prerequisites>Associate (a guild).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are in a settlement that is the size of small town or larger, you can purchase (but not sell) items through your contacts. Treat your current settlement as though it were a metropolis to determine its base value and available magic items. You pay a 5% markup for such items, and orders take 3d6 days to be delivered through guild channels. You can pay an additional 1,000 gp to have your item magically delivered in 1d3 days instead.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gun Twirling" title="Gun Twirling" groups="Grit" description="You can spin and juggle a small firearm, making it difficult to predict where you will shoot.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Gunslinger feat or grit class feature, Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can spend 1 grit point to make a feint attempt using a one-handed firearm for which you have Weapon Focus (instead of a melee weapon). The target of this feint must be within 30 feet of you and be able to see you.</p>
			<p>If you have the Quick Draw feat, you can holster a one-handed firearm as a free action as long as you have at least 1 grit point.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gunslinger" title="Gunslinger" groups="3.5E" description="You are so skilled with firearms that you can fire one without letting down your guard.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +4, Weapon Focus (any firearm), proficiency with any firearm.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you attack with a firearm, you do not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Attacking with any kind of ranged weapon in a threatened square provokes attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gunsmithing" title="Gunsmithing" groups="" description="You know the secrets of repairing and restoring firearms.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you have access to a gunsmith&apos;s kit, you can create and restore firearms, craft bullets, and mix black powder for all types of firearms. You do not need to make a Craft check to create firearms and ammunition or to restore firearms.</p>
			<p>Crafting Firearms: You can craft any early firearm for a cost in raw materials equal to half the price of the firearm. At your GM&apos;s discretion, you can craft advanced firearms for a cost in raw materials equal to half the price of the firearm. Crafting a firearm in this way takes 1 day of work for every 1,000 gp of the firearm&apos;s price (minimum 1 day).</p>
			<p>Crafting Ammunition: You can craft bullets, pellets, and black powder for a cost in raw materials equal to 10% of the price. If you have at least 1 rank in Craft (alchemy), you can craft alchemical cartridges for a cost in raw materials equal to half the price of the cartridge. At your GM&apos;s discretion, you can craft metal cartridges for a cost in raw materials equal to half the cost of the cartridge. Crafting bullets, black powder, or cartridges takes 1 day of work for every 1,000 gp of ammunition (minimum 1 day).</p>
			<p>Restoring a Broken Firearm: Each day, with an hour&apos;s worth of work, you can use this feat to repair a single firearm with the broken condition. You can take time during a rest period to restore a broken firearm with this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are a gunslinger, this feat grants the following additional benefit. You can use this feat to repair and restore your initial, battered weapon. It costs 300 gp and 1 day of work to upgrade it to a masterwork firearm of its type.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Halfling Slinger" title="Halfling Slinger" groups="Combat" description="You have honed your racial talent for slingcraft.">
		<Prerequisites>Halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 racial bonus on attack rolls made using a sling.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hamatula Grasp" title="Hamatula Grasp" groups="Combat" description="You deal terrible damage to impaled foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Hamatula Strike, Improved Grapple, Strength 13, Base Attack Bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When attacking an impaled opponent (see Hamatula Strike) with the weapon that impales them, you only suffer a -2 penalty to your grapple check. If the check succeeds, you deal an extra 1d6 damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hamatula Strike" title="Hamatula Strike" groups="Combat" description="You can catch your opponents on your weapon and hold them in place.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Grapple, Strength 13, Base Attack Bonus +7.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you damage an opponent with a piercing weapon, you can immediately make a grapple check; success means the opponent is impaled on your weapon and you both gain the grappled condition. While the opponent is impaled, as an attack action you may make a grapple check on your turn at a -4 penalty to damage the opponent with your weapon, even if your weapon cannot normally be used in a grapple.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only attack with an unarmed strike, natural weapon, or light weapon against opponents you are grappling.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hamatulatsu" title="Hamatulatsu" groups="Combat" description="You have mastered a deadly fighting form inspired by the hideous attacks of the barbed devil.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Weapon Focus (unarmed strike).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your unarmed attacks can deal either bludgeoning or piercing damage. You decide which type of damage you deal whenever you attack a foe, but you may only choose one type at a time. If you critically hit a foe with your unarmed strike while doing piercing damage, the additional pain caused by the strike causes the foe to become sickened for 1 round (or staggered for 1 round if the target is already sickened). Multiple critical hits in a round against a single foe do not increase the duration of the sickened or staggered condition.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Hamatulatsu may be selected as a substitute bonus feat at 6th level by a monk even if the monk does not otherwise meet the prerequisites. This fighting style is normally only taught to women of a specific fighting school.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: By spending 5 stamina points, you can treat a hit with an unarmed strike as a critical hit for the purpose of determining the benefits that you gain from Hamatulatsu.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hammer Throw" title="Hammer Throw" groups="Combat" description="You can throw a hammer with such force that it knocks your foes over.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Trip, Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot, base attack bonus +1, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make a single ranged attack with a weapon that deals bludgeoning damage against a creature no more than one size category larger than you that is within the weapon&apos;s first range increment.</p>
			<p>If you hit and damage the target, you can immediately attempt to perform a trip combat maneuver against that target. This does not provoke an attack of opportunity, and if your combat maneuver check fails by 10 or more, you do not fall prone.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hammer the Gap" title="Hammer the Gap" groups="Combat" description="You repeatedly strike the same location, causing increasing amounts of damage.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you take a full-attack action, each consecutive hit against the same opponent deals extra damage equal to the number of previous consecutive hits you have made against that opponent this turn. This damage is multiplied on a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hand's Autonomy" title="Hand's Autonomy" groups="" description="Your possessed hand can act independently.">
		<Prerequisites>Possessed Hand.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You reduce the penalties for fighting with two weapons (including fighting with double weapons or when throwing weapons from each hand) by 2, to a minimum penalty of &#x2013;1. This benefit stacks with the Two-Weapon Fighting feat. When you are unconscious, paralyzed, asleep, or stunned, your possessed hand can still act on your behalf in a limited fashion. The hand uses your statistics when performing any action in this manner. The hand can&apos;t take attacks of opportunity, but can draw attacks of opportunity from actions it takes. The hand can perform the following actions each turn on your initiative count.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hand's Detachment" title="Hand's Detachment" groups="" description="Your possessed hand can painlessly pull free of your body or reattach itself, leaving you with a bloodless but raw-looking stump at the end of one arm while the hand itself performs remote tasks under your command, acting in many ways like a strange familiar.">
		<Prerequisites>Hand&apos;s Autonomy, Possessed Hand.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can remove your possessed hand, allowing the possessing spirit to animate and control its motion.</p>
			<p>Removing or reattaching your possessed hand is a full-round action. This deals no damage to you, but you can&apos;t use the hand while it is removed. The hand acts as a wizard&apos;s familiar, using your character level as your effective wizard level, except it doesn&apos;t gain the alertness, share spells, deliver touch spells, spell resistance, or scry on familiar abilities. Use the statistics for a crawling hand to represent the detached hand, save that the hand isn&apos;t undead, doesn&apos;t have the mark quarry ability, and shares your alignment. If the hand is destroyed, the spirit regenerates your missing hand in 2d4 days. This process can be accelerated by regenerate or similar magic. You cannot use the Possessed Hand feat or any feat with the Possessed Hand feat as a prerequisite until the hand is fully regenerated.</p>
			<p>If you have the familiar class feature, you can choose for your possessed hand to become your familiar, granting it all familiar abilities as normal. If selected as a familiar, your possessed hand grants you a +3 bonus on Sleight of Hand checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hand's Knowledge" title="Hand's Knowledge" groups="" description="The connection to the memories of the spirit possessing your hand deepens.">
		<Prerequisites>Possessed Hand.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one Knowledge skill; this skill becomes a class skill for you. Additionally, select one of the following skills: Disable Device, Escape Artist, Heal, Sleight of Hand, or Use Magic Device. This skill becomes a class skill for you and you can attempt checks with the skill untrained.</p>
			<p>Once per day as a swift action, you can gain a bonus to any of the above skill checks equal to 1/2 your character level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hand's Sight" title="Hand's Sight" groups="" description="By manifesting an eerie, spiritual eye of its own, your possessed hand can â€œseeâ€ on your behalf.">
		<Prerequisites>Possessed Hand.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While your possessed hand isn&apos;t carrying anything, you gain darkvision with a range of 60 feet and cannot be flanked.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hard-headed" title="Hard-headed" groups="Combat,Dwarf" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls and combat maneuver checks made using a helmet. You receive a +2 bonus on saves against spells and special abilities that cause you to become staggered or stunned.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Harder They Fall" title="Harder They Fall" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You can work with an ally to move or knock over a foe that's too large for either of you to overcome alone.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Int 13, Combat Expertise, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the aid another action to grant an ally who also has this feat a +2 bonus on a bull rush or trip combat maneuver check, the ally can attempt that maneuver even against foes two or more size categories larger than herself.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Harmonic Sage" title="Harmonic Sage" groups="" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Bardic performance class feature, Knowledge (engineering) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While inside an artificial structure, you can spend a free action to make a DC 15 Knowledge (engineering) check when you begin your bardic performance. Success on this check allows you to do one of the following.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A bardic performance lasts only as long as you maintain it.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Harmonic Spell" title="Harmonic Spell" groups="" description="You can weave bardic music effects into your spellcasting in such a way that your spellcasting and bardic performance become indistinguishable.">
		<Prerequisites>Bardic performance ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you cast a 1st or higher level spell while you are maintaining a bardic performance, you can maintain the bardic performance for that round without expending one of your rounds of performance for the day. In addition, you can switch from one bardic performance to another as a swift action when you cast a spell while maintaining a bardic performance.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Harrowed" title="Harrowed" groups="" description="Numerous Harrow readings early in your life seem to have hit the mark precisely, increasing your belief that you are destined for a specific purpose in life.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +1 bonus on all Will saves made to resist enchantment effects. Once per day, you may draw a card from a Harrow deck you own. At any one time for the rest of that day, you may apply a +2 bonus on any d20 roll modified by the card&apos;s suit. For example, if you drew a card from the suit of Dexterity, you could apply this +2 bonus on an Initiative check, a Reflex save, a Dexterity-based skill check, or a ranged attack roll. You may assign this +2 bonus after you make the roll, but you must do so before you know whether the roll was a success or not.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Harrowed Summoning" title="Harrowed Summoning" groups="" description="Your summoned creatures are empowered by the magic of the harrow.">
		<Prerequisites>Harrowed.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast a conjuration (summoning) spell or use a spell-like ability to summon one or more creatures, you can draw two random cards from a complete harrow deck you own. Doing so adds both a somatic component (if the spell does not already have one) and a focus component (the harrow deck) to the spell, but does not increase the spell&apos;s casting time.</p>
			<p>For the duration of the spell, each summoned creature gains a +4 enhancement bonus to the corresponding ability scores of the drawn card&apos;s suits. If both cards are the same suit, each summoned creature gains a +6 bonus to that ability score instead. If either card&apos;s alignment is a true match for the summoned creatures&apos; alignment, the duration of the spell is doubled, while drawing an opposite match halves the duration of the spell. If both a true match and an opposite match are drawn, the spell&apos;s duration is unchanged.</p>
			<p>A creature summoned in this way is distinctly altered by the cards drawn. Its physical appearance reflects the visual elements of the cards. The creature&apos;s personality is also influenced by the cards, but not so much as to alter its alignment.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Harrying Partners" title="Harrying Partners" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="Your movements perfectly synchronize with your ally's to greater effect.">
		<Prerequisites>Any teamwork feat, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully use the aid another action to improve the Armor Class or attack roll of an ally who also has this feat, the benefit from aid another lasts until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The bonus granted by aid another either grants your ally a +2 bonus on her next attack roll against an opponent or grants your ally a +2 bonus to AC against that opponent&apos;s next attack made before the beginning of your next turn.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Haruspicy" title="Haruspicy" groups="" description="You observe the signs of the universe by studying how spilled blood and viscera fall, learning insights into how to best appease unseen forces.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (religion) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you perform a successful coup de grace, you gain a +2 circumstance bonus on skill checks attempted as part of a single occult ritual or occult skill unlock performed within the next minute. Alternatively, you can instead gain a +1 caster level bonus on a single divination or necromancy spell. The ritual or spell must begin within 1 minute of the coup de grace.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Haunt Scavenger" title="Haunt Scavenger" groups="Item Creation" description="You can use spiritual essence to craft magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Any one item creation feat or Craft (alchemy) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can harvest the ectoplasmic remains of haunts, incorporeal undead, or the like to craft magic items.</p>
			<p>Whenever you encounter a recently neutralized haunt, the remains of an incorporeal undead creature, or the remains of a creature that has the ability to possess another creature using a racial spell-like ability or supernatural ability (such as a ghost or a shadow demon), you can attempt to extract material components from those remains that are suitable for crafting magic items. You must have access to an alchemist&apos;s lab in order to extract components from a haunt or creature, and you must begin extracting these components within 10 minutes of the haunt or creature&apos;s death or destruction.</p>
			<p>After 10 minutes, the components have degraded too much to be of any use to you.</p>
			<p>Harvesting components with this feat can take several hours. Performing at least 1 minute of work extracting components from a haunt or creature prevents its material components from degrading further for 24 hours, allowing you to safely suspend and resume harvesting these components without fear of subsequent degradation. This ectoplasmic residue is portable once the extraction work begins, provided you have a vial to contain the source residue (the actual amount of residue is never much, physically, but the value of the components you can extract from the residue increases with the power of the original haunt or creature).</p>
			<p>Each hour, attempt a Craft (alchemy) or a Knowledge (religion) check to successfully handle the residue and extract useful material. The DC for this check is equal to 15 + the CR of the haunt or creature being harvested.</p>
			<p>If you succeed at the check, you harvest 50 gp worth of components. If you fail the check by 4 or less, you can attempt to harvest those components again.</p>
			<p>If you fail the check by 5 or more, the residue spoils and you cannot scavenge any more from that particular source. A single source can yield an amount of components up to a maximum value of 50 gp per point of CR before it is depleted.</p>
			<p>Material components harvested with Haunt Scavenger can be used in place of the material components of enchantment or necromancy spells and extracts, provided they are of equal or greater value compared to the spell&apos;s normal material components.</p>
			<p>Additionally, they can be used in place of actual gold to fund the construction of a magic item with an enchantment or necromancy aura.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Haunted Gnome" title="Haunted Gnome" groups="Combat" description="You use your gnome magic to take on an eerie illusory appearance.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, gnome magic racial trait, Knowledge (arcana) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You add haunted fey aspect to your list of gnome magic spell-like abilities, and you can use this spell-like ability twice per day.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Haunted Gnome Assault" title="Haunted Gnome Assault" groups="Combat" description="Discharging your disturbing glamer as you strike a telling blow, you haunt a foe with lingering fear.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, gnome magic racial trait, Haunted Gnome, Knowledge (arcana) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one use of your gnome magic that is independent of your gnome magic spell-like abilities. When you wish to cast a gnome magic spell-like ability for which you have no daily uses remaining, you can expend this independent use to do so.</p>
			<p>Further, while you are under the effect of haunted fey aspect, you can discharge that spell as a free action after you hit an opponent with a charge attack or score a critical hit against an opponent. If you do, that opponent becomes shaken for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Haunted Gnome Shroud" title="Haunted Gnome Shroud" groups="Combat" description="Your disturbing glamer expands to make your exact location hard to pinpoint.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, gnome magic racial trait, Haunted Gnome, Haunted Gnome Assault, Knowledge (arcana) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain another independent use of your gnome magic like that which Haunted Gnome Assault grants. Further, while you are under the effect of haunted fey aspect, you also have concealment (20% miss chance) against an opponent until that opponent deals you damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heavenly Radiance" title="Heavenly Radiance" groups="Aasimar" description="Your heavenly light can be used in a variety of ways.">
		<Prerequisites>Aasimar, daylight spell-like ability, sufficiently high level (see below).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional use per day of daylight. Choose one spell from the table below; by expending a use of daylight, you may use this spell as a spell-like ability. To select a spell, you must meet the minimum character level for its listing in the table. The save DC for this spell is Charisma-based.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You may take this feat multiple times. Each time you select it, you gain an additional use of daylight and may select another spell from the table.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heavy Gravity Acclimation" title="Heavy Gravity Acclimation" groups="" description="Your muscles work overtime in areas with heavy gravity.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 17 or Endurance.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You do not take the normal penalties for being on heavy gravity planes. At the GM&apos;s discretion, this effect may apply to certain environments on the Material Plane, such as high-gravity planets. In addition, your Strength is considered to be 4 higher for the purpose of determining your carrying capacity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hefty Brute" title="Hefty Brute" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="You might be a different subspecies or simply a well-fed and well-grown beast, but either way you're built on a more massive scale than the rest of your kind.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion or familiar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat your size as one category larger for the purposes of calculating CMB, CMD, carrying capacity, and any size-based special attacks you use or that are used against you (such as grab, swallow whole, and trample).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heighten Spell" title="Heighten Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can cast spells as if they were a higher level.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>A heightened spell has a higher spell level than normal (up to a maximum of 9th level). Unlike other metamagic feats, Heighten Spell actually increases the effective level of the spell that it modifies. All effects dependent on spell level (such as saving throw DCs and ability to penetrate a lesser globe of invulnerability) are calculated according to the heightened level.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: The heightened spell is as difficult to prepare and cast as a spell of its effective level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hell Knight Aegis" title="Hell Knight Aegis" groups="" description="Your armor guards you against many threats.">
		<Prerequisites>Heavy Armor Proficiency, base attack bonus +5, must swear allegiance to a Hell Knight order.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day as a full-round action, you can give your Hell Knight armor the broken condition. Upon doing so, you are affected by one of the following spells (your choice), using your character level as your caster level: break enchantment, neutralize poison, remove disease, or remove paralysis. Once you have used this benefit, your armor must be repaired as normal to restore its full bonus to your Armor Class and return its armor check penalty to normal.</p>
			<p>You can use this ability even if paralyzed or otherwise restrained, but not if you are unconscious. For the purposes of this ability, &#x201C;Hell Knight armor&#x201D; means any armor with &#x201C;Hell Knight&#x201D; in its name. You cannot use this ability if your armor is already broken.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hell Knight Obedience" title="Hell Knight Obedience" groups="" description="Performing daily reckonings grants you special boons.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (planes) 3 ranks, must swear allegiance to a single Hell Knight order.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Upon taking this feat, you gain proficiency in all of your Hell Knight order&apos;s favored weapons. Additionally, by meditating and inflicting strenuous reckonings upon yourself, you unlock the power behind your order&apos;s doctrine. Each Hell Knight order has its own unique reckoning&#x2014;a trial of obedience and pain (described in Hell Knight order). When coupled with the necessary reflection and meditation, this reckoning takes 1 hour per day to perform. Once you have performed your order&apos;s reckoning, you gain the benefit of a special ability as indicated in the Reckoning entry for the Hell Knight order to which you&apos;ve sworn allegiance. If you have at least 12 Hit Dice, you also gain the first boon granted by the Hell Knight order. If you have at least 16 Hit Dice, you also gain the Hell Knight order&apos;s second boon. If you have 20 Hit Dice or more, you also gain the Hell Knight order&apos;s third boon. Unless a specific duration or number of uses per day is listed in a boon&apos;s description, the boon&apos;s effects are constant.</p>
			<p>If you ever fail to perform a daily reckoning, you lose all access to the benefits and boons granted by this feat until you next perform the reckoning.</p>
			<p>You can take this feat only if you are associated with a Hell Knight order, whether you&apos;re in training to become a Hell Knight, already a member, or otherwise aligned with the order&#x2014;the specifics are left to you and the GM to determine. Once per year, you can change your Hell Knight allegiance, but doing so requires the approval of the Hell Knight order you wish to join. If you are ever cast out of the Hell Knight order to which you&apos;ve sworn allegiance, you lose the benefits of this feat until you restore yourself in the Hell Knights&apos; esteem. The details of this are left to the GM&apos;s discretion.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hell Knight Obsession" title="Hell Knight Obsession" groups="" description="You equate pain with discipline and can inflict damage upon yourself to unlock greater power.">
		<Prerequisites>Hell Knight Obedience, Knowledge (planes) 3 ranks, must swear allegiance to a single Hell Knight order.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>During your hour-long reckoning, if you choose to deal lethal damage to yourself, you reach a state of fantastic focus. Once during the next 24 hours, you can draw upon this focus to gain the benefits of any one of the following effects. To activate the ability, you must deal 1 point of lethal damage to yourself as a swift action (unless otherwise noted). Members of the Order of the Nail often install a sharp barb within their armor that deals this damage when the wearer is subject to a critical hit; if you&apos;re struck by a critical hit while wearing such armor, using this ability doesn&apos;t require a swift action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hellcat Pounce" title="Hellcat Pounce" groups="Combat" description="You attack unsuspecting foes twice.">
		<Prerequisites>Hellcat Stealth, Skill Focus (Stealth), sneak attack +2d6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you attack and damage an opponent in the surprise round, you may immediately make a second attack against the same opponent using the same attack bonus. The target is not considered flat-footed against this second attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This ability only functions when carrying a light load or less.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hellcat Stealth" title="Hellcat Stealth" groups="" description="You are difficult to see in the light.">
		<Prerequisites>Skill Focus (Stealth), Stealth 6 ranks. </Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may make Stealth checks in normal or bright light even when observed, but at a -10 penalty. </p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You cannot make Stealth checks while observed.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Helpless Prisoner" title="Helpless Prisoner" groups="" description="You can talk your way out of most restraints.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 5 ranks, Escape Artist 1 rank, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are restrained or imprisoned, you can make a Bluff check against any one creature within 30 feet in which you emphasize both your own harmlessness and the pain or inconvenience of your current condition. If the creature knows you are dangerous, it adds a +4 bonus to its Sense Motive check. If you win the check, the target does something intended to make you a little more comfortable&#x2014;or at least shut you up&#x2014;that gives you a +5 bonus on your next Escape Artist check.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>At the GM&apos;s discretion, an especially evil or cruel creature may gain a +2 bonus to its Sense Motive check to resist this ability. If it succeeds, it does something to make your bindings even more secure and less comfortable, giving you a &#x2013;5 penalty on all Escape Artist checks made in those particular bonds.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hemorrhaging Venom" title="Hemorrhaging Venom" groups="Combat" description="Your venom destroys blood vessels and melts bone.">
		<Prerequisites>Spit Venom, Virulent Venom, base attack bonus +7, nagaji.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your ability to spit poison granted by the Spit Venom feat deals 2d6 points of bleed damage on a failed saving throw in addition to all other effects. The bleeding can be stopped as normal with a successful DC 15 Heal check or the application of any effect that heals hit point damage. In addition, you gain one additional use per day of the ability to spit poison granted by the Spit Venom feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hero's Display" title="Hero's Display" groups="Combat, Performance" description="With a dramatic flourish you display your weapons to the crowd. Onlookers are elated, and your enemies are demoralized.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus, and proficiency with the selected weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you spend a swift action to make a performance combat check, you present the weapon in which you have Weapon Focus in a triumphant display. You gain a +2 bonus on the performance combat check and make an Intimidate check to demoralize all foes within 30 feet who can see your display.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hero's Fortune" title="Hero's Fortune" groups="Luck" description="Even at the start of your career, it was clear that you had a chance at greatness, and your legend continues to grow with every adventure.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a hero point. The maximum number of hero points you can have at any one time is increased to 5.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can have no more than 3 hero points at one time.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>NPCs who take this Feat receive 1 hero point and can have up to 3 (not 5).</p>
			<p>Note: See Hero Points for full details.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heroic Defiance" title="Heroic Defiance" groups="" description="You struggle on when others would fall.">
		<Prerequisites>Diehard, Endurance, base Fortitude save +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day as an immediate action you can delay the onset of one harmful condition or affliction (such as panicked, paralyzed, stunned, and so on), including permanent and instantaneous conditions. Activating this feat delays the onset of the condition until the end of your next turn, after which time the condition takes its normal effect. This feat has no effect on hit point damage or ability damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heroic Interposition" title="Heroic Interposition" groups="Combat" description="You arrive just when you are most needed to vanquish evil.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Dodge, Improved Initiative, Mobility, worshiper of an empyreal lord.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can move up to your speed as an immediate action, but you must end this movement adjacent to an opponent who is about to make an attack against an ally. As long as you are visible to the opponent you moved next to, that opponent takes a -2 penalty on the attack roll to which you moved in response.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: By spending 4 stamina points, you can use this feat an additional time per day.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heroic Leader" title="Heroic Leader" groups="Combat" description="Whether part of a partnership or an army, you stand head and shoulders above your companions.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13; any combat feat; ability to gain an animal companion, cohort, eidolon, familiar, or mount.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your animal companion, cohort, eidolon, familiar, or mount doesn&apos;t count as threatening your opponent for the purposes of feats that require you to be the only character threatening a target. Allies with Hit Dice equal to or less than 1/2 your own Hit Dice don&apos;t count as threatening opponents for the purposes of such feats.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heroic Recovery" title="Heroic Recovery" groups="" description="You can throw off the effects of crippling conditions.">
		<Prerequisites>Diehard, Endurance, base Fortitude save +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day as a standard action you may attempt a new saving throw against a harmful condition or affliction requiring a Fortitude save that is affecting you. If this save against the affliction fails, there is no additional effect, but a successful save counts toward curing an affliction such as poison or disease. You cannot use this feat to recover from instantaneous effects, effects that do not allow a saving throw, or effects that do not require a Fortitude save.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Heroic Will" title="Heroic Will" groups="Human" description="Your indomitable will breaks free from mental shackles.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will, base Will save +4, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day as a standard action, you may attempt a new saving throw against a harmful condition requiring a Will save that is affecting you. If you are dominated, controlled, or cannot take an action because of the effect against which you are trying to make a new saving throw, you can make this saving throw at the start of the turn as no action, but on a success, your turn ends. You cannot use this feat to remove instantaneous effects, effects that do not require a Will save, or effects that do not allow a saving throw.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hex Strike" title="Hex Strike" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Hex class feature, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you gain this feat, choose one hex that you can use to affect no more than one opponent. If you make a successful unarmed strike against an opponent, in addition to dealing your unarmed strike damage, you can use a swift action to deliver the effects of the chosen hex to that opponent. Doing so does not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you take it, you apply it to a different qualifying hex.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hidden Presence" title="Hidden Presence" groups="" description="You are adept at hiding within your host.">
		<Prerequisites>Int or Cha 17, ability to cast possession or greater possession.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While possessing another creature, you can hide yourself from divinations and pass through wards such as magic circle against evil or the effects of a forbiddance spell. You must attempt a Will save against the spell (even if it doesn&apos;t normally allow a saving throw). If you succeed, the spell treats you as if you were your host (for instance, divinations would reveal only the host&apos;s alignment, and forbiddance keyed to the host&apos;s alignment wouldn&apos;t damage you). If your saving throw fails, the spell functions against you as normal; if the spell normally allows a save, your previous failure doesn&apos;t count as a failed save against the spell&apos;s normal effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hide Worker" title="Hide Worker" groups="" description="You excel at crafting armor made from the hides of animals or monsters.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (armor) 3 ranks, Knowledge (nature) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 bonus on Craft (armor) checks to create armor or shields from the hides of living creatures (such as dragonhide). If you succeed at a Craft (armor) check to create armor or shields from the hides of living creatures by 5 or more, you also decrease the cost to make the item by 10%.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hide-Out" title="Hide-Out" groups="" description="You have a hide-out you can seek refuge in when needed.">
		<Prerequisites>Associate (an assassins guild).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Anyone attempting Diplomacy or Survival checks to locate you takes a &#x2013;10 penalty, and anyone attempting to scry upon you or magically divine your location must first succeed at a caster level check (DC = 15 + your character level). You can stay in your hide-out for up to 1 day per character level before you are forced to vacate.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="High Magic Focus" title="High Magic Focus" groups="Teamwork" description="With the help of your fellow scholars, you can cast higher forms of magic, enhancing your spells by drawing upon their magical reserves rather than your own.">
		<Prerequisites>Any metamagic feat, Spellcraft 7 ranks, ability to cast 2nd-level spells, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With the help of allies who also have this feat, you can spontaneously apply metamagic feats to your spells without using a higher-level slot or increasing the casting time. Each ally must ready an action to cast the same spell you intend to cast. For each other ally within 30 feet who does so, you reduce the cost of the spontaneous metamagic feat by 1 level (to a minimum of 0, and you must have at least one ally assist you, even if the metamagic feat is normally a +0 adjustment). The allies don&apos;t need to have the metamagic feat you choose to apply, and the effective level of the spell (after applying the metamagic feat) can&apos;t be higher than the highest level of spells you can cast.</p>
			<p>Lastly, when you use this ability, the spell each ally readies is lost, as if they had cast that spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hindrance Dismissal" title="Hindrance Dismissal" groups="" description="You've mastered the art of dismissing certain spells when they become a problem for you or your allies. ">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can dismiss any pit spell (such as create pit, hungry pit, spiked pit, and similar spells with &#x2018;pit&apos; in their names) or wall spell (such as wall of fire, wall of ice, and similar spells with &#x2018;wall&apos; in their names) you cast. The spells must have a duration of at least 1 round. This ability follows the normal rules for dismissing spells, allowing you to dismiss conjured pits and walls as a standard action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Several pit and wall spells cannot be dismissed without the use of this feat.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hobgoblin Discipline" title="Hobgoblin Discipline" groups="Hobgoblin" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, Hobgoblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are within 30 feet of at least two other hobgoblins, you gain a +1 morale bonus on saving throws.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hold the Blade" title="Hold the Blade" groups="Combat" description="You can take your opponent's weapon after being stabbed in the back.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Disarm, base attack bonus +10.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever an enemy deals damage to you with a melee weapon as part of a flanking attack or sneak attack, you can make a combat maneuver check to disarm against that opponent as an immediate action. You must have at least one hand free when you use this feat. When you use this feat, you take a -4 penalty to your AC until your next turn. You can only use this feat once per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hook Fighter" title="Hook Fighter" groups="Combat" description="In your deft hands, a climbing tool becomes a deadly weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat a grappling hook as a one-handed weapon that deals piercing damage equal to a heavy pick of its size and that has the disarm and trip special weapon features. You do not incur penalties as you would for using a grappling hook as an improvised weapon. If you are proficient with whips and your grappling hook has at least 10 feet of rope or chain attached to it, you can treat it as a two-handed melee weapon with 15-foot reach, though you can use it against foes anywhere within your reach (including adjacent foes), though you don&apos;t threaten any squares with it.</p>
			<p>Changing between using a grappling hook as a normal weapon and a reach weapon is a move action. When performing a reposition maneuver with a grappling hook, you can only move the target toward you from its original position.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Horde Charge" title="Horde Charge" groups="Teamwork,Orc/Half-Orc" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, half-orc or orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When charging during the same round as an ally with this feat, you gain a +2 bonus on attack and damage rolls in addition to the normal bonus for charging. If you can make multiple attacks on a charge, this bonus only applies to the first attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Horn Rider" title="Horn Rider" groups="Combat" description="You can defend yourself using the horn or tusk of a creature you're lashed to.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 shield bonus to AC when lashed into a horn harness.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A creature with this feat can take the Mounted Archery feat without possessing 1 rank in the Ride skill or the Mounted Combat feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Horn Rider's Charge" title="Horn Rider's Charge" groups="Combat" description="When the animal you're lashed to charges, you use its momentum in your own attack.">
		<Prerequisites>Horn Rider, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you&apos;re lashed into a horn harness and you ready an action to make a melee attack against the target of a charge made by the creature you&apos;re lashed to, you gain the attack bonus for charging and your attack deals double damage (or triple damage with a lance). This benefit does not stack with the benefit of Spirited Charge.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Horn of the Criosphinx" title="Horn of the Criosphinx" groups="Combat" description="Hammer-masters developed a fighting style based on certain attributes of sphinxes, focusing particularly on how these creatures can stand steadfast even in the face of imminent onslaught or make their own deadly assaults at a moment's notice. You end your charge in a devastating two-handed attack.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6 or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you make a successful charge attack while wielding a two-handed weapon in both hands, add two times your Strength bonus to the damage roll.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A character wielding a two-handed weapon adds 1-1/2 times her Strength bonus to damage rolls.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk can use this feat as long as he is wielding a two-handed weapon or both his hands are empty.</p>
			<p>Note: A monk can take any of these feats as bonus feats at the indicated levels. To benefit from the feats, monks must have both hands free and capable of delivering an unarmed strike.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Horrific Gorging" title="Horrific Gorging" groups="Combat, Monster" description="In the space of a few horrific seconds, you can chew up and gulp down an entire humanoid body.">
		<Prerequisites>Bite attack, Large or larger, swallow whole universal monster ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a full-round action, you can completely consume a dead, unconscious, paralyzed, or otherwise helpless humanoid creature that you could normally swallow with your swallow whole ability. When you do, you deal bite damage as a critical hit and swallow the humanoid as your swallow whole special ability.</p>
			<p>Allies of the swallowed creature within 30 feet that can see you indulge in this horrific feast must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your Hit Dice + your Charisma modifier) to avoid being shaken for 1d4 rounds. This part of the ability is a mind-affecting fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Horse Master" title="Horse Master" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Expert trainer class feature, Ride 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Use your character level to determine your effective druid level for determining the powers and abilities of your mount.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You use your cavalier level to determine your effective druid level for determining the powers and abilities of your mount.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Human Spirit" title="Human Spirit" groups="Half-Elf" description="Your blood burns with the passion and unyielding quest for self-improvement displayed so prominently by your human relatives.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-elf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive 1 bonus skill rank. Whenever you gain another Hit Die, you gain an additional skill rank. You cannot gain more than four skill ranks in this way.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only take this feat at 1st level. If you take this feat, you cannot take the Elven Spirit feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Huntmaster" title="Huntmaster" groups="Human" description="You are an expert trainer of horses, hounds, falcons, or hunting cats.">
		<Prerequisites>Handle Animal 1 rank; either the animal companion, divine bond (mount), or mount class feature; human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you have the animal companion class feature, pick one of the following types of animal companions that this feat affects: bird, dog, small cat, or horse. If you have the divine bond (mount) or mount class feature, this feat always affects horses. You gain a +2 bonus on Handle Animal and Knowledge (nature) checks with creatures of that type of animal. Furthermore, you are treated as one level higher when determining the abilities of your animal companion or mount, as long as it is of the chosen type.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hurricane Punch" title="Hurricane Punch" groups="Combat" description="Your fast strikes hit with the force of a hurricane, pushing your foes away.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Bull Rush, Improved Unarmed Strike, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you hit the same creature with unarmed strikes at least twice in the same round, you can attempt a bull rush combat maneuver against that creature as a swift action. You can also move with the target even if you have no movement remaining, but the distance you move can&apos;t exceed half your speed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hurtful" title="Hurtful" groups="Combat" description="You know how to add injury to insult.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully demoralize an opponent within your melee reach with an Intimidate check, you can make a single melee attack against that creature as a swift action. If your attack fails to damage the target, its shaken condition from being demoralized immediately ends.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hydraulic Maneuver" title="Hydraulic Maneuver" groups="Undine" description="You can use your hydraulic push to disarm or trip.">
		<Prerequisites>Hydraulic push spell-like ability, undine.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may use hydraulic push to attempt a bull rush, disarm, dirty trick (blind or dazzle), or trip combat maneuver. Each time you use hydraulic push, you must decide which of the allowed combat maneuvers you want to perform. You may use this feat with your hydraulic push racial spell-like ability, your class-granted use of hydraulic push, or any hydraulic push spells you cast, but not with magic items or other external sources that use that spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Hydraulic push can only be used to make a bull rush combat maneuver.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Hymn Singer" title="Hymn Singer" groups="" description="Your music is infused with your faith.">
		<Prerequisites>Bardic performance, good alignment, worshiper of a good deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using bardic performance, you may choose to play, recite, or sing a religious song or piece of scripture of your faith. Each round of bardic performance you spend in this way, you count as presenting a holy symbol, chanting prayers, or ringing a hand bell for the purpose of keeping vampires at bay.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
</Bundles>
