<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Bundles>
	<Bundle id="Calculating Mind" title="Calculating Mind" groups="" description="You see potential in the world around you that nobody else notices. Your numerological abilities are heightened by this uncommon aptitude.">
		<Prerequisites>Sacred Geometry, Knowledge (engineering) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Anytime you use the Sacred Geometry feat, you can use d8s instead of d6s when rolling your dice pool.</p>
			<p>You can use any combination of d6s and d8s that you wish, as long as the number of dice does not exceed the number of ranks you possess in Knowledge (engineering).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Call Out" title="Call Out" groups="Combat" description="A well-crafted insult forces an opponent to duel you.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make an Intimidate check against a hostile target within 30 feet that can clearly see and hear you. The DC of this check is equal to 10 + your opponent&apos;s Hit Dice + its Wisdom modifier. If the target is trained in Sense Motive, the DC is instead equal to 10 + your opponent&apos;s Sense Motive bonus, if higher. If you succeed at this check, the target enters a duel with you. The target cannot withdraw from the duel for 1 round + 1 round for every 5 by which the check beat the DC.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Call Truce" title="Call Truce" groups="" description="You can passionately entreat your enemies with the aim of making combat unnecessary.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 15, Persuasive, Diplomacy 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While in combat, as a 1-round action (as if it were a spell with a 1-round casting time, you can call for a truce with any creatures that have an Intelligence score of 4 or greater and can understand you. When doing so, you can&apos;t be wielding a weapon or threatening implement, such as a charged spell, wand, or anything else the creatures you are entreating might consider threatening. You must also be in plain sight of most the creatures you are entreating.</p>
			<p>Once you&apos;ve called for a truce, if any of your allies attack or take any threatening action against those you are entreating before the start of your next turn, your call is unsuccessful.</p>
			<p>At the start of your next turn, attempt a single Diplomacy check (DC = 30 + the Charisma modifier of the creature with the highest Charisma modifier in the opposing group). If you are successful, combat ceases for 1 minute, or until any creature in the opposing group is threatened or attacked.</p>
			<p>If you fail the check by 5 or more, you cannot use Diplomacy again with any creature you attempted to entreat for 1d4 hours. If anyone in your group instead plans to use the parley to gain a combat advantage, the opponents can attempt a Sense Motive check against each such member of your group to get a hunch, with a DC equal to either 20 or the result of that character&apos;s Bluff check, whichever is higher.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If the parley would inherently result in the opponents surrendering or losing, if the opponents are mind-controlled or fanatics, or if there are other appropriate circumstances at the GM&apos;s discretion, you might not be able to use this feat. For instance, if the opponents&apos; main advantage over your group comes from a short-duration spell that would end during a parley (see Calling for a Cease-Fire), you cannot use this feat. Circumstances could potentially increase the check&apos;s DC by 5, 10, or even up to 20.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Camouflaged Trap" title="Camouflaged Trap" groups="" description="You excel at hiding your traps in the wilderness, making them more difficult for your enemies to locate and avoid.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (traps) 4 ranks, Survival 4 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you craft and set a trap in a wilderness environment, you increase the DC of the Perception check required to find it by 5.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cannon Master" title="Cannon Master" groups="Combat" description="You have learned how to keep firearm siege engines ready for battle despite harrowing circumstances.">
		<Prerequisites>Siege Engineer, Knowledge (engineering) or Profession (siege engineer) 7 ranks, proficiency with at least one firearm siege engine.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 competence bonus on any Craft (siege engine) checks made to repair a firearm siege engine. In addition, if you are the crew leader for a firearm siege engine with the broken condition, that siege engine&apos;s misfire range is increased by only 2 instead of by 4, and the broken siege engine must misfire twice before it explodes.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: While acting as the leader of a firearm siege engine crew, you can spend 5 stamina points as an immediate action when the siege engine rolls a misfire to negate the misfire.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Canny Tumble" title="Canny Tumble" groups="Combat" description="Your acrobatic prowess distracts your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Mobility, Acrobatics 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Acrobatics to move through an opponent&apos;s threatened area or space without provoking an attack of opportunity from that opponent, you gain a +2 circumstance bonus on your next melee attack roll against that opponent and that opponent is denied its Dexterity bonus to AC, as long as you make that attack before the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Careful Flyer" title="Careful Flyer" groups="" description="You move with ease when you fly at a slower rate.">
		<Prerequisites>Acrobatic, Fly 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you take a move action to fly, even when moving less than half your speed, you do not need to succeed at a Fly check to continue flying. When moving less than half your speed in a round, you also gain a +2 bonus on Acrobatics checks to avoid attacks of opportunity and a +2 bonus to your AC against attacks of opportunity you provoke because of movement.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You must succeed at a Fly check to continue flying unless you move at least half your speed.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Careful Reader" title="Careful Reader" groups="" description="Your training has taught you proper caution and wariness when deciphering the ancient scrolls and inscriptions of fallen civilizations.">
		<Prerequisites>Linguistics 3 ranks, Spellcraft 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 bonus on saving throws against written magical effects, including explosive runes, glyph of warding, illusory script, symbol of death, and similar magic, as well as against any form of curse, madness, possession, or similar effect&#x2014;magical or not&#x2014;that might occur from reading a book, inscription, scroll, or any other form of writing.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Careful Sneak" title="Careful Sneak" groups="" description="By taking your time, you negate penalties while sneaking in most armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Stealth 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You do not apply the armor check penalty for light and medium armor on Stealth skill checks as long as you move half your speed or less. You still cannot run or charge while using Stealth in this way.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Careful Speaker" title="Careful Speaker" groups="" description="The paranoid terror that comes from living in a region with a dangerous government has made you unusually aware of what you say.">
		<Prerequisites>Wisdom 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on all Bluff checks made to fool someone or pass secret messages (but not to feint in combat), and a +2 bonus on all Will saves against attempts to scry upon you or read your mind.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Carrion Feeder" title="Carrion Feeder" groups="Tengu" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Tengu.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 racial bonus on saving throws against diseases and ingested poisons (but not other poisons). You receive a +2 bonus on Survival skill checks to find food for yourself (and only yourself ).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cartogramancer" title="Cartogramancer" groups="" description="You combine your knowledge of geography with the art of teleportation.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (geography) 10 ranks, ability to cast greater teleport.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you cast greater teleport&#x2014;or similar teleportation effects that require a reliable description of the location&#x2014;but do not have a reliable description of the destination, you can attempt a DC 25 Knowledge (geography) check prior to casting the spell to gain a reliable description of some location within 100 miles of the destination. If you exceed the DC by 10, you gain a description of some location within 50 miles, and if you succeed the DC by 20, you gain a description of some location within 25 miles. Once you have attempted such a check for a specific location, you cannot attempt it again, and if you attempt to use greater teleport elsewhere in the same general area, the result is the same.</p>
			<p>For instance, if you don&apos;t know the location of the villain&apos;s castle, you also don&apos;t know a location within 100 miles of the stables next to the villain&apos;s castle, or within 100 miles of the town half a mile away from the villain&apos;s castle.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cartwheel Dodge" title="Cartwheel Dodge" groups="" description="You use your knack for avoiding damage to reposition yourself in combat.">
		<Prerequisites>Evasion class feature, improved evasion class feature, acrobatics 12 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully use improved evasion to avoid taking damage, you can move up to half your speed as an immediate action. This movement provokes attacks of opportunity as normal.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Caster's Champion" title="Caster's Champion" groups="Combat" description="You draw upon the power of an allied arcane spellcaster to enhance your weapons with magical energy.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Three times per day as a swift action, when you are within 30 feet of an ally who is an arcane spellcaster, you can channel a portion of her arcane power into your weapons. For 1 round, you gain a +1 bonus on all weapon damage rolls, and your weapons are treated as magic for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction. When your base attack bonus reaches +4 and every 4 points thereafter, this bonus increases by 1, to a maximum of +5 at 16th level.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat counts as Arcane Strike for the purposes of prerequisites.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Casterbane Shot" title="Casterbane Shot" groups="Combat, Grit" description="Life has taught you to disable spellcasters with your firearms.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Gunslinger or the grit class feature, Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you ready a ranged attack with a firearm to attack a spellcaster when he begins casting a spell and successfully hit your opponent, you can expend 1 grit point to increase the target&apos;s concentration check DC for being injured while casting by 5.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When using Casterbane Shot, you can spend up to 5 stamina points to increase the DC of the concentration check imposed by the feat by an amount equal to the number of stamina points spent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Casual Illusionist" title="Casual Illusionist" groups="Gnome" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Gnome, gnome magic racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you have at least one spell-like ability unused from your gnome magic racial trait, you gain a +2 racial bonus on all Bluff, Disguise, and Sleight of Hand checks you make. At 10th level, these bonuses increase to +4.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat counts as the Deceitful feat for the purposes of all prerequisites.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cat and Mouse" title="Cat and Mouse" groups="Combat" description="You can forgo an obvious counterstrike against an opponent to better spot breaches in its defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 5 ranks, Sense Motive 5 ranks, opportune parry and riposte deed.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the opportune parry and riposte deed to successfully parry an opponent&apos;s attack, if you have your immediate action available and choose not to attempt a riposte, you gain a +1 dodge bonus to your AC and a +2 bonus on all combat maneuver checks against the opponent you successfully parried for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cat's Fall" title="Cat's Fall" groups="" description="Much like a cat, you can instantly shift your balance when you fall and roll with the impact, avoiding serious injury and landing on your feet.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Acrobatics 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you succeed at a DC 15 Acrobatics skill check to soften a fall, you ignore the first 20 feet of that fall and convert the damage from the next 10 feet of the fall to nonlethal damage. You land on your feet as long as you take less than 20 points of damage from the fall.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A successful DC 15 Acrobatics check allows you to ignore the first 10 feet fallen, and you fall prone if you take any falling damage.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Catch Off-Guard" title="Catch Off-Guard" groups="Combat" description="Foes are surprised by your skilled use of unorthodox and improvised weapons.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You do not suffer any penalties for using an improvised melee weapon. Unarmed opponents are flat-footed against any attacks you make with an improvised melee weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You take a -4 penalty on attack rolls made with an improvised weapon.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Catfolk Exemplar" title="Catfolk Exemplar" groups="Catfolk" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Catfolk.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can take the Aspect of the Beast feat even if you do not meet the normal prerequisites. Furthermore, your catlike nature manifests in one of the following ways. You choose the manifestation when you take this feat, and cannot change it later.</p>
			<p>Enhanced Senses (Ex): If you have low-light vision, you gain the scent catfolk racial trait. If you have the scent racial trait, you gain low-light vision.Fast Sprinter (Ex): You gain a 10-foot racial bonus to your speed when using the charge, run, or withdraw actions. If you have the sprinter racial trait, your racial bonus to speed when using the charge, run, or withdraw action increases to a 20-foot bonus.Sharp Claws (Ex): If you do not have the cat&apos;s claws racial trait or the claws of the beast manifestation from the Aspect of the Beast feat, you gain the cat&apos;s claws racial trait. If you have either the cat&apos;s claws racial trait or the claws of the beast manifestation, your claw damage increases to 1d6.<Special>
			</Special></p><p>You can take this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you select it, you must choose a different manifestation.</p>
		<p></p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Caustic Slur" title="Caustic Slur" groups="" description="You know exactly how to insult your favored enemies in order to make them lose their heads.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, favored enemy class feature, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make a Bluff check against one sort of favored enemy. Any creature of that type within 60 feet of you must make a Will saving throw or become angered. If an affected creature attacks you, it&apos;s treated as if it were using Power Attack (taking a penalty on attack rolls but gaining a bonus on damage rolls). If the creature already has the power attack feat, the attack penalty increases by 1 and the damage bonus increases by 2. These modifiers end when combat ends. This ability does not work on creatures that cannot understand you, though sometimes a simple gesture is sufficient for an intelligent opponent to catch your gist regardless of any language barrier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cautious Fighter" title="Cautious Fighter" groups="Combat,Halfling" description="You care more about survival than victory.">
		<Prerequisites>Halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When fighting defensively or using total defense, your dodge bonus to AC increases by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cavalry Formation" title="Cavalry Formation" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You are skilled at riding in close formation with your mounted allies without impeding your effectiveness on the battlefield.">
		<Prerequisites>Mounted Combat.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You and your mount can overlap the space of mounts whose riders have this feat, although no more than two creatures can share any one square. Further, you can charge through a space containing an allied mount if that mount&apos;s rider has this feat, although the space from which you make your charge attack must comply with this feat&apos;s other benefit or be unoccupied.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cecaelia Focus Tattoo" title="Cecaelia Focus Tattoo" groups="" description="You have tattooed the humanoid portion of your skin with a swirling mark that provides you with focus and pride.">
		<Prerequisites>Cecaelia.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one of the cecaelia focus tattoos below; you gain its benefits while it is active. While you can have any number of focus tattoos, only one can be active at a time. You activate a focus tattoo by concentrating on its importance to you for 1 hour without interruption. Once a focus tattoo is active, it remains so until you activate a new tattoo.</p>
			<p>Each time you would gain a favored class bonus, you may forgo that benefit and instead get another tattoo from the Cecaelia Focus Tattoos list (below). Instead of getting a new tattoo, you can increase the complexity of an existing tattoo by selecting the same tattoo again. You may choose any tattoo multiple times; if you do, its benefits stack while it is active.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Celestial Obedience" title="Celestial Obedience" groups="" description="Your reverence for an empyreal lord is so great that daily prayer and minor sacrifices grant you special boons.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (planes) 3 ranks, must worship an empyreal lord.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Each empyreal lord requires a different obedience, but all obediences take only 1 hour to perform. Once you&apos;ve performed the obedience, you gain the benefit of a special ability or resistance as indicated in the &#x201C;Obedience&#x201D; entry for the empyreal lord.</p>
			<p>If you have at least 12 Hit Dice, you also gain the first boon granted by your empyreal lord upon undertaking your obedience. If you have at least 16 Hit Dice, you also gain the empyreal lord&apos;s second boon. If you have 20 Hit Dice or more, you also gain the empyreal lord&apos;s third boon. Unless a specific duration or number of uses per day is listed, a boon&apos;s effects are constant.</p>
			<p>Mystery cultists gain access to these boons at lower levels as a benefit of their prestige class. If you ever fail to perform a daily obedience, you lose all access to the benefits and boons granted by this feat until you next perform the obedience.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Celestial Servant" title="Celestial Servant" groups="Aasimar" description="Rather than being a normal animal or beast, your companion or familiar hails from the heavenly realms.">
		<Prerequisites>Aasimar, animal companion, familiar, or mount class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your animal companion, familiar, or mount gains the celestial template and becomes a magical beast, though you may still treat it as an animal when using Handle Animal, wild empathy, or any other spells or class abilities that specifically affect animals.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Censoring Critical" title="Censoring Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits mute your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +15.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit against an opponent, the victim is unable to speak for 1d4+1 rounds. This prevents spellcasters from using spells with verbal components. A successful Fortitude saving throw reduces this muteness to 1 round. The DC of this Fortitude save is equal to 10 + your base attack bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can apply the effects of only one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you have Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Centered Spell" title="Centered Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can make a spell explode around you, leaving a safe zone for yourself at the center of the blast.">
		<Prerequisites>Spellcraft 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can center the area of a spell with an area effect and duration of instantaneous on you, and exclude yourself from the effects of the spell. Your familiar (if any) is also excluded from the effect, provided that it is in your square and at least one size category smaller than you.</p>
			<p>A centered spell does not use up a higher-level spell slot than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cerberus Crush" title="Cerberus Crush" groups="Combat" description="When you strike from three directions, you channel deadly force into each blow.">
		<Prerequisites>Cerberus Snare, Cerberus Style, Vital Strike, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 13th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can apply the benefits of Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, and Greater Vital Strike to all attacks made using Cerberus Style.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cerberus Snare" title="Cerberus Snare" groups="Combat" description="Your strikes latch onto your opponent like the jaws of a cerberus, preventing them from fleeing across planes.">
		<Prerequisites>Cerberus Style, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you damage an opponent with Cerberus Style, that opponent cannot take 5-foot steps until the beginning of your next turn. Additionally, it is barred from dimensional travel. This effect functions as dimensional anchor, except that its duration is 1 round. Spell resistance applies; for the purpose of checks to overcome spell resistance, your caster level is equal to your character level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cerberus Style" title="Cerberus Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You rain blows upon your enemies from three directions, like the three heads of the cerberus guardians of Hell.">
		<Prerequisites>Cleave, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6 or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make a single unarmed strike at your full base attack bonus against a foe within reach. If you hit, you deal damage normally and can make an additional attack (using your full base attack bonus) against up to two other foes that are also within reach. You take a -2 penalty to your Armor Class until the start of your next turn for each additional attack you make with this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chain Mastery" title="Chain Mastery" groups="Combat" description="You wield spiked chains with effortless lethality.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (spiked chain).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat a spiked chain as a one-handed martial weapon for all purposes. You can still choose to wield a spiked chain as a two-handed weapon, and if you do so, you gain a +2 bonus on combat maneuver checks to disarm or trip foes with your spiked chain.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chain-flail Master" title="Chain-flail Master" groups="Combat" description="You can use a dwarven chain-flail with only one hand.">
		<Prerequisites>Two-Weapon Fighting, base attack bonus +4, proficiency with the dwarven chain-flail.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use a chain-flail as a one-handed weapon. When using it one-handed, changing whether it&apos;s a normal or reach weapon is a full-round action. If you have the Darting Viper feat, changing its reach is a move action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A dwarven chain-flail requires two hands to wield.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chairbreaker" title="Chairbreaker" groups="Combat" description="You deal more damage by breaking nearby objects against your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Catch Off-Guard, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you attack a target with an improvised weapon, you can give that weapon the broken condition to deal 1d4 points of additional damage on that attack.</p>
			<p>Additionally, you gain a +4 bonus on the roll to confirm a critical hit with this attack. If you confirm the crit, the extra damage granted by this feat is also multiplied and the improvised weapon is destroyed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chakra Adept" title="Chakra Adept" groups="" description="Your body and soul have grown more accustomed to kundalini energy.">
		<Prerequisites>Chakra Initiate, ability to awaken the heart chakra.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your pool of serpent-fire ki increases to 4 points. When you maintain your chakras as a swift action without opening a new chakra, you can choose to attempt either the Fortitude save or the Will save instead of both.</p>
			<p>In addition, after you stop spending ki to maintain your chakras, the kundalini energy lingers in your body. On the first round during which you spend no ki to maintain your chakras, your highest chakra closes and you can spend a swift action to use any one of the abilities of your remaining open chakras. On the next round after that, all of your chakras close, and you must spend 1 point of ki and a swift action to start again from your root chakra.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chakra Initiate" title="Chakra Initiate" groups="" description="You have an extra wellspring of kundalini energy that you can use to open your chakras.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to awaken the root chakra.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a pool that holds 3 points of serpentfire ki, which you can use only to open or maintain chakras.</p>
			<p>These serpent-fire ki points are replenished at the same time you replenish the points in your regular ki pool.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chakra Mandala" title="Chakra Mandala" groups="" description="Using scars, tattoos, or henna, you inscribe symbols over your chakras to help maintain your balance.">
		<Prerequisites>Ki pool class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you fail the Fortitude saving throw to maintain your awakened chakras, you take only half the normal damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chakra Master" title="Chakra Master" groups="" description="You have mastered all seven chakras, and use your ki to pull more power from the flow.">
		<Prerequisites>Chakra Adept, Chakra Initiate, ability to awaken the crown chakra.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your pool of serpent-fire ki increases to 5 points. You can spend 3 ki points instead of 1 when you open or maintain a chakra to gain the benefits of two chakras instead of one in that round. If you are opening or maintaining your crown chakra, this stacks with the crown chakra&apos;s special power, allowing you to gain the benefits of three chakras in a round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Changeling Familiar" title="Changeling Familiar" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="Many familiars are able to turn into other animals, but a few familiars have greater talents, and can transform into humanoid bodies of their own.">
		<Prerequisites>Familiar class feature, caster level 9th, your familiar must have the change shape universal monster ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your familiar&apos;s change shape universal monster ability can function as alter self, and it gains a single alternate form of either Small or Medium size. This form is of a child or teenager of its master&apos;s species, and once chosen cannot be changed. Such changeling familiars always bear some kind of visible mark of their original nature, such as a cat&apos;s eyes, a serpent&apos;s tongue, or small demonic horns. The changeling familiar does not gain any new languages with this transformation, so changeling familiars are often mute.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channel Deific Essence" title="Channel Deific Essence" groups="" description="Rather than bringing forth positive or negative energy to heal allies or blast undead, you channel a fraction of your deity's power into yourself.">
		<Prerequisites>Alignment Channel, channel energy 5d6, domain class feature, same alignment as patron deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can expend a use of channel energy to select a domain you have. You gain the ability associated with that domain from the invoke deity spell for a number of rounds equal to your number of channel energy dice. While this ability is active, taking actions directly opposed to your deity&apos;s teachings or alignment causes you to take the penalties listed in invoke deity and ends this effect. You can gain only one ability from this feat at a time, and its effects do not stack with invoke deity.</p>
			<p>If you instead expend two uses of channel energy, you can instead infuse a single willing target within 30 feet with deific essence. The target need not be a worshiper of your deity, but is subject to the same penalties if it takes actions directly opposed to your deity&apos;s teachings or alignment.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channel Force" title="Channel Force" groups="Channeling; Aasimar" description="Your channel is bolstered by your faith, allowing you to move and damage your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Aasimar, channel energy 2d6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you channel energy to deal damage, you may choose to affect only a single target within 30 feet. In addition to dealing damage, if that single target fails its saving throw, you may pull or push the target up to 5 feet for every 2d6 points of channel energy damage you are capable of dealing.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channel Ray" title="Channel Ray" groups="" description="You can focus your channeled energy on a single target.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you channel energy, you can project a ray from your holy symbol instead of creating a burst. You must succeed at a ranged touch attack to hit an unwilling target; your target is then affected by the channeled energy as normal and receives a saving throw. You need not make an attack roll to affect a willing creature with the ray. The ray has a range of 30 feet per channel energy die, and its save DC is increased by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channel Smite" title="Channel Smite" groups="Combat" description="You can channel your divine energy through a melee weapon you wield.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Before you make a melee attack roll, you can choose to spend one use of your channel energy ability as a swift action. If you channel positive energy and you hit an undead creature, that creature takes an amount of additional damage equal to the damage dealt by your channel positive energy ability. If you channel negative energy and you hit a living creature, that creature takes an amount of additional damage equal to the damage dealt by your channel negative energy ability. Your target can make a Will save, as normal, to halve this additional damage. If your attack misses, the channel energy ability is still expended with no effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channel Spirit" title="Channel Spirit" groups="" description="You can willingly allow spirits to possess you, trading a taste of your life for their knowledge and abilities.">
		<Prerequisites>Spirit Ridden or spirit class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one of the spirit legends available to a medium. You can trade control of your body to a spirit of this type for power. You must perform a seance, taking 1 hour and requiring your concentration. At the end of the seance, you invite a spirit of the chosen type to inhabit your body. You do not require an appropriate location to channel the spirit. You gain the benefits of the spirit&apos;s spirit bonus and seance boon, but no spirit powers. Your spirit bonus is +1, or equal to your spirit bonus from any medium class levels you have (whichever is higher). You don&apos;t select a taboo and the spirit gains no influence over you. You can continue to gain the benefits of the spiritual possession for up to 1 hour per character level you have. At the end of the duration, the spirit takes over your body, and you become an NPC under the GM&apos;s control for a duration equal to the amount of time the spirit possessed you. You can end the duration prematurely as a free action, but the spirit still takes over your body. If you have the spirit class feature, you can&apos;t use this feat and act as a vessel for a second spirit simultaneously, but you gain spirit powers as normal for your medium level.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take this feat, you gain a new spirit you can channel.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channeled Blessing" title="Channeled Blessing" groups="" description="Your channeled energy can deliver a warpriest's blessing.">
		<Prerequisites>Blessings class feature, channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you channel energy to heal, you can instead deliver a warpriest&apos;s blessing to a single willing creature (including yourself ) in the area that otherwise would have been healed by your channeled energy. The blessing must be one that requires a standard action and affects one or more creatures. If the blessing would normally affect multiple targets, you affect only a single target. The target receives the blessing in place of the healing and any other effects of the channeled energy. (This application doesn&apos;t count toward your uses of blessings per day.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channeled Revival" title="Channeled Revival" groups="" description="You can expend a large portion of your channeling power to reverse death itself.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy 6d6 (positive energy).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a full-round action that provokes attacks of opportunity, you can expend three uses of your channel energy class feature to restore a dead creature to life as if you had cast the breath of life spell.</p>
			<p>Editor&apos;s Note</p>
			<p>What is the range of Channeled Revival?</p>
			<p>It uses the range of your channel energy ability.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channeled Shield Wall" title="Channeled Shield Wall" groups="" description="You draw upon your channel energy to enhance the protective ability of your shield and those of allies while they are adjacent to you.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy 3d6, proficiency with a shield.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can spend a use of your channel energy to grant yourself a +2 deflection bonus while using a shield. This bonus lasts 1 minute per cleric level or effective cleric level. While you benefit from this bonus, allies with shields also gain a +2 deflection bonus while they are adjacent to you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channeling Force" title="Channeling Force" groups="Combat" description="You distill your channeled energy into a sheen of force that surrounds your weapon for a limited time.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast at least one force spell, channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A swift action, you can expend one use of channel energy to grant your weapon attacks a bonus on damage rolls equal to the number of dice of your channel energy. This extra damage is force damage. This lasts for your next three weapon attacks or until the end of combat, whichever comes first.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channeling Scourge" title="Channeling Scourge" groups="" description="Your zeal for hunting your faith's enemies empowers your ability to channel divine energy, as long as you channel that energy for harm.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature, inquisitor level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use channel energy to deal damage, your inquisitor levels count as cleric levels for determining the number of damage dice and the saving throw DC.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Channeling Variance" title="Channeling Variance" groups="" description="You alter your channeled energies based on your god's tenets.">
		<Prerequisites>Domain class feature, channel energy class feature, must worship and receive spells from a deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one variant channeling ability. The chosen ability must match one of your deity&apos;s domains, subdomains, or areas of concern. Three times per day when you channel energy, you can apply the modifications of the chosen variant channeling ability to your channeled energy, including reductions to the damage dealt or healing performed by your channeled energy.</p>
			<p>If you already have a variant channeling ability, this feat instead allows you to channel energy without the modifications of your chosen variant channeling ability (including reductions to the damage dealt or healing performed by your channeled energy) three times per day.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat can be selected twice. The second time you do, you can use Channeling Variance whenever you channel energy instead of just three times per day.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Charge Through" title="Charge Through" groups="Combat" description="You can overrun enemies when charging.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Overrun, Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When making a charge, you can attempt to overrun one creature in the path of the charge as a free action. If you successfully overrun that creature, you can complete the charge. If the overrun is unsuccessful, the charge ends in the space directly in front of that creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You must have a clear path toward the target of your charge.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Charge of the Righteous" title="Charge of the Righteous" groups="Combat" description="You charge toward undead and fiends with confidence in your righteous cause.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, any good alignment</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You do not take a penalty to AC while charging undead creatures and evil outsiders.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When you charge, you take a -2 penalty to AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When charging any creature with an evil alignment, you can spend 2 stamina points in order to ignore the -2 penalty to AC imposed by charging.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Charging Hurler" title="Charging Hurler" groups="Combat" description="You know how to use your momentum to enhance your thrown weapon attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use the charge rules to make a thrown weapon attack. All the parameters of a charge apply, except that you must only move closer to your opponent, and you must end your movement within 30 feet of that opponent. If you do, you can make a single thrown weapon attack against that opponent, gaining the +2 bonus on the attack roll and taking a -2 penalty to your AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Charming Performance" title="Charming Performance" groups="" description="Your musical skill, dramatic timing, or mastery of language make you seem more personable.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Perform (any) 1 rank, bardic performance or raging song.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use Perform, rather than Diplomacy, to improve an NPC&apos;s starting attitude toward you.</p>
			<p>Alternatively, by praising another character, you may use Perform to improve an NPC&apos;s starting attitude toward another character, though the DC for doing so is increased by 5. Either use of this feat requires at least 5 minutes of performance. You can&apos;t improve an NPC&apos;s attitude beyond friendly in this way, but if you would have made them helpful, you gain a +2 bonus on your next normal Diplomacy check against that NPC attempted within 24 hours.</p>
			<p>If using the contact rules, seeing you perform can count as up to four of the five positive interactions required to cultivate a contact.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Charnel Soldiers" title="Charnel Soldiers" groups="" description="The mindless undead you command fight together like seasoned warriors.">
		<Prerequisites>Any teamwork feat, ability to control or create undead.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you create undead, they gain one teamwork feat you know as a bonus feat, though they gain its benefits only when cooperating with you or with other undead that you have created. If you control undead with the Command Undead feat or a spell like command undead, they likewise gain one teamwork feat you know as a bonus feat as long as they remain under your control. Intelligent undead gain no benefit from this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cherry Blossom Spell" title="Cherry Blossom Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can infuse your spells with the ability to cripple your targets with old age or regress them to the folly of youth.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When a living creature takes damage from the affected spell, that creature also takes 2 points of damage to Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution or 2 points of damage to Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma (your choice). If the spell does not normally allow a save, the target can attempt a Fortitude save to negate the effect. Ageless or immortal creatures are immune to this effect. This is a magical aging effect, but it does not alter the creature&apos;s true age&#x2014;it merely simulates the effects of old age on the flesh or the reversion to a more infantile mental age. A cherry blossom spell uses up a slot 3 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level. Spells that don&apos;t deal damage don&apos;t benefit from this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Child of Two Fates" title="Child of Two Fates" groups="" description="You have learned to make the most of your torn existence.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (local) 5 ranks, half-elf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can select a teamwork feat that a human or elf ally within 30 feet possesses. You can ignore any race, ethnicity, or racial trait prerequisites, but you must still meet any other prerequisites for that feat to gain this benefit. You&apos;re treated as if you possess that feat for up to 1 minute, as long as you stay within 30 feet of the ally whose teamwork feat you have chosen to emulate.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Childlike" title="Childlike" groups="" description="Your resemblance to a human child tends to make others trust you, perhaps more than they should.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can take 10 on Bluff checks to convince others you are telling the truth, so long as your story makes you appear innocent. You gain a +2 bonus on Disguise skill checks to pose as a human child, and ignore the check penalties for disguising yourself as a different race and age category while doing so.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chilling Amplification" title="Chilling Amplification" groups="" description="Your cold spells render their targets sluggish.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you cast a spell with the cold descriptor, you can take a &#x2013;1 penalty on attack rolls made with the spell and reduce the spell saving throw&apos;s DC by 1 to cause any target that is dealt cold damage by the spell to have its movement speed reduced by 5 feet and become unable to take 5-foot steps. This effect lasts for 1 round + 1 round per 3 spell levels of the spell. You must choose to use this feat before making an attack roll or before your targets attempt their saving throws. This feat has no effect on spells that neither allow a saving throw nor require an attack roll.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Choir of Blades" title="Choir of Blades" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You can imitate your allies' exotic martial styles to such an extent that you can gain benefits to your own fighting abilities, even without formal training.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you&apos;re adjacent to an ally of a race different that your own who also has this feat, you gain the following benefits. If your ally has a racial bonus on attack rolls against a particular creature type or subtype, you also gain that bonus. If your ally has ancestral arms, weapon familiarity, or any other racial trait that grants weapon proficiencies, you also gain those proficiencies.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Chokehold" title="Chokehold" groups="Combat" description="While grappling, you can cut off an opponent's air and blood supply.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you have an opponent up to one size category larger than you grappled, you can attempt a grapple combat maneuver with a -5 penalty on the check. If you succeed, you have pinned your opponent and hold the opponent in a chokehold. When you maintain the grapple, you also maintain the chokehold. A creature in a chokehold cannot breathe or speak, and thus cannot cast spells that have a verbal component. An opponent you have in a chokehold has to hold his breath or begin suffocating. Any creature that does not breathe, is immune to bleed damage, or is immune to critical hits is immune to the effects of your chokehold. When the grapple is ended, so is the chokehold.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Circling Mongoose" title="Circling Mongoose" groups="Combat" description="You keep your opponent on the defensive as you circle around threateningly.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Dodge, Mobility, Spring Attack, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are adjacent to a foe, as a full-round action, you can take a full-attack action to make melee attacks against the foe, moving 5 feet before each attack. You must move 5 feet before each melee attack you make, and can&apos;t exceed your maximum speed, exceed your maximum number of attacks in a round, or attack any other target until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
			<p>You must remain adjacent to the foe, and your movement provokes attacks of opportunity as normal unless you succeed at the appropriate Acrobatics checks. If your first attack against the foe hits, you are considered to be flanking the foe on your second attack. Subsequent attacks made as part of the full-attack action continue to be treated as if you were flanking the foe until one of your attacks misses, at which point your attacks are treated normally.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A character without this feat is limited to only one 5-foot step during a full attack, taken before, after, or between attacks.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Circling Offense" title="Circling Offense" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You are skilled at approaching large foes with an ally in a way that makes it difficult for your foes to find an advantage against you or your ally.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Mobility, base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +1 dodge bonus to your Armor Class against attacks of opportunity provoked by moving through a creature&apos;s reach, provided the creature is of a larger size category than you and provided at least one other ally with Circling Offense is within the creature&apos;s reach. If a creature that you&apos;re receiving this dodge bonus against attacks you and misses with the attack, it provokes attacks of opportunity from any of your allies who possess Circling Offense.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Circuitous Shot" title="Circuitous Shot" groups="Combat" description="You can bounce ranged attacks off objects to obscure their point of origin and surprise foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 19, Blind-Fight, Improved Precise Shot, Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose to take a -2 penalty on a ranged weapon attack to ricochet it off a stone or metal surface and resolve the attack as if it originated from the chosen ricochet point for the purpose of determining cover (but not for determining concealment). Add the entire distance the weapon or ammunition traveled to determine range penalties for the attack. Bouncing a shot this way can potentially enable you to make ranged attacks against foes who have total cover against you by going around obstacles, but such a foe still has total concealment against your attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="City Sprinter" title="City Sprinter" groups="" description="You are skilled at moving quickly through forbidding parts of cities.">
		<Prerequisites>Street Smarts.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You do not treat crowds as difficult terrain. You also gain an additional +2 bonus on Acrobatics checks to move along rooftops and on slippery sections of city streets and sewers.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Clambering Escape" title="Clambering Escape" groups="Combat" description="You can escape an area effect by throwing an enemy in its path to shield yourself.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Reposition, evasion class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully use your evasion class feature to avoid taking damage from an effect that allows a Reflex saving throw, you can attempt a special reposition combat maneuver check against any one foe within reach as an immediate action. If successful, you switch positions with the target of your combat maneuver. If your foe was not initially within range of the effect that you evaded, it must save against the effect as if it had been within the area of effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Clarity of Pain" title="Clarity of Pain" groups="" description="You can inflict pain upon yourself to sharpen your focus.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Improved Iron Will, Iron Will.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Three times per day, as an immediate action when you fail a saving throw against a charm or compulsion effect, you can inflict 1d6 points of slashing, piercing, or bludgeoning damage to yourself in order to reroll that saving throw. You can&apos;t reroll the saving throw if you negate the damage, such as by having damage reduction greater than or equal to the damage you dealt to yourself; instead, you spend the immediate action and daily use of this feat but gain no benefit. You must take the result of the second roll, even if it is worse.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Claw Pounce" title="Claw Pounce" groups="Combat, Catfolk" description="You can charge and make an attack with your paws.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Dex 15, Nimble Striker, base attack bonus +10, catfolk, cat&apos;s claws racial trait or Aspect of the Beast (claws of the beast manifestation).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you make a charge, you can make a full attack with your claws.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Charging is a special full-round action that limits you to a single attack.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Claw Wrench" title="Claw Wrench" groups="Combat" description="You can pry open a mighty beast's grasp or snapping jaws.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can attempt a grapple combat maneuver with a -5 penalty against a creature that is currently grappling another creature via its grab special ability. If you succeed, you pry open the creature&apos;s grasp, releasing any creatures it had grappled.</p>
			<p>Additionally, you can ready an action to trigger if a creature attempts a bite attack against you. When the readied action triggers, you can attempt a grapple combat maneuver with a +2 bonus. If you succeed, you grapple the creature and cause the bite attack to miss. As long as you maintain the grapple, the creature can&apos;t use its bite attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cleansing Burst" title="Cleansing Burst" groups="" description="Your channeled energy wards off disease.">
		<Prerequisites>Able to cast remove disease or the ability to cure disease with a mercy, channel positive energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you channel positive energy to harm or turn undead creatures, any undead creatures in the area lose the ability to cause disease with their melee and ranged attacks for 1d4+1 rounds. If an undead creature successfully saves against your channeled energy, this duration is reduced to 1 round for that creature. Immunity to positive energy negates this ability.</p>
			<p>When you channel positive energy to heal living creatures, any living creatures in the area gain a +4 sacred bonus on saving throws against disease for 1d4+1 rounds. Creatures not healed by positive energy receive no benefit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cleave" title="Cleave" groups="Combat" description="You can strike two adjacent foes with a single swing.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can make a single attack at your full base attack bonus against a foe within reach. If you hit, you deal damage normally and can make an additional attack (using your full base attack bonus) against a foe that is adjacent to the first and also within reach. You can only make one additional attack per round with this feat. When you use this feat, you take a -2 penalty to your Armor Class until your next turn.</p>
			<p>Can I use Cleave or Great Cleave to cleave to or from an image created by a mirror image spell?</p>
			<p>No. If your initial attack hit the caster, you can&apos;t cleave to an image as if it were an actual creature. If your initial attack hit an image, you failed to hit your intended target (the caster), and therefore can&apos;t cleave. As you can&apos;t specifically target an image (because you can&apos;t tell the images from the actual caster), you likewise can&apos;t aim for an image and try to cleave to another image.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
			<p>Can I take a 5-foot step in the middle of my attempt to use the Cleave feat, to bring another foe within reach?</p>
			<p>No. Cleave is a special action and the conditions for that action are checked at the moment you begin your action. At that moment, all of the available targets are checked to make sure they adjacent to each other and within reach. You cannot take a 5-foot step in the middle of the action and check conditions again. If you do not have two targets within reach, adjacent to each other at the start of the attack, you could not even attempt to make an attack using Cleave.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cleave Through" title="Cleave Through" groups="Combat, Dwarf" description="You are ferocious at hewing smaller opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Cleave, Power Attack, base attack bonus +11, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Cleave or Great Cleave, if your initial attack hits, you may take a single 5-foot step as a free action before making your additional attacks. If doing so places a creature within your threatened area, that creature becomes a legal target for your additional Cleave attack(s) as long as it meets all the other prerequisites.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You may only make additional attacks with Cleave against creatures you threaten when you make your initial attack.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cleaving Finish" title="Cleaving Finish" groups="Combat" description="When you strike down an opponent, you can continue your swing into another target.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Cleave, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you make a melee attack, and your target drops to 0 or fewer hit points as a result of your attack, you can make another melee attack using your highest base attack bonus against another opponent within reach. You can make only one extra attack per round with this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cleaving Sweep" title="Cleaving Sweep" groups="Combat" description="You can sweep multiple foes to the ground with a single blow of your axe.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Cleave, Improved Trip, Weapon Focus (greataxe), base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using a full-attack action with a two-handed weapon, you can give up your regular attacks and instead attempt a trip combat maneuver at your highest base attack bonus against each opponent within reach. You must attempt a separate combat maneuver check against each opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Clinging Climber" title="Clinging Climber" groups="Combat" description="Using leverage and pure brawn, you can cling to a cliff face, ladder, or rope with your legs to free both of your hands to take other actions.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Climb 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a move action while climbing, you can cling to your climbing surface with your legs by succeeding at a Climb check with the same DC as that of climbing the surface as a move action. If successful, you can make attacks with a two-handed ranged weapon and reload ranged weapons until you resume climbing. The GM can rule that this feat doesn&apos;t work on certain climbing surfaces.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cloak and Dagger Style" title="Cloak and Dagger Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your attacks effortlessly inflict debilitating conditions on unaware opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Dirty Trick, Vital Strike, Weapon Focus with the chosen weapon, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one light melee weapon. While using this style, whenever you use the attack action to attack an opponent during a surprise round with your chosen weapon, you can attempt a dirty trick combat maneuver check against that opponent as a free action. Additionally, if an adjacent target attempts to remove a condition that you inflicted upon it with the dirty trick combat maneuver, it provokes an attack of opportunity from you.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>In addition to the chosen weapon, a character with the weapon training class feature can use Cloak and Dagger Style with any light melee weapon belonging to any fighter weapon group he has selected with weapon training.</p>
			<p>A character with the swashbuckler weapon training class feature can use Cloak and Dagger Style with light and one-handed piercing weapons.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cloak and Dagger Subterfuge" title="Cloak and Dagger Subterfuge" groups="Combat" description="Your increased martial skill allows you to take advantage of distracted foes to easily impose conditions, and even steal items without being noticed.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Cloak and Dagger Style, Combat Expertise, Improved Dirty Trick, Weapon Focus with the chosen weapon, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Cloak and Dagger Style and wielding your chosen weapon, whenever you make an attack of opportunity against a target, you can attempt a free dirty trick combat maneuver check against the target as a free action as well. Additionally, whenever you successfully perform a dirty trick maneuver against a target, you can immediately attempt a steal combat maneuver check against the target as a free action. If you succeed, the target is unaware you have stolen an item.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cloak and Dagger Tactics" title="Cloak and Dagger Tactics" groups="Combat" description="You devastate enemies that you catch off-guard.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Cloak and Dagger Style, Cloak and Dagger Subterfuge, Combat Expertise, Improved Dirty Trick, Vital Strike, Weapon Focus with the chosen weapon, base attack bonus +16.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Cloak and Dagger Style and wielding your chosen weapon, whenever you hit an opponent that is denied its Dexterity bonus to AC or that you are flanking, or make an attack using Vital Strike (or its improved or greater versions), you can attempt a dirty trick combat maneuver check against that opponent as a free action. If you succeed, the target must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your base attack bonus + your Intelligence modifier) or take an additional penalty from the dirty trick selected from the following list: anchored in place and unable to move from that square, confused, exhausted, or staggered. This additional penalty lasts only 1 round, regardless of how long the dirty trick&apos;s normal penalty lasts, and can be removed by the target with a standard action. You can only attempt one free dirty trick combat maneuver check per round using this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Close-Quarters Thrower" title="Close-Quarters Thrower" groups="Combat" description="You are agile enough to avoid melee attacks while throwing weapons or bombs.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Dodge, Weapon Focus with selected thrown weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a type of thrown weapon. You do not provoke attacks of opportunity for making ranged attacks using the selected weapon. If you are an alchemist, and you select this feat and choose alchemist bombs, you do not provoke attacks of opportunity for the process of drawing components of, creating, and throwing a bomb.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Making a ranged attack provokes attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cloud Gazer" title="Cloud Gazer" groups="Sylph" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Sylph.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can see through fog, mist, and clouds, without penalty, ignoring any cover or concealment bonuses from such effects. If the effect is created by magic, this feat instead triples the distance you can see without penalty.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cloud Step" title="Cloud Step" groups="" description="Your tread is of unearthly lightness.">
		<Prerequisites>Spider Step, monk level 12th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a move action, you can air walk (as the spell) up to half your slow fall distance, maximum 50 feet. You must reach a solid, level surface by the end of your turn or you will fall.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cloven Helm" title="Cloven Helm" groups="Combat, Dwarf" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Dented Helm, Hard-Headed, base attack bonus +11, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wearing a helmet, you add +1 to your AC against critical hit confirmation rolls; this benefit stacks with Dented Helm. When you use Dented Helm to deflect a critical hit, you may apply all damage from the critical hit to your helmet before applying any damage to yourself. If you take no damage, any additional effects, such as critical feats or poison, are negated.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Clustered Shots" title="Clustered Shots" groups="Combat" description="You take a moment to carefully aim your shots, causing them all to strike nearly the same spot.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use a full-attack action to make multiple ranged weapon attacks against the same opponent, total the damage from all hits before applying that opponent&apos;s damage reduction.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If the massive damage optional rule is being used, that rule applies if the total damage you deal with this feat is equal to or exceeds half the opponent&apos;s full normal hit points (minimum 50 points of damage).</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coaxing Spell" title="Coaxing Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your charms and enchantments reach the minds of even the lowliest dungeon denizens.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Focus (enchantment), Knowledge (dungeoneering) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>This feat only works with mind-affecting effects. A coaxing spell affects mindless oozes and vermin as if they weren&apos;t mindless, but has no effect on other creature types.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (a coaxing spell uses a spell slot 2 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cockatrice Strike" title="Cockatrice Strike" groups="Combat" description="With a single strike, you transmute flesh to stone.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Gorgon&apos;s Fist, Medusa&apos;s Wrath, base attack bonus +14.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a full-round action, you can make a single unarmed strike against a dazed, flat-footed, paralyzed, staggered, stunned, or unconscious foe. If that attack is a critical hit, the target is petrified unless it succeeds on a Fortitude saving throw with a DC of 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier. This is a supernatural polymorph effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Advice" title="Combat Advice" groups="" description="Your succinct words can aid an ally even in the heat of battle.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a move action, you can offer useful advice to an ally engaged in combat at just the right moment. Designate an enemy; your ally gains a +2 competence bonus on her next attack roll against that enemy. For your ally to benefit from this feat, you must be able to clearly see your ally and the designated enemy, and your ally must be able to hear you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Casting" title="Combat Casting" groups="" description="You are adept at spellcasting when threatened or distracted.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +4 bonus on concentration checks made to cast a spell or use a spell-like ability when casting on the defensive or while grappled.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Distraction" title="Combat Distraction" groups="Goblin" description="Anyone who attacks you while you act like a lunatic exposes themselves to brutal counterattacks from your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin, Acrobatics 1 rank, Escape Artist 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a full-round action, you can choose to do something that seems to serve no useful purpose. Example actions could include laughing at another creature&apos;s misfortune, rooting in your pockets for a snack, bending over to pick up what looks like a weird bug, or trying to fly into the air by flapping your arms like a sea gull. Although you&apos;re acting like a lunatic, your unpredictable actions are distracting. Any creature other than a goblin within 5 feet of you takes a &#x2013;2 penalty on Perception checks and concentration checks for as long as you continue to be a distraction and remain in range. This penalty stacks with other goblins performing combat distractions, as long as you&apos;re both adjacent to the distracted target.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Expertise" title="Combat Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You can increase your defense at the expense of your accuracy.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose to take a -1 penalty on melee attack rolls and combat maneuver checks to gain a +1 dodge bonus to your Armor Class. When your base attack bonus reaches +4, and every +4 thereafter, the penalty increases by -1 and the dodge bonus increases by +1. You can only choose to use this feat when you declare that you are making an attack or a full-attack action with a melee weapon. The effects of this feat last until your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Meditation" title="Combat Meditation" groups="Combat" description="Quick momentary meditation allows you to gain insight in combat.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Meditation Master, character level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can meditate as a full-round action. If you do, you gain all the benefits of your meditation feats, but they last for only 1 round per character level. Combat meditation allows you to expend the +1 insight bonus granted from the Meditation Master feat to instead roll twice when attempting an ability check, attack roll, saving throw, or skill check, taking the better of the two results. You must decide to use this ability before the initial roll is made. You may only use this alternate ability in place of bonuses granted by the Meditation Master feat. You can perform combat meditation a number of times per day equal to your Wisdom modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Patrol" title="Combat Patrol" groups="Combat" description="You range across the battlefield, dealing with threats wherever they arise.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat reflexes, Mobility, base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a full-round action, you may set up a combat patrol, increasing your threatened area by 5 feet for every 5 points of your base attack bonus. Until the beginning of your next turn, you may make attacks of opportunity against any opponent in this threatened area that provokes attacks of opportunity. You may move as part of these attacks, provided your total movement before your next turn does not exceed your speed. Any movement you make provokes attacks of opportunity as normal.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Reflexes" title="Combat Reflexes" groups="Combat" description="You can make additional attacks of opportunity.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may make a number of additional attacks of opportunity per round equal to your Dexterity bonus. With this feat, you may also make attacks of opportunity while flat-footed.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A character without this feat can make only one attack of opportunity per round and can&apos;t make attacks of opportunity while flat-footed.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>The Combat Reflexes feat does not allow a rogue to use her opportunist ability more than once per round.</p>
			<p>Can a character with Snap Shot and Combat Reflexes make multiple attacks of opportunity with a ranged weapon, assuming that loading the ranged weapon is a free action?</p>
			<p>Yes. As long as you can reload your weapon with a free action you can reload your weapon as part of the ranged attack attack of opportunity you are making with the Snap Shot feat.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Rhythm" title="Combat Rhythm" groups="Combat, Combination" description="The more your attacks land, the more confident your strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6 or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you deal damage with a melee attack to an opponent you have already damaged this round, you can reduce the total of any voluntary penalties to your melee attack rolls imposed by actions or feats (such as the Power Attack feat) by 1 (to a minimum penalty of 0). This reduction in penalties lasts until the beginning of your next turn and stacks with itself.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Style Master" title="Combat Style Master" groups="Combat" description="You shift between combat styles, combining them to increased effect.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, two or more style feats, base attack bonus +6 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can switch your style as a free action. At the start of combat, pick one of your styles. You start the combat in that style, even in the surprise round.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>It takes a swift action to begin or switch your styles.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Combat Vigor" title="Combat Vigor" groups="Combat" description="You can quickly recuperate from devastating attacks without divine assistance.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a vigor pool with a maximum number of points equal to your Constitution bonus. As a standard action, you can spend up to 1 vigor point per 3 Hit Dice you have (minimum 1) to regain 1d6 hit points per vigor point spent (maximum 7d6). Each time you spend vigor points, you become fatigued for 1 minute. You cannot spend vigor points while fatigued or exhausted. Spending vigor points doesn&apos;t provoke attacks of opportunity. The points in your vigor pool are replenished to their maximum after you rest for 8 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Command Animals" title="Command Animals" groups="" description="You channel energy to get animals to do your bidding.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal domain, channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can use one of your daily uses of channel energy in an attempt to control animals within 30 feet. Animals can attempt a Will save (DC = 10 + half your class level + your Charisma modifier) to negate the effect. Animals that fail their saves fall under your control, obeying your commands to the best of their ability as if under the effects of a charm monster spell with a caster level equal to your class level. An affected animal can attempt a new saving throw each day to escape this effect. You can control any number of animals, so long as their total Hit Dice do not exceed your class level. If you use channel energy in this way, it has no other effect (it does not heal or harm nearby creatures). If an affected animal is controlled by or a companion of another creature, you must attempt an opposed Charisma check whenever your orders conflict.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Command Plants" title="Command Plants" groups="" description="You channel energy to bring plants under your control.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature, Plant domain.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can use one of your daily uses of channel energy to command plants within 30 feet of you. Plants can attempt a Will save (DC = 10 + half your class level + your Charisma modifier) to negate the effect. This functions as the command plants spell with a caster level equal to your class level. Each affected plant can attempt a new saving throw each day to escape this effect. You can control any number of plants, so long as their total Hit Dice do not exceed your class level. If you use channel energy in this way, it has no other effect (it does not heal or harm nearby creatures). If an affected plant creature is controlled by or a companion of another creature, you must attempt an opposed Charisma check whenever your orders conflict.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Command Undead" title="Command Undead" groups="" description="Using foul powers of necromancy, you can command undead creatures, making them into your servants.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel negative energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can use one of your uses of channel negative energy to enslave undead within 30 feet. Undead receive a Will save to negate the effect. The DC for this Will save is equal to 10 + 1/2 your cleric level + your Charisma modifier. Undead that fail their saves fall under your control, obeying your commands to the best of their ability, as if under the effects of control undead. Intelligent undead receive a new saving throw each day to resist your command. You can control any number of undead, so long as their total Hit Dice do not exceed your cleric level. If you use channel energy in this way, it has no other effect (it does not heal or harm nearby creatures). If an undead creature is under the control of another creature, you must make an opposed Charisma check whenever your orders conflict.</p>
			<p>Note*: The duration, per this FAQ is permanent or until said undead is destroyed or makes the save.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Companion Figurine" title="Companion Figurine" groups="" description="You've developed an especially close bond with the creature summoned by your figurine of wondrous power. ">
		<Prerequisites>Handle Animal 1 rank, own a figurine of wondrous power. </Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may select the creature summoned by your figurine of wondrous power as an animal companion or familiar, or as appropriate. The figurine has the standard abilities of a familiar or animal companion of its type, plus additional abilities related to its figurine type (see below). The main advantage of this is that if your familiar or companion is killed in creature form, it merely reverts to statue form and can be used again later.</p>
			<p>The following standard figurines are available as animal companions (C) or familiars (F). </p>
			<p>Ebony Fly (C): You must have the Vermin Heart feat to select this creature as an animal companion. It is treated as a horse animal companion, and at 8th level it gains a fly speed of 120 feet (average maneuverability). </p>
			<p>Golden Lions (C): When you select a golden lion as an animal companion, one of the pair becomes your companion and the other retains its standard figurine abilities. </p>
			<p>Ivory Goats (C): When selecting an ivory goat as an animal companion, you select one of the three goats in the set (traveling, travail, or terror) as your companion; the others remain standard figurines. All three goats are treated as horse animal companions. The goat of traveling never suffers from fatigue or exhaustion from extended travel. The goat of travail has 2 horn attacks (1d8 + Str bonus) in addition to a horse&apos;s normal attacks. The goat of terror has the fear aura and magical weapon horns as described in its figurine entry. </p>
			<p>Marble Elephant (C): The elephant is treated as an elephant companion. </p>
			<p>Serpentine Owl (C, F): The owl is treated as a bird animal companion or an owl familiar, but only in its Small horned owl form. In its giant owl form, it is merely a creature, not an animal companion or familiar. After three uses of its giant owl form, the figurine loses that transformation ability forever but still functions normally in its horned owl form as an animal companion or familiar. </p>
			<p>Silver Raven (C, F): The raven is treated as a bird animal companion or a raven familiar. It retains its metallic appearance and animal messenger ability (though this is redundant for an intelligent familiar) but not its hardness when in animal form. </p>
			<p>While the figurine is active, you and the active figurine gain all the normal benefits of having a companion creature; for example, a wizard with a silver raven familiar gains a +3 bonus on Appraise checks, the raven can speak one language, and so on. While the figure is inactive, you gain none of these benefits but are not otherwise hampered by its inert state (as if the creature were out of range but not dead). The usable duration of the companion figurine doubles; for example, an ebony fly is normally usable up to three times per week for up to 12 hours per use, but as a companion creature you may use it up to six times per week for up to 12 hours per use. The figurine is still a magic item and is subject to effects like antimagic field and dispel magic that affect magic items; it uses its caster level or your own, whichever is greater.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Compelling Harmonies" title="Compelling Harmonies" groups="Teamwork" description="Your harmonies reinforce and empower your allies' magic.">
		<Prerequisites>Basic Harmony, Perform (keyboard, percussion, sing, string, or wind) 10 ranks, bardic performance or raging song.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you may expend one round of bardic performance to boost the effectiveness of the bardic performance of an ally within 60 feet who also has this feat. Until the beginning of your next turn, if that ally uses a bardic performance that allows a saving throw, increase that saving throw DC by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Compounded Pain" title="Compounded Pain" groups="Combat" description="Your painful stare causes two additional effects.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 13th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can apply the effects of two stare feats to your painful stares.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can apply the effects of only one stare feat to a given painful stare.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Compulsion Mastery" title="Compulsion Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can gain influence over the minds of others using enchantment magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude save bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cast suggestion as per the spell by using an item that has an enchantment spell of 3rd level or higher in its construction requirements.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day at base Fortitude save bonus +9 and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Conceal Scent" title="Conceal Scent" groups="3.5E" description="You have learned the essential tricks of disguising your odor and keeping creatures from locating you by your scent.">
		<Prerequisites>Stealth 1 rank, Survival 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Creatures cannot use the scent ability to track you (though they can still track you through standard means such as footprints). Creatures with scent can detect your presence by smell at half the normal distance, but cannot pinpoint your location with scent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Conceal Spell" title="Conceal Spell" groups="" description="You can hide the evidence of spells you cast.">
		<Prerequisites>Deceitful, Bluff 1 rank, Disguise 1 rank, Sleight of Hand 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast a spell or use a spell-like ability, you can attempt to conceal verbal and somatic components among other speech and gestures, and to conceal the manifestation of casting the spell, so others don&apos;t realize you&apos;re casting a spell or using a spell-like ability until it is too late. The attempt to hide the spell slows your casting slightly, such that spells that normally take a standard action to cast now take a full-round action, and spells that normally take longer than a standard action take twice as long. (Swift action spells still take a swift action.) To discover your ruse, a creature must succeed at a Perception, Sense Motive, or Spellcraft check (the creature receives an automatic check with whichever of those skills has the highest bonus) against a DC equal to 15 + your number of ranks in Bluff or Disguise (whichever is higher) + your Charisma modifier; the creature gains a bonus on its check equal to the level of the spell or spell-like ability you are concealing.</p>
			<p>If your spell has a somatic component, any creature that can see you receives a Perception or Spellcraft check (whichever has the highest bonus) against a DC equal to 15 + your number of ranks in Sleight of Hand + your Dexterity modifier; the creature gains a bonus on its check equal to the level of the spell or spell-like ability you are concealing.</p>
			<p>Since you are concealing the spell&apos;s manifestation through other actions, others observing you realize you&apos;re doing something, even if they don&apos;t realize you&apos;re casting a spell. If there is a verbal component, they still hear your loud, clear voice but don&apos;t notice the spell woven within.</p>
			<p>If an opponent fails its check, your casting also does not provoke attacks of opportunity, and an opponent that fails its check can&apos;t use readied actions that depend on realizing that you&apos;re casting a spell or using a spell-like ability, or readied actions such as counterspelling that require identifying the spell you&apos;re casting. Spells such as fireball that create an additional obvious effect (aside from the manifestation of casting that all spells and spell-like abilities share) still create that effect, though it might not be obvious who cast the spell unless it emanates from you.</p>
			<p>If a character interacts with you long enough to attempt a Sense Motive check without realizing you have been casting spells, that character can use Sense Motive to gain a hunch that you&apos;re behaving unusually.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Concealment Mastery" title="Concealment Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can use illusion magic items to conceal your presence, or possibly even your true nature.">
		<Prerequisites>Stealth 3 ranks, Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude saving throw bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has an illusion spell of 1st level or higher listed in its construction requirements to cast vanish. If you have 7 ranks in both Stealth and Use Magic Device, you can instead cause an item that has an illusion spell of 2nd level or higher listed in its construction requirements to cast either invisibility or undetectable alignment. You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day when your base Fortitude save bonus reaches +9 and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Concentrated Fire" title="Concentrated Fire" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="Your simultaneous ranged attacks punch through your foe's defenses with ease.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot, elf, weapon familiarity racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you and a single ally who also has this feat both ready an action to each make a ranged attack against the same opponent and choose the same condition for the readied action, when you and the ally make those attacks, each of you can use the highest of the two attack rolls for your attack roll. Furthermore, if you and your ally both hit the target, you can total the damage for both attacks before applying the target&apos;s damage reduction or energy resistance.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Concentrated Splash" title="Concentrated Splash" groups="Combat" description="You can limit the splatter of your splash weapons to increase damage against your target.">
		<Prerequisites>Precise Shot or Throw Anything.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you deal a direct hit to a creature with a splash weapon that normally also deals splash damage, you can choose to forgo dealing splash damage.</p>
			<p>If you do, the damage dealt to the target of the direct hit increases by 50%. This damage is multiplied on a critical hit.</p>
			<p>This feat cannot be used with an alchemist&apos;s bombs.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Concussive Spell" title="Concussive Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You cause creatures to be disoriented when you affect them with a spell that has the sonic descriptor.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>With sonic damage comes a concussive wave of energy that rattles creatures affected by the spell. A concussive spell causes creatures that take damage from a spell that has the sonic descriptor to take a &#x2013;2 penalty on attack rolls, saving throws, skill checks, and ability checks for a number of rounds equal to the actual spell level of the spell. A concussive spell only affects spells with the sonic descriptor.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (a concussive spell uses up a spell slot two levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Conditional Spell" title="Conditional Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You know how to apply restrictions on how a creature can use the benefits of your spells.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>A conditional spell is subject to the rules laid out in the spell conditional favor.</p>
			<p>Metamagic Adjustment: +1 (a conditional spell takes up a spell slot 1 level higher than normal.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Confabulist" title="Confabulist" groups="" description="Sometimes your second attempt at a deception does the trick.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 9 ranks, Sense Motive 9 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you fail to deceive someone with a Bluff check, you can immediately attempt another version of the same basic deception against that creature at a &#x2013;5 penalty by downplaying the failed Bluff and quickly moving on to another one. You cannot use this ability if the first Bluff was so egregious that further checks would have been impossible (as per the Bluff skill). If you fail the second attempt, you cannot retry the Bluff check and all further attempts to perpetrate that particular deception are impossible.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When you fail a Bluff check against a creature, that creature is innately suspicious. You take a &#x2013;10 penalty on future attempts to deceive that creature, or at the GM&apos;s discretion, such attempts may be impossible.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Confounding Tumble Deed" title="Confounding Tumble Deed" groups="Panache" description="You can befuddle a foe by striking a blow after tumbling.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Swashbuckler feat or panache class feature, Canny Tumble, Acrobatics 7 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Acrobatics to move through an opponent&apos;s threatened area or space without provoking an attack of opportunity from that opponent and then hit that foe with a melee attack in the same round, as a free action you can spend 1 panache point to deny that foe its Dexterity bonus to its armor class until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Confusing Stare" title="Confusing Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your stare addles your foe's mind.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 7th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you trigger your painful stare, the target must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + half your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or else become confused for 1 round. The target must roll twice to determine the result of its confused condition, and you select which roll is used.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Consecrate Spell" title="Consecrate Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You infuse spells with heavenly power, drastically increasing their effectiveness against would-be heralds of evil.">
		<Prerequisites>Aasimar, able to prepare or cast consecrate.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A consecrated spell is treated as a maximized spell against evil creatures and creatures with the evil subtype. Against all other creatures, this feat does not modify the spell in any way (for example, a consecrated fireball acts as a normal fireball against neutral or good creatures). This feat does not stack with Maximize Spell.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (a consecrated spell uses up a spell slot two levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Consume Essence" title="Consume Essence" groups="Combat, Monster" description="Creatures that you swallow are quickly absorbed and soon utterly annihilated.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6; evil alignment; swallow whole universal monster ability; must be of the magical beast, outsider, or undead type.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you start your turn having swallowed at least one creature, each swallowed creature must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your Hit Dice + your Charisma modifier) or gain a temporary negative level. Swallowed creatures that die from these negative levels are consumed as per disintegrate. This is a death effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are of the undead type, each time a swallowed creature gains a temporary negative level from this ability, you add 5 temporary hit points to the number of hit points that swallowed creatures must deal to escape, up to a maximum of 15 temporary hit points. These temporary hit points last for 10 minutes.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Contagious Spell" title="Contagious Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells are dangerous to dispel and likely to backfire upon those who try.">
	Requirement(s): You can apply Contagious Spell only to targeted spells that are harmful to their target and don&apos;t have a range of personal; a contagious spell never spreads to someone who would benefit from being the target of the spell.
		<Benefit>
			<p>A caster level check to dispel or remove a contagious spell that fails by 5 or more causes it to spread from the original target to the creature that attempted to remove it. The spell spreads to the new target regardless of its normal range or any special targeting requirement like a melee or ranged touch attack. The spell is treated as if you had just cast it on the new target. The new target receives a saving throw or the benefit of spell resistance (if applicable) if the spell normally allows it.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (an contagious spell uses up a spell slot 2 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A contagious spell can be identified normally as it is being cast with a successful Spellcraft check.</p>
			<p>Identifying whether a spell is contagious by its effect, however, requires the use of the analyze dweomer spell or a similar effect.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Contingent Channeling" title="Contingent Channeling" groups="" description="You can imbue others with your healing energy so that they can use it at the moment of greatest need.">
		<Prerequisites>True healer class feature, Selective Channeling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use a standard action to touch an ally and expend one of your daily uses of channel energy to create a repository of positive energy within that ally. This repository contains the same number and type of dice as normal for your channel energy feature, and it lasts for 1 minute. An ally who has such a repository can use an immediate action to roll the repository&apos;s dice and regain a number of hit points equal to the result. If an ally who has such a repository is reduced to negative hit points, the repository triggers, allowing the ally to heal without using an action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Contingent Spell" title="Contingent Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You are able to set up healing spells in advance so that they instantly take effect at the most opportune moments, especially those that take place on the field of battle.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast cure spells (a cure spell is any spell with &apos;cure&apos; in its name).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A contingent spell infuses a target with a dormant healing or restorative spell that can trigger when the target needs it the most. This metamagic feat can be applied to only cure spells; breath of life; or any harmless spell that can be used to remove ability score damage, ability score drain, or a negative condition or effect (including break enchantment, neutralize poison, and remove disease). When you cast a contingent spell, you must set a specific trigger that dictates under what circumstances the target is immediately subject to the spell&apos;s effects (for instance, &apos;When the target dies, breath of life takes effect&apos;). The contingent spell&apos;s effects can remain dormant within the target for up to 10 minutes per caster level you have. A creature can be infused with only one contingent spell at a time.</p>
			<p>Metamagic Adjustment: +2 (a contingent spell uses up a spell slot 2 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Conviction" title="Conviction" groups="" description="Your actions are bolstered by divine determination.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you present to a vampire a holy symbol or other object it is averse to, the DC for the creature to overcome such an aversion increases by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cooperative Counterspelling" title="Cooperative Counterspelling" groups="Teamwork" description="Thanks to your heritage, you can thwart magical attacks almost instinctively.">
		<Prerequisites>Spellcraft 5 ranks, racial spell-like ability replicating a spell of 1st level or higher.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you and an ally who also has this feat both ready an action to counterspell, you can counter a spell if you both expend any spell of the same level and school as the spell you wish to counter. If you both attempt to counterspell with dispel magic, you each gain a +2 bonus on your caster level checks. If you have more than one ally readying an action to counterspell, you can select only one of those allies for the purpose of this feat, and that ally must also select you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cooperative Crafting" title="Cooperative Crafting" groups="" description="Your assistance makes item crafting far more efficient.">
		<Prerequisites>1 rank in any Craft skill, any item creation feat.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can assist another character in crafting mundane and magical items. You must both possess the relevant Craft skill or item creation feat, but either one of you can fulfill any other prerequisites for crafting the item. You provide a +2 circumstance bonus on any Craft or Spellcraft checks related to making an item, and your assistance doubles the gp value of items that can be crafted each day.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cooperative Disabling" title="Cooperative Disabling" groups="Teamwork" description="You are skilled at working with an ally to disable traps.">
		<Prerequisites>Disable Device 1 rank, trapfinding class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the Disable Device skill and fail the check against a trap, a single adjacent ally with this feat who is also within reach of the trap can attempt a Disable Device check against the same device as an immediate action. The ally must have remained adjacent throughout the process of disabling the device and must have either aided your Disable Device check or taken no other action. If your ally succeeds at the check, your attempt is considered to be successful. If your ally fails, your attempt is considered to have failed by 5 or more, even if the original check failed by 4 or less.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cooperative Rend" title="Cooperative Rend" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You and an ally each sink a claw into your foethen all you have to do is pull.">
		<Prerequisites>Rend, troll.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you and an ally who has this feat are both threatening the same creature, you must hit the target with at least one of your claw attacks to use your rend ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You must hit with two of your claw attacks to use your rend ability.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cooperative Swarmer Combat" title="Cooperative Swarmer Combat" groups="Combat" description="You're a team player and help out those normally too large or clumsy to fight in close quarters with you.">
		<Prerequisites>Swarming racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can share a square with an ally your size or larger, even if your ally does not have the swarming racial trait. Neither you nor the creature you share a space with count as flanking your targets, but you gain a +2 shield bonus to AC while sharing a square with a larger ally. If you perform an aid another action to aid your ally&apos;s attack roll or AC, increase the bonus you provide by 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coordinated Blast" title="Coordinated Blast" groups="Teamwork" description="With trained precision, you create safe pockets within the areas of your spells, inside which your allies remain safe.">
		<Prerequisites>Spellcraft 5 ranks, any racial spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use a spell or ability with an area (such as fireball or channel energy), you can exclude any number of allies who also have this feat from that area of effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coordinated Charge" title="Coordinated Charge" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You are an expert at leading your allies into the fray.">
		<Prerequisites>You have at least two other teamwork feats, base attack bonus +10.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When an ally with this feat charges a creature that is no further away from you than your speed, you can, as an immediate action, charge that creature. You must be able to follow all of the normal charge rules.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coordinated Defense" title="Coordinated Defense" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You are adept at working with allies to avoid being tripped, grappled, and subjected to other maneuvers.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are adjacent to an ally who also has this feat, you receive a +2 competence bonus to your Combat Maneuver Defense. This bonus increases to +4 if the creature attempting the maneuver is larger than both you and your ally.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coordinated Distraction" title="Coordinated Distraction" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="When working in tandem, you can make it difficult for foes to use their magical abilities.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you and at least one ally with this feat threaten the same enemy, the enemy treats the DC to cast spells defensively as 2 higher for each threatening character with this feat. If you or your allies are incapable of taking an attack of opportunity against the target for any reason, the effects of this feat do not apply.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coordinated Maneuvers" title="Coordinated Maneuvers" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You are skilled at working with your allies to perform dangerous combat maneuvers.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are adjacent to an ally who also has this feat, you receive a +2 competence bonus on all combat maneuver checks. This bonus increases to +4 when attempting to break free from a grapple.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coordinated Shot" title="Coordinated Shot" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="Your ranged attacks against an opponent take advantage of your ally's positioning.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If your ally with this feat is threatening an opponent and is not providing cover to that opponent against your ranged attacks, you gain a +1 bonus on ranged attacks against that opponent. If your ally with this feat is flanking that opponent with another ally (even if that other ally doesn&apos;t have this feat), this bonus increases to +2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cornugon Shield" title="Cornugon Shield" groups="Combat" description="You can use your spiked chain as both armor and weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Weapon Focus (spiked chain).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a spiked chain, you gain a +1 shield bonus to your AC. When you are fighting defensively or using the total defense action, this shield bonus increases to +2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cornugon Smash" title="Cornugon Smash" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Power Attack, Intimidate 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you damage an opponent with a Power Attack, you may make an immediate Intimidate check as a free action to attempt to demoralize your opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cornugon Stun" title="Cornugon Stun" groups="Combat" description="You are able to make stunning attacks with special monk weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Stunning Fist.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may use Stunning Fist when making melee attacks with special monk weapons as well as when making unarmed attacks.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only use Stunning Fist when making an attack with an unarmed strike.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cornugon Trip" title="Cornugon Trip" groups="Combat" description="You can throw your spiked chain to make trip attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Improved Trip, Weapon Focus (spiked chain).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may throw your spiked chain (as if it were a thrown weapon with a range increment of 10 feet) and can make trip attacks when throwing it. Failing at this attack does not knock you prone.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Corsair" title="Corsair" groups="" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Spent at least 1 month working on a ship.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on initiative checks made while on a ship and deal an additional +1 damage when using light or one-handed weapons on a ship.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cosmopolitan" title="Cosmopolitan" groups="" description="Living in large, exotic cities has put you in touch with many diverse civilizations, cultures, and races.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can speak and read two additional languages of your choice. In addition, choose two Intelligence-, Wisdom-, or Charisma-based skills. Those skills always count as class skills for you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Counter Reflexes" title="Counter Reflexes" groups="Combat" description="Your opponent's advanced training in moving around you is surpassed only by your readiness for it.">
		<Prerequisites>Anticipate Dodge, Dodge, Mobility; base attack bonus +9, brawler level 6th, or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Opponents with the Mobility feat do not gain the dodge bonus granted by that feat when they provoke attacks of opportunity by moving out of or within your threatened area.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Counterpoint to Inspiration" title="Counterpoint to Inspiration" groups="Teamwork" description="As your allies' morale swells, your enemies falter.">
		<Prerequisites>Basic Harmony, Compelling Harmonies, Perform (keyboard, percussion, sing, string, or wind) 10 ranks, bardic performance or raging song.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When an ally with this feat is within 60 feet and uses a bardic performance or raging song that grants allies a morale bonus or competence bonus, you may perform the same bardic performance or raging song to increase those bonuses by +1. This increase only lasts as long as you and your ally each maintain the same performance, and cannot be extended with effects like Lingering Performance.</p>
			<p>Additional bards with this feat beyond the second don&apos;t increase the bonuses further.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Counterpunch" title="Counterpunch" groups="Combat" description="With deft reflexes, you capitalize on opponents' mistake.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 18, Combat Reflexes, Improved Unarmed Strike, Weapon Focus (unarmed strike); base attack bonus +16 or brawler level 12th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per round, when you are fighting unarmed with both hands free and an opponent misses you with a melee attack, it provokes an attack of opportunity from you. You must use an unarmed strike for this attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Courageous Resolve" title="Courageous Resolve" groups="Halfling" description="Even when others run, you tend to stand your ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Craven racial trait or fearless racial trait, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you have the fearless racial trait, your racial bonus on saving throws against fear effects increases to +4. If you have the craven racial trait, you still take the &#x2013;2 penalty on fear saves, but you can gain the benefit of morale bonuses on saving throws against fear effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Coven Caster" title="Coven Caster" groups="" description="You share your mother's gift for working in groups.">
		<Prerequisites>Changeling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can attempt a special aid another action (1d20 + your choice of your Intelligence or Charisma modifier; DC 10). If you succeed, you can increase an adjacent spellcaster&apos;s caster level by 1 until the beginning of your next turn. If you also have the coven witch hex, you can apply this bonus to all members of your coven within 30 feet.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cover Tracks" title="Cover Tracks" groups="" description="You are very difficult to follow in the wild, leaving few tracks in your wake.">
		<Prerequisites>Survival 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You increase the DC of Survival checks to track you by 5 when moving at full speed and by 10 when moving at half speed. You can cover the tracks of a number of allies within 30 feet equal to your Wisdom modifier plus half your character level, increasing the DC to track them by 2 if they are moving at full speed or by 5 if they are moving at half speed.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the favored terrain class feature and you are in that terrain, you also add your favored terrain bonus to the DC to track you or your allies.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Covering Defense" title="Covering Defense" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at protecting yourself and your allies with your shield.">
		<Prerequisites>Shield Focus, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the total defense action while using a light, heavy, or tower shield, you can provide a cover bonus to AC against all attacks to an adjacent ally your size or smaller. This cover bonus is equal to your shield&apos;s shield bonus and lasts until the beginning of your next turn. your shield does not provide a cover bonus to reflex saves.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Covering Fire" title="Covering Fire" groups="Combat,Teamwork; RTT" description="You distract your enemies with ranged attacks to protect your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use the aid another action with a ranged attack against an opponent, regardless of whether the opponent threatens an ally. Range penalties apply to this attack roll. Choose one ally when making the attack. If the attack is successful, that ally gains a +2 bonus to AC against that opponent&apos;s next attack, as long as the attack comes before the beginning of your next turn. All allies with this feat also gain this bonus against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Covering Shield" title="Covering Shield" groups="Combat" description="You can use your shield to protect your most vulnerable parts from area effects.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Shield Focus, Shield Proficiency.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using a shield of the type to which your Shield Focus feat applies, you gain a bonus on Reflex saves against area of effect attacks equal to your shield&apos;s base bonus to armor class plus any bonuses granted by feats or class abilities. This does not transfer any enhancement bonuses on a shield to Reflex saves.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cracking the Shell" title="Cracking the Shell" groups="Combat, Combination" description="The tip of your weapon pierces both the body and the spirit.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with piercing weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you deal damage with a melee attack with a piercing weapon to an opponent you have already damaged this round, you can also reduce the value of that target&apos;s spell resistance or energy resistances by 1 until the start of your next turn. This reduction stacks with itself.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Construct" title="Craft Construct" groups="Item Creation" description="Contents">
	You can create construct creatures like golems.
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 5th, Craft Magic Arms and Armor, Craft Wondrous Item.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create any construct whose prerequisites you meet. The act of animating a construct takes one day for each 1,000 gp in its market price. To create a construct, you must use up raw materials costing half of its base price, plus the full cost of the basic body created for the construct. Each construct has a special section that summarizes its costs and other prerequisites. A newly created construct has average hit points for its Hit Dice.</p>
			<p>A homunculus is shaped from a mixture of clay, ash, mandrake root, spring water, and one pint of the creator&apos;s own blood. These materials cost 50 gp. After the body is sculpted, it is animated through an extended magical ritual that requires a specially prepared laboratory or workroom, similar to an alchemist&apos;s laboratory, and costing an additional 1,000 gp to supply. If the creator is personally constructing the creature&apos;s body, the building and ritual can be performed together. A homunculus with more than 2 Hit Dice can be created, but each additional Hit Die adds +2,000 gp to the cost to create.</p>
			<p>The person whose blood is used to form a homunculus&apos;s body becomes its master; it is possible for one person to give blood for the creation, another to sculpt the base material, and another to magically animate it as a minion for the one who provided the blood.</p>
			<p>CL 7th; Price 2,050 gp</p>
			<p>CONSTRUCTION REQUIREMENTS</p>
			<p>Feats Craft Construct, arcane eye, mirror image, mending; Skill Craft (leather) or Craft (sculptures) DC 12; Cost 1,050 gp.</p>
			<p>A character with the Craft Construct feat can create homunculi with new abilities in addition to those normally possessed by homunculi.</p>
			<p>To create a homunculus with one or more improvements, the crafter must include large quantities of certain reagents (represented by the price listed for each of the improvements below) while performing the ritual to create a homunculus. For every 1,000 gp worth of additional abilities to be granted to the homunculus, the DC of the Craft check to create the homunculus increases by 1 (minimum +1).</p>
			<p>The crafter can also add new abilities to an existing homunculus by performing a brief surgical procedure. To do so, the crafter must purchase the necessary reagents and make a successful Heal check (DC equal to the DC of the Craft check necessary to create such a homunculus from scratch).</p>
			<p>After encountering constructs firsthand on an adventure, it is only natural that you might want to have such a loyal and potentially powerful ally for yourself. The Craft Construct feat has been a part of the game from the beginning, but the process of crafting a construct, like crafting any magic item, can be confusing. The following section outlines in greater detail the various things to consider when attempting to craft a construct, making the process easier to understand.</p>
			<p>In addition to raw materials, you must supply certain spells to animate a construct, potentially in addition to any other requirements. The exact requirements vary from one construct to another and are included in its construction requirements entry.</p>
			<p>Item Creation Feat: You must have the Craft Construct feat to create a construct. This requirement is mandatory and cannot be avoided unless you have a class feature, feat, or other ability that specifically allows you to do so. Note that because Craft Construct requires both the Craft Magic Arms and Armor and Craft Wondrous Item feats, as well as caster level 5th, these prerequisites will need to be met as well. Some constructs may require you to have one or more additional feats. If these are item creation feats, they are also mandatory.</p>
			<p>Spell Requirements: A construct&apos;s spell requirements are listed in the construction requirements section of the stat block, in alphabetical order. As with other magic items, you must have prepared the spells to be cast (or must know the spells, in the case of spontaneous spellcasters) but need not provide any material components or focuses the spells require. The act of working on the construct expends the prepared spells, making them unavailable for casting during each day of the construct&apos;s creation (that is, those spell slots are expended from the caster&apos;s currently prepared spells, just as if they had been cast.) For each spell requirement you do not meet, the DC to craft the construct increases by 5.</p>
			<p>Caster Level: Some constructs, especially the more powerful ones, require the creator to be of a certain caster level in order to craft them. Unlike some other crafting requirements, this requirement must be met in order to craft the construct, and cannot be ignored simply by increasing the DC of the skill check to craft the construct by 5.</p>
			<p>Special Requirements: Some constructs have special requirements or restrictions governing their creation.</p>
			<p>Robots, as a general rule, cannot be crafted by player characters, as their construction requires highly specialized and complex technology that is not normally available.</p>
			<p>Other constructs have specific requirements that the caster must meet. As a general rule, unless the description of the construct indicates otherwise, any additional construction requirements other than feats can be bypassed by increasing the DC of the skill check to craft the construct by 5.</p>
			<p>In order to create a construct, you must first gather the necessary materials. This includes both the materials that form the construct&apos;s body and additional materials worth half the base price of the construct. Each construct that can be crafted lists a cost, in gp, in the construction requirements section. This cost includes both the cost of the construct&apos;s body and the cost of the additional materials; this is the full amount that you must pay in order to create the construct.</p>
			<p>The full cost for the construct, including any cost required to provide its body, must be paid before work can begin on the construct.</p>
			<p>Finding Materials: Most of the time, it is assumed that the materials for creating the construct&apos;s body are readily available and can simply be purchased as part of the cost of the construct&apos;s creation. However, depending on the nature of the construct and the materials available at hand, this may not always be the case. Typically, a construct&apos;s entry will describe exactly what its body is made of. If those materials are not readily available for purchase, then you must collect them by some other means, which may involve an adventure run by the GM. Other times, the construct&apos;s body may already be found fully prepared, potentially inspiring the players to attempt to craft a construct of that specific type.</p>
			<p>In this case, the cost for the construct&apos;s body itself does not need to be paid.</p>
			<p>Animating a construct can be a time-consuming process.</p>
			<p>The act of animating a construct takes 1 day for every 1,000 gp in its market price (note that this is different than the cost that must be paid to create the construct). For the purposes of crafting constructs (as well as other magic items), 1 day of work consists of 8 hours of uninterrupted labor, which must occur in a fairly quiet, comfortable, and well-lit place. Certain types of constructs may require specialized equipment or laboratories in order to craft, and in this case, the crafter must have access to these resources and facilities.</p>
			<p>Accelerated Work: You cannot rush the process of crafting a construct by working for more than 8 hours in a given day (even if you do not need to sleep, or are otherwise able to get extra hours out of the day). However, if you increase the DC to create the construct by 5 (a decision that must be made before the crafting process begins), you can accelerate the process to require only 4 hours of work per 1,000 gp in the item&apos;s base price. This allows you to effectively accomplish 2 days&apos; worth of work in a single day, or finish the construct in the same number of days by spending less time on it each day.</p>
			<p>Dangerous Conditions: If you are not able to fully focus on your work, it takes much longer to accomplish. Characters attempting to craft in distracting or dangerous conditions, such as a crafter who is working while out adventuring, do so at a much slower pace. You can devote only 4 hours per day to item creation while adventuring or in similar conditions, and you work at half the normal pace (so you complete only 2 hours of work that day).</p>
			<p>Intermittent Creation: You do not need to continue working on crafting a construct nonstop until you finish it. While each 8-hour (or 4-hour) block of time spent on crafting must be continuous, once those hours have been spent, you can stop work to pursue other activities as you see fit. You can leave a project partially finished for days, weeks, or even months, not making any progress toward its completion, without impacting the crafting process (provided you do not start crafting something else; see Simultaneous Creation below).</p>
			<p>Simultaneous Creation: You can work on only one item at a time. If you start work on a new item, all materials used on the previous item (as well as all progress made on it) are wasted. This applies to all magic items, not just constructs, so for example if you are working on a crafting a stone golem and take a break to craft a hat of disguise, the materials and progress put towards the stone golem will be lost.</p>
			<p>Crafting a construct isn&apos;t easy, and not everyone is able to do it. Simply spending time and money does not make the construct spring into existence. Instead, the crafter must succeed at a skill check in order to successfully craft the construct. The skill check is not attempted until the very end of the process, once you have spent the required time working on the construct.</p>
			<p>Skill Type: The exact skills that can be used to craft a particular construct are given in its construction requirements and vary from one construct type to another. As a general rule, most constructs require a Craft skill of some kind, although some may allow other skills (such as the flesh golem, which can be created with Heal). Most constructs list more than one possible skill, and you can choose which of these skills to use when making the check.</p>
			<p>DC: The DC of the skill check to craft a construct is located in its construction requirements and varies from one construct type to another. Generally speaking, the DC is equal to 5 + the default caster level of the construct. Beyond this base DC, several modifiers can increase the DC.</p>
			<p>Accelerated Crafting: When you begin crafting a construct, you can choose to work at an accelerated pace. This halves the amount of time required to create the construct but increases the DC of the skill check to create the construct by 5.</p>
			<p>Unmet Prerequisites: As with creating any other magic item, there are certain prerequisites that are mandatory (such as the item creation feat) and others that are optional (such as the spell requirements). For each optional component that you fail to meet, the DC to create the construct increases by 5.</p>
			<p>Failure: If you fail the skill check to craft the construct by less than 5, the attempt fails, and the materials and time spent crafting the construct are wasted. Normally, if a character fails a check to create a magic item by 5 or more, the result is a cursed item. At the GM&apos;s discretion, if a player fails a check to create a construct by 5 or more, the results may be more dire&#x2014;the magic animating the construct might fail spectacularly and result in a damaging explosion, or the resulting construct could be uncontrolled and violent.</p>
			<p>Once the crafting process is complete, the resulting construct is ready to receive orders. A construct recognizes its creator intuitively and obeys all commands issued to it by that individual.</p>
			<p>Hit Points: A newly created construct has the average hit points for its Hit Dice. When a construct is created, it has full hit points and is not damaged.</p>
			<p>Feats and Skills: Most constructs are mindless, and so they do not have feats or skills. However, a small number of constructs have an Intelligence score, and their creator determines what feats and skill ranks the construct has when it is created. This choice cannot later be changed.</p>
			<p>Besides the normal method of crafting a construct from scratch, there are several ways that you can potentially go about gaining possession of a construct.</p>
			<p>Golem Manuals: The wondrous items known as golem manuals contain all the information and magical power required to create a particular kind of golem. This effectively grants the Craft Construct feat to anyone using the manual to craft a golem of that type, and it provides an increase in caster level for the purpose of meeting the prerequisite to craft that specific type of golem. Further, the manual grants a +5 competence bonus on skill checks to craft the golem and contains all the necessary spells, which can be activated by anyone who has the relevant spells on their class&apos;s spell list (but only for the purpose of crafting the golem). When using a golem manual, you must still spend the normal amount of time to craft the golem and pay the cost of the golem&apos;s body (or provide it through other means), but you do not need to pay the rest of the normal cost to create the golem.</p>
			<p>For example, with a clay golem manual, you would need to provide a body worth 1,500 gp (rather than the normal full cost of 21,500 gp), spend 42 days constructing the golem&apos;s body (1 for each 1,000 gp in the normal price of the golem), have a caster level of 9th or higher (as the manual provides a +2 bonus and the normal requirement is 11th level), have animate objects, bless, commune, prayer, and resurrection on your class&apos;s spell list, and succeed at a DC 16 Craft (sculptures) or Craft (pottery) check (but the manual gives you a +5 bonus on the check.)</p>
			<p>Purchasing a Construct: Rather than go through all the hassle of building a construct from scratch, you can always allow someone else to do all of the work for you and simply purchase the results. of course, this can be quite expensive, as a great deal of time and energy goes into the creation of constructs, and those who are skilled enough to craft them generally charge a premium for their services. Any construct that can be crafted has a market price, which is usually fairly close to twice the cost to craft the construct. Purchasing a construct follows the same rules as purchasing other magic items, meaning that for particularly powerful and expensive constructs, a prospective buyer might need to travel to a sufficiently large city.</p>
			<p>Stealing a Construct: Generally speaking, constructs are quite difficult to steal, being large and heavy. More to the point, stealing them is not terribly effective unless you have a way to control them. One option is the spell control construct, which can grant a limited ability to hijack a construct. By using the spell to bring the construct to a desired location and giving it a final command before the spell ends, you can set the construct to guard a desired spot or direct it to simply wait for you to cast control construct on it again the next time you want to give it orders. of course, if the construct&apos;s true owner is able to track it down or you lose control of the construct, you might find the stolen construct turned against you!</p>
			<p>Presented here are new construct modifications that can be used to alter or enhance existing constructs so that they are suited to particular purposes.</p>
			<p>These modifications are used to alter a construct&apos;s basic properties: movement speed, resistances, senses and spell-like abilities.</p>
			<p>Movement Modification: This modification improves a construct&apos;s existing movement. This modification can improve a construct&apos;s land speed, increasing the speed by 10 feet, up to a total speed equal to double its original land speed. Each 10-foot improvement costs 2,000 gp. Constructs with a climb or swim speed can improve these speeds by 10 feet, up to a total speed equal to double the original speed, at a cost of 3,000 gp per 10-foot improvement. Constructs with a fly speed can improve these speeds by 10 feet, up to a total speed equal to double the original speed, at a cost of 4,000 gp per 10-foot improvement.</p>
			<p>Constructs can also gain new means of locomotion with this modification. A construct can gain a climb or swim speed of 15 feet at a cost of 6,000 gp. A construct can gain a fly speed of 15 feet at a cost of 8,000 gp so long as it has at least 5 Hit Dice. A Tiny or smaller construct gains a maneuverability of good, a Medium or Small construct gains a maneuverability of average, a Large or Huge construct gains a maneuverability of poor, and Gargantuan or larger constructs gain a maneuverability of clumsy.</p>
			<p>Resistances: This modification grants resistances to a construct or improves existing resistances. The construct gains energy resistance 5 to one of the following energy types: acid, cold, electricity, or fire. This base resistance costs 4,000 gp. This modification can also improve resistance to the above energy types, up to a total equal to double the original value or 15, whichever is lower. Improving energy resistance in this way costs 6,000 gp for every increment of 5 by which the resistance is increased. Constructs with vulnerability to one of the above energy types, such as an ice golem&apos;s vulnerability to fire, cannot gain resistance to that energy type with this modification.</p>
			<p>Sense Modification: This modification improves the construct&apos;s existing senses. This modification can improve a construct&apos;s darkvision, extending the range of that darkvision by an additional 30 feet, up to a total range of 120 feet. Each improvement costs 2,500 gp. This modification can also provide blindsense and blindsight to a construct. Blindsense can be added at a cost of 4,000 gp per 30 feet of blindsense, up to a total of 60 feet of blindsense. Blindsight can be added to a construct with blindsense at a cost of 7,500 gp per 15 feet of blindsight, up to a total of 30 feet of blindsight.</p>
			<p>Spell-Like Ability Modification: This modification allows a construct to cast a spell-like ability in a limited capacity. A spell-like ability chosen for this modification can be of any level, but it must be one that the construct&apos;s creator can cast. The construct can cast the selected spell-like ability once per day. Using this modification, a construct&apos;s creator can provide additional castings of the same spell-like ability by paying the cost for that spell multiple times. For example, a construct can gain the ability to cast fireball three times per day if the creator pays for the cost of the spell-like ability three times. A construct&apos;s Hit Dice limit the total amount of spell-like abilities it can gain from this modification. A construct can gain only a number of spell levels through this modification up to a total equal to its Hit Dice. Following the above example, the construct requires at least 9 Hit Dice to cast fireball three times per day. The cost for adding a spell like ability is equal to 3,000 gp per spell level of the spell. For the purposes of this cost, a 0-level spell has a spell level of 1/2.</p>
			<p>These modifications represent more complex changes to the structure and function of the construct; each has specific requirements, a cost equivalent to the minimum level to cast the spell &#xD7; the spell level &#xD7; 250 gp, and a potential increase to the construct&apos;s CR.</p>
			<p>Requirements Craft Construct; Spells alarm</p>
			<p>CR Increase none; Cost 250 gp</p>
			<p>This modification allows a construct to alert its creator with a mental alarm. The creator sets a specific password for the construct. Any creature it encounters that does not speak the password within 1 round causes the construct to activate the mental alarm, which alerts the creator so long as the creator is within 1 mile. The mental alarm awakens the creator from non-magical sleep but does not otherwise disturb concentration.</p>
			<p>The creator can deactivate or reactivate a construct&apos;s alarm feature as a standard action. The maximum distance of the mental alarm can be increased by paying an additional 250 gp for each additional mile of maximum distance.</p>
			<p>Requirements Craft Construct, Craft Wondrous Item, mage&apos;s private sanctum, Small or larger construct</p>
			<p>CR Increase none; Cost 11,250 gp</p>
			<p>This modification allows a construct to transform into a shelter capable of housing its creator and her allies. The transformation is a rigorous process that requires 10 minutes to complete. Once transformed, the shelter can house a number of inhabitants based on the construct&apos;s size. A Colossal construct can house one Colossal creature, two Gargantuan creatures, four Huge creatures, eight Large creatures, 16 Medium creatures, or 32 Small creatures. A Gargantuan construct can house one Gargantuan creature, two Huge creatures, four Large creatures, eight Medium creatures, or sixteen Small creatures, and so forth. A construct shelter does not have any accommodations beyond the basics required to rest.</p>
			<p>Creatures within the shelter can see out, but creatures outside cannot see into the shelter.</p>
			<p>The construct can still receive orders and can eject a creature or prevent a creature from entering according to its creator&apos;s orders. A creature can avoid being ejected with a successful Reflex save (DC = 10 + the construct&apos;s CR). A creature that attempts to enter the shelter must attempt to break through with a Strength check opposed by the construct&apos;s Strength check, forcing its way into the shelter on a success. Alternatively, a creature seeking entry can attack the shelter. The shelter always has an AC of 10, but it retains any damage reduction or hardness the construct has. The attacker must deal damage equal to one-quarter the construct&apos;s total hit points to gain entry, reducing the construct&apos;s hit points by an equivalent amount.</p>
			<p>Requirements Craft Construct, Craft Wondrous Item; Spells secret chest, Small or larger construct</p>
			<p>CR Increase none; Cost 11,250 gp</p>
			<p>This modification creates an extradimensional space within the construct, allowing the creator and her allies to store objects within the construct. The construct&apos;s size determines the amount of storage available. A Small construct contains 4 cubic feet of space that can hold up to 25 pounds. This space and weight limit is doubled for each size category larger than Small, up to a total of 128 cubic feet and a weight limit of 800 pounds for a Colossal construct. The construct can retrieve any object held within this space as a swift action. Other creatures accessing this space can retrieve an object as a move action. This extradimensional space otherwise functions like a bag of holding.</p>
			<p>Requirements Craft Construct, telepathy</p>
			<p>CR Increase none; Cost 16,500 gp</p>
			<p>This modification allows a creator to issue orders to its construct via a mental connection. The creator must be within 100 feet of the construct to issue orders in this way. Unintelligent constructs and constructs unable to communicate can receive orders but not respond through this mental connection.</p>
			<p>Requirements Craft Construct; Spells make whole</p>
			<p>CR Increase +1; Cost 1,500 gp</p>
			<p>This modification allows a construct to use some of the innate magic that powers its body to repair damage to itself. As a swift action, the construct can gain fast healing 5. A construct can activate this fast healing for a number of rounds per day equal to half its Hit Dice (minimum 1 round). These rounds do not need to be consecutive. A construct can gain this modification multiple times. Each time, the total number of rounds per day increases by a number equal to half the construct&apos;s Hit Dice (minimum 1 round), up to a maximum equal to double the construct&apos;s Hit Dice. Constructs that already have the fast healing ability instead increase their fast healing value by 2, up to a maximum equal to double the construct&apos;s original fast healing value.</p>
			<p>Requirements Craft Construct; Spells fireball</p>
			<p>CR Increase +1; Cost 3,750 gp</p>
			<p>This modification causes a construct to explode in a shower of razor-sharp scrap and debris when it is reduced to 0 or fewer hit points. All creatures within a 10-foot burst of the construct take a number of points of slashing damage equal to 1d6 times the construct&apos;s CR. A successful Reflex save (DC = 10 + half the construct&apos;s Hit Dice + the construct&apos;s Constitution modifier) halves this damage. If a construct already has a similar ability, such as the death burst of a clockwork golem, the DC of the ability instead increases by 4.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Cybernetics" title="Craft Cybernetics" groups="" description="You can build cyberware and install it in a creature's body.">
		<Prerequisites>Technologist, Heal 9 ranks, Knowledge (engineering) 9 ranks Benefit: You can create cybernetic items. Creating a cybernetic item takes 1 day for every 1,000 gp in the item&apos;s price. To create the object, you must use up raw materials costing half of this total price.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can repair a broken cybernetic item if it is one that you could make. Doing so costs half the raw materials and half the time it would take to craft that item from scratch.</p>
			<p>You can also install a cybernetic item in a creature&apos;s body.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Magic Arms and Armor" title="Craft Magic Arms and Armor" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create magic armor, shields, and weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create magic weapons, armor, or shields. Enhancing a weapon, suit of armor, or shield takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in the price of its magical features. To enhance a weapon, suit of armor, or shield, you must use up raw materials costing half of this total price.</p>
			<p>The weapon, armor, or shield to be enhanced must be a masterwork item that you provide. Its cost is not included in the above cost.You can also mend a broken magic weapon, suit of armor, or shield if it is one that you could make. Doing so costs half the raw materials and half the time it would take to craft that item in the first place.See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Ooze" title="Craft Ooze" groups="Item Creation" description="You can use alchemy to create dangerous ooze creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Brew Potion, Craft Wondrous Item, Craft (alchemy) 3 ranks, caster level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create living oozes as though they were magical items. Creating an ooze creature takes 1 day for each 500 gp in its construction cost. To create an ooze, you must have access to an oozing vat (see below), you must use up raw materials worth the construction cost of the ooze, and you must succeed at a Craft (alchemy) check (DC 10 + 2 &#xD7; the ooze&apos;s CR). A failed check ruins the materials used, while a check that fails by 5 or more also results in an ooze that attacks its creator for 1d4 rounds before dissipating into useless waste material. A newly created ooze has average hit points for its Hit Dice. Oozes created with this feat are mindless and uncontrolled, and even normally intelligent oozes like slithering trackers that are created this way have no Intelligence score&#x2014;nor any loyalty to their creator.</p>
			<p>While ooze creatures cannot normally be purchased in traditional marketplaces, GMs who wish to include such an option in their games&#x2014;perhaps with oozes sold as black market commodities&#x2014; need only double the construction cost of a specific ooze creature in order to figure out a fair market price.</p>
			<p>The following table lists some of the most commonly crafted oozes and their creation requirements. At the GM&apos;s discretion, other types of ooze creatures can be created with this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Pharmaceutical" title="Craft Pharmaceutical" groups="" description="You can craft pharmaceuticals.">
		<Prerequisites>Technologist, Heal 9 ranks, Knowledge (nature) 9 ranks</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create any pharmaceutical or poison. Creating a pharmaceutical takes 2 hours if its base price is 250 gp or less; otherwise, the creation of the pharmaceutical takes 1 day for every 1,000 gp in its price. To create the pharmaceutical or poison, you must use up raw materials costing half of this total price.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Poppet" title="Craft Poppet" groups="Item Creation" description="Some construct builders learn their art by creating poppets.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can craft poppets and add augmentations to existing poppets that you control. You are treated as having both Craft Magic Arms and Armor and Craft Wondrous Item for the purpose of fulfilling the prerequisites for Craft Construct.</p>
			<p>Poppets can be enhanced with a variety of abilities or built in a slightly larger size.The following abilities can be added to a poppet at the time of creation or added later to a poppet under the crafter&apos;s control. Each augmentation is listed with the additional price to a buyer, as well as the additional requirements that a crafter must meet to produce the augmentation (in addition to the Craft Construct or Craft Poppet feat), followed by the additional cost to the crafter.Unless otherwise stated, a poppet can gain each augmentation only once.Agile Poppet (Price +200 gp): The poppet&apos;s joints are carefully articulated to provide it a more flexible range of motion. The poppet gains Acrobatic, Athletic, or Stealthy as a bonus feat. A poppet can gain this augmentation up to three times, providing the poppet with a different feat each time. Requirements: minor creation; Cost: +100 gp.Armored Poppet (Price +300 gp): An armored poppet has thick wooden plates around its torso. The poppet gains a +2 armor bonus to AC. Requirements: mage armor; Cost: +150 gp.Durable Poppet (Price +500 gp): A durable poppet can sustain more blows before breaking apart. It gains 10 additional hit points. Requirements: false life; Cost: +250 gp.Fleet Poppet (Price +250 gp): The poppet has longer legs, allowing it to move more quickly. The poppet&apos;s base land movement speed increases from 20 feet to 30 feet. Requirements: expeditious retreat or longstrider; Cost: +125 gp.Heavy Lifter (Price +250 gp): The poppet has a series of harnesses, plates and sturdy leather straps that allow it to distribute weight more evenly. The poppet&apos;s carrying capacity triples. Requirements: ant haul; Cost: +125 gp.Mighty Poppet (Price +400 gp): The poppet&apos;s Strength score increases by 4. Requirements: bull&apos;s strength; Cost: +200 gp.Nimble Poppet (Price +400 gp): The poppet&apos;s Dexterity score increases by 4. Requirements: cat&apos;s grace; Cost: +200 gp.Scaling Poppet (Price +400 gp): The poppet&apos;s construction integrates climbing tools, allowing it to move across steep surfaces with ease. It gains a climb speed of 20 feet. A poppet must have the Athletic feat before gaining this augmentation. Requirements: minor creation, spider climb; Cost: +200 gp.Sealed Poppet (Price +200 gp): A layer of protective sealants protects the poppet from flames. The poppet loses its vulnerability to fire. Requirements: resist energy; Cost: +100 gp.Soaring Poppet (Price +800 gp): The poppet gains a rudimentary pair of wings, granting it the ability to fly at a speed of 20 feet with poor maneuverability. A poppet can gain this augmentation a second time to increase its fly speed to 30 feet and gain Hover as a bonus feat. A poppet must have the Acrobatic feat before gaining this augmentation. Requirements: fly, minor creation; Cost: +400 gp.Swimming Poppet (Price +400 gp): The poppet bears fins, flippers, or other accessories to assist with swimming. It gains a swim speed of 20 feet. A poppet must have the Athletic feat before gaining this augmentation. Requirements: minor creation, water breathing; Cost: +200 gp.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Rod" title="Craft Rod" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create magic rods.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create magic rods. Crafting a rod takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a rod, you must use up raw materials costing half of its base price.</p>
			<p>See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Shadow Piercing" title="Craft Shadow Piercing" groups="Item Creation" description="You can craft magical piercings infused with the power of shadow.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (jewelry) 5 ranks, caster level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create special wondrous items&#x2014;typically barbs, hooks, rings, and spikes&#x2014;that adorn piercings in the wearer&apos;s flesh and grant magical abilities. Both you and the recipient of the piercing (if not yourself) must be present for the entire piercing process.</p>
			<p>Shadow piercings must be placed in a part of the body normally associated with a magic item slot, but they do not take up a slot on the body, nor interfere with other magic items that use those slots. A single slot can only hold one shadow piercing (non-magical piercings do not count against this limit). Shadow piercings can be applied to the following slots: belt, body, chest, eyes, feet, hands, head, neck, shoulder, and wrist.A single slot can hold multiple physical piercings, though the pieces of jewelry operate as a single item and must be created for that purpose. Shadow piercings have different levels of power: minor, major, and greater. Minor shadow piercings usually include one piece of jewelry, while major and greater shadow piercings often are made up of multiple rings and spikes that cover the entire area of the piercing&apos;s slot (but are still considered a single item). A creature can only use a number of shadow piercings equal its Constitution modifier plus its Wisdom modifier.Carefully inserting or removing a shadow piercing takes a full-round action and deals no damage. Alternatively, a shadow piercing may be pulled out of a creature using the steal maneuver as a standard action that deals 1d6 points of damage. Only a creature with the Craft Shadow Piercing feat may create or insert a shadow piercing, but any creature may remove one. Inserting a shadow piercing is impossible unless the target is willing or helpless. After being removed, a shadow piercing may be inserted into another creature by someone with this feat. Since they are treated as magic items, they are affected by dispel magic.Shadow piercings follow the rules for magic item creation, except the creator can use the Craft (jewelry) skill instead of Spellcraft. New shadow piercings can be researched and designed using the rules for pricing new magic items. Shadow piercing powers for a specific slot must be thematically similar or linked. Since shadow piercings don&apos;t interfere with other magic items in the same slot, but can only have one piercing per slot, the base price is multiplied by 1.5 instead of doubled as if they had no space limitation.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Staff" title="Craft Staff" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create magic staves.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 11th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create any staff whose prerequisites you meet. Crafting a staff takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a staff, you must use up raw materials costing half of its base price. A newly created staff has 10 charges.</p>
			<p>See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Technological Arms and Armor" title="Craft Technological Arms and Armor" groups="" description="You can build technological weapons and armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Technologist, Craft (mechanical) 7 ranks, Knowledge (engineering) 7 ranks</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create technological weapons or armor. Creating a technological weapon or suit of armor takes 1 day for every 1,000 gp in the item&apos;s price. To create the object, you must use up raw materials costing half of this total price.</p>
			<p>You can also repair a broken technological weapon or suit of armor if it is one that you could make. Doing so costs half the raw materials and half the time it would take to craft that item from scratch.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Technological Item" title="Craft Technological Item" groups="" description="You can craft technological gear and items.">
		<Prerequisites>Technologist, Craft (mechanical) 5 ranks, Knowledge (engineering) 5 ranks</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create technological gear. Creating a piece of technological gear takes 1 day for every 1,000 gp in the item&apos;s price. To create the object, you must use up raw materials costing half of this total price.</p>
			<p>You can also repair a broken technological item if it is one that you could make. Doing so costs half the raw materials and half the time it would take to craft that item from scratch.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Wand" title="Craft Wand" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create magic wands.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create a wand of any 4th-level or lower spell that you know. Crafting a wand takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a wand, you must use up raw materials costing half of this base price. A newly created wand has 50 charges.</p>
			<p>See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Craft Wondrous Item" title="Craft Wondrous Item" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create wondrous items, a type of magic item.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create a wide variety of magic wondrous items. Crafting a wondrous item takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its price. To create a wondrous item, you must use up raw materials costing half of its base price.</p>
			<p>You can also mend a broken wondrous item if it is one that you could make. Doing so costs half the raw materials and half the time it would take to craft that item.</p>
			<p>See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crane Riposte" title="Crane Riposte" groups="Combat" description="You use your defensive abilities to make overpowering counterattacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Crane Style, Crane Wing, Dodge, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +8 or monk level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You take only a -1 penalty on attack rolls for fighting defensively.</p>
			<p>Whenever you deflect an opponent&apos;s attack using Crane Wing or lose the dodge bonus from Crane Wing because an attack missed you by 4 or less, you can make an attack of opportunity against the attacker after the attack misses.</p>
			<p>In addition, when you deflect an attack using Crane Wing while taking the total defense action, you may make an attack of opportunity against that opponent (even though you could not normally do so while taking the total defense action).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crane Style" title="Crane Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your unarmed fighting techniques blend poise with graceful defense.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +2 or monk level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You take only a -2 penalty on attack rolls for fighting defensively. While using this style and fighting defensively or using the total defense action, you gain an additional +1 dodge bonus to your Armor Class.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crane Wing" title="Crane Wing" groups="Combat" description="You move with the speed and finesse of an avian hunter, your sweeping blocks and graceful motions allowing you to deflect melee attacks with ease.">
		<Prerequisites>Crane Style, Dodge, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +5 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When fighting defensively with at least one hand free, you gain a +4 dodge bonus to AC against melee attacks. If a melee attack misses you by 4 or less, you lose this dodge bonus until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
			<p>If you using the total defense action instead, you can deflect one melee attack that would normally hit you. An attack so deflected deals no damage and has no other effect (instead treat it as a miss). You do not expend an action when using this feat, but you must be aware of the attack and not flat-footed.</p>
			<p>Original Wording</p>
			<p>Benefit: Once per round while using Crane Style, when you have at least one hand free and are either fighting defensively or using the total defense action, you can deflect one melee weapon attack that would normally hit you. You expend no action to deflect the attack, but you must be aware of it and not flat-footed. An attack so deflected deals no damage to you.</p>
			<p>Editor&apos;s note: Wording of the first benefit paragraph in the second printing:</p>
			<p>When fighting defensively with at least one hand free, you gain a +4 dodge bonus to AC against melee attacks. If a melee attack misses you by 4 or less, you lose this dodge bonus until the beginning of your next turn. If you are using the total defense action instead, you can deflect one melee attack that would normally hit you. An attack so deflected deals no damage and has no other effect (instead treat it as a miss). You do not expend an action when using this feat, but you must be aware of the attack and not flat-footed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cranial Adjustment" title="Cranial Adjustment" groups="" description="You have learned to manually adjust the plates that make up the skull, inducing altered states in your subjects.">
		<Prerequisites>Deft Hands or Trepanation.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can perform the hypnotism occult skill unlock even if you can&apos;t use psychic magic. If you can cast psychic spells or have the Psychic Sensitivity feat, you can use hypnotism one additional time per day.</p>
			<p>You can use the Sleight of Hand skill in place of Diplomacy to hypnotize a subject, but doing so requires 10 minutes of contact with the target&apos;s skull. You can perform an adjustment that takes 1 hour to access the deeper recesses of a target&apos;s emotional mind, either granting the target a +2 bonus or imposing a &#x2013;2 penalty on the target&apos;s saving throws against mind-affecting emotion effects for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cranial Implantation" title="Cranial Implantation" groups="" description="You turn the science of phrenology inward, driving needles and nails into your or another's brain to grant focus through the pathways of pain.">
		<Prerequisites>Self-Sufficient or Trepanation, Heal 7 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can perform the phrenology occult skill unlock, though you must use needles or similar sharp implements rather than your fingertips, dealing 1d3 points of damage to the subject. If you can cast psychic spells or have the Psychic Sensitivity feat, you can use phrenology one additional time per day.</p>
			<p>In addition, you can insert needles into a creature&apos;s brain to help center its thoughts and emotions. Doing so requires a successful Heal check (DC = 25 + the target&apos;s Hit Dice). Creatures with implanted needles gain a +1 bonus on saving throws against spells with the emotion or fear descriptor (or similar effects), but take a &#x2013;1 penalty on saving throws against spells with the electricity or pain descriptors. Implanting needles deals 1d6 points of damage to the patient, which can&apos;t be healed by any means until the needles are removed (which requires a second successful Heal check at the same DC, or a restoration or regenerate spell).</p>
			<p>If you have implanted needles into your own cranium, you can probe them as a swift action while casting a spell, dealing an amount of damage to yourself equal to 1 + the spell&apos;s level.</p>
			<p>The pain from this probing stimulates your powers of focus, granting you a bonus of +1d6 on any concentration check you must attempt as part of casting that spell. This damage doesn&apos;t force you to attempt a concentration check.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crashing Wave Buffet" title="Crashing Wave Buffet" groups="Combat" description="You disorient your opponents by pushing and pounding them mercilessly, just like how the sea beats relentlessly against the rocks.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 15, Crashing Wave Style, Improved Drag, Improved Reposition, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When dragging or repositioning an opponent, you use your full body to knock your opponent around like a constant wave. At the end of the drag or reposition maneuver, your opponent must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + half your character level + your Wisdom modifier + 2 for every 5 feet you drag or reposition your opponent). On a failed save, your opponent becomes disorientated from the movement and takes a -2 penalty on attack rolls, combat maneuver checks, and Dexterity-based skill checks until the end of its next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crashing Wave Fist" title="Crashing Wave Fist" groups="Combat" description="In addition to simply moving it, you are able to strike your enemy while pushing it around.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 15, Crashing Wave Buffet, Crashing Wave Style, Improved Drag, Improved Reposition, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When dragging or repositioning an opponent, at any point during the movement, you can make one unarmed attack against the opponent using your highest attack bonus. You can make one additional attack for every 5 feet you drag or reposition the opponent beyond the first 5 feet. You take a cumulative -5 penalty on each additional attack made in this way.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crashing Wave Style" title="Crashing Wave Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You relentlessly push your enemies around, as the sea moves those within and upon it against their will.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Improved Drag, Improved Reposition, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully drag or reposition an opponent while using this style, at any point during the dragging or repositioning of the opponent, you can move 5 feet as an immediate action, including moving into a square previously occupied by the opponent, even if you have already taken a move action this round. This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Create Enhanced Firearm" title="Create Enhanced Firearm" groups="" description="You can craft superior firearms.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft Magic Arms and Armor; Craft (weapons) 1 rank or Gunsmithing.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you craft a firearm or magical firearm, you can use reinforced components to make the weapon more reliable. This increases the item&apos;s total construction cost by 10%. The misfire chance of the weapon is reduced by 1. This can never reduce a firearm&apos;s misfire chance by more than 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Create Reliquary Arms and Shields" title="Create Reliquary Arms and Shields" groups="" description="Your magical creations are infused with divine power.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft Magic Arms and Armor, ability to cast consecrate or desecrate.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you craft a magic weapon, magic armor, or magic shield, you may add one casting of consecrate or desecrate as part of the item crafting process. This increases the item&apos;s price by 250 gp.</p>
			<p>The item becomes a reliquary and can be used as a holy (or unholy) symbol divine focus of your deity. If you cast consecrate or desecrate, your reliquary counts as a permanent fixture for that spell while it remains in the spell&apos;s area.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Create Sanguine Elixir" title="Create Sanguine Elixir" groups="" description="You can condense a fraction of your bloodline's power into a powerful elixir.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 15, Brew Potion, Craft (alchemy) 12 ranks, sorcerer level 3rd. </Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, when you clear your mind to regain spell slots, you can create a sanguine elixir. When you do, pick one of your bloodline powers. You transfer that power into a small potion that any creature can drink to temporarily gain the benefit of your bloodline power. Creating a sanguine elixir takes 1 hour, and requires special oils and distillates worth 100 gp, and when you make the sanguine elixir, you lose access to the bloodline power until the next time you clear your mind to regain spell slots. When a creature drinks a sanguine elixir, it can activate the bloodline power anytime before the end of its next turn, as if it had access to that bloodline power. A creature that drinks the elixir cannot gain the benefit if its character level does not equal or exceed the minimum level of the bloodline power. Any level-dependent effects use the character level of the creature that drinks the sanguine elixir, or your sorcerer level, whichever is lower. Drinking a sanguine elixir is just like drinking a potion. A sanguine elixir is treated as a magic item with your caster level.</p>
			<p>Sanguine elixirs are extremely unstable. They lose their potency 1 day after they are created.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Creative Armorsmith" title="Creative Armorsmith" groups="Combat" description="You can temporarily customize your own armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (armor) 3 ranks, Knowledge (engineering) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With an hour of work, you can temporarily add an armor modification of your choice to your armor, or temporarily remove an existing modification, at no cost. You must have access to masterwork artisan&apos;s tools designed for armorsmithing to perform this alteration. This alteration lasts for 8 hours. Armor modifications you add this way only provide their benefits to you; any other wearer suffers the modification&apos;s drawbacks but does not gain its benefits.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Creative Weaponsmith" title="Creative Weaponsmith" groups="Combat" description="You can temporarily customize your own weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (weapons) 3 ranks, Knowledge (engineering) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With an hour of work, you can temporarily add a weapon modification of your choice to your weapon (or temporarily remove an existing modification) at no cost. You must have access to masterwork artisan&apos;s tools designed for weaponsmithing to perform this alteration. This alteration lasts for 8 hours. Weapon modifications you add this way only provide their benefits to you; any other wielder treats the weapon as one category more difficult to use than normal, but does not gain its benefits.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crescent Blade Dervish" title="Crescent Blade Dervish" groups="Combat" description="In the thick of battle, your crescent blades spin in arcs of glittering death, striking faster than the eye can follow.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Int 13, Combat Expertise, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (crescent blade), base attack bonus +2.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you wield a crescent blade and you threaten three or more opponents, you gain one additional attack at your highest base attack bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can use Crescent Blade Dervish in conjunction with the Whirlwind Attack feat. In such a case, you can attack every foe you threaten, plus an additional foe of your choosing a second time.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crescent Blade Master" title="Crescent Blade Master" groups="Combat" description="You have perfected the use of crescent blades, gaining a deadly control to which few have ever aspired.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Int 13, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (crescent blade).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You do not take a penalty on attack rolls when wielding a crescent blade. Additionally, you treat crescent blades as if they had the disarm and trip qualities. (See page 20 for details on crescent blades.)</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Crescent blades impose a -2 penalty on attack rolls.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Criminal Reputation" title="Criminal Reputation" groups="" description="Your acts of audacious larceny have endeared you to the criminal underworld.">
		<Prerequisites>Diplomacy 5 ranks, Intimidate 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Diplomacy and Intimidate checks when interacting with criminals, whether they&apos;re individual thieves and cutpurses or criminal organizations.</p>
			<p>If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
			<p>These bonuses do not stack with those granted by Persuasive, but this feat counts as Persuasive for the purposes of feats and other rules elements with Persuasive as a prerequisite.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crippling Critical" title="Crippling Critical" groups="Combat" description="You are able to maim a target and hinder its movement.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit against an opponent, its speed is halved for 1 minute. A successful Fortitude save reduces this duration to 1d4 rounds. The DC of this save is equal to 10 + your base attack bonus. Against creatures with multiple types of movement, you must choose which movement type to affect. A flying creature hit by this attack must make a DC 10 Fly check to remain airborne, and has its maneuverability reduced by one step.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crippling Thrust" title="Crippling Thrust" groups="Combat" description="With one precise stab, you hamper movement.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with piercing weapon, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, make a single attack with your chosen weapon. If the attack hits, the target&apos;s movement speed is halved until the start of your next turn. When your base attack bonus reaches +11, the target&apos;s movement is so hampered that even a 5-foot step provokes an attack of opportunity. When your base attack bonus reaches +16, the target must also succeed at a Reflex save with a DC equal to 10 + your base attack bonus or become entangled. An entangled creature&apos;s movement can be halved only once. You can use this feat&apos;s benefits only once per minute.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Critical Conduit" title="Critical Conduit" groups="" description="You are deadly when delivering your master's magic.">
		<Prerequisites>Deliver touch spells ability, familiar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When delivering a touch spell for your master, the critical threat range of your touch attack is doubled. This feat does not stack with Improved Critical or other effects that increase critical threat range.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Feats that are meant for familiars can be switched out for a familiar&apos;s default feats (as listed in the familiar&apos;s statistics) if the familiar meets the prerequisites. Such feat replacements must be made when the PC first acquires a new familiar, and like all new feats from supplemental sources the new feats should be approved by the GM before being integrated into play.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Critical Focus" title="Critical Focus" groups="Combat" description="You are trained in the art of causing pain.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +4 circumstance bonus on attack rolls made to confirm critical hits</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Critical Mastery" title="Critical Mastery" groups="Combat,Critical" description="Your critical hits cause two additional effects.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, any two critical feats, 14th-level fighter.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you score a critical hit, you can apply the effects of two critical feats in addition to the damage dealt.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit in addition to the damage dealt.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Critical Versatility" title="Critical Versatility" groups="Combat,Human" description="An open mind and combat training grant versatility to your critical hits.">
		<Prerequisites>Fighter level 11th, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can spend 1 hour practicing maneuvers to gain one single critical feat that you meet the prerequisites for. You gain the benefits of the chosen critical feat until you choose to practice a different critical feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crossbow Mastery" title="Crossbow Mastery" groups="Combat" description="You can load crossbows with blinding speed and even fire them in melee with little fear of reprisal.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Point-Blank Shot, Rapid Reload, Rapid Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The time required for you to reload any type of crossbow is reduced to a free action, regardless of the type of crossbow used. You can fire a crossbow as many times in a full attack action as you could attack if you were using a bow. Reloading a crossbow for the type of crossbow you chose when you took Rapid Reload no longer provokes attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, a ranger with the archery combat style may select Crossbow Mastery as a combat style feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crowd Control" title="Crowd Control" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You and your allies have been trained to prevent enemies from moving around or through your formation.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 competence bonus to your CMD when an enemy uses Acrobatics to move through a square you threaten. For each ally within your reach that also has this feat, the bonus increases by an additional 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crowd of Bullies" title="Crowd of Bullies" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="Your failed attempt to humiliate a foe reveals its weaknesses to your allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you fail a combat maneuver check, your allies within 30 feet who also have this feat gain a +2 circumstance bonus on combat maneuver checks of the same type against the same foe for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crusader's Fist" title="Crusader's Fist" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Lay on hands class feature or touch of corruption class feature, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you attack with an unarmed strike and hit a creature that you can harm with your lay on hands or touch of corruption feature, you can use a swift action to expend a daily use of that feature to deal its normal damage as if you had hit with the feature&apos;s normal touch attack. This extra damage is not multiplied if you scored a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crusader's Flurry" title="Crusader's Flurry" groups="" description="You learned to use your deity's favored weapon as part of your martial arts form.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel energy class feature, flurry of blows class feature, Weapon Focus with your deity&apos;s favored melee weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use your deity&apos;s favored weapon as if it were a monk weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crushing Blow" title="Crushing Blow" groups="Combat" description="Your focus allows you to smash your enemy's defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Stunning Fist.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can make a Stunning Fist attempt as a full-round action. If successful, instead of stunning your target, you reduce the target&apos;s AC by an amount equal to your Wisdom modifier for 1 minute. This penalty does not stack with other penalties applied due to Crushing Blow.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crushing Impact" title="Crushing Impact" groups="Combat" description="You slam into your foes with brute strength as unyielding as a wall.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Bull Rush, Improved Unarmed Strike, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you successfully bull rush an enemy and its movement is stopped by a solid object or barrier, you deal your unarmed strike damage to the foe, as long as it&apos;s within your threatened area. If you performed your bull rush as part of a charge, you gain a +2 bonus on your damage roll.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Crypt Spell" title="Crypt Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can infuse your magic with the power of the crypts, sending foes to face ineluctable judgment.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can enhance any spell that inflicts hit point damage to become a crypt spell. A creature that dies within 1 round of being damaged by a crypt spell is considered to have been killed by a death effect for the purpose of being returned to life. An undead creature damaged by a crypt spell gains the sickened condition for a number of rounds equal to the spell&apos;s original spell level; this duration is halved if the undead creature succeeds at its saving throw against the spell. If the spell does not allow a save, the target can attempt a Will save to negate the sickened effect. A crypt spell gains the death descriptor.</p>
			<p>A crypt spell uses a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s normal spell level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cudgeler Style" title="Cudgeler Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You have learned how to rush your foe and deliver an incapacitating blow.">
		<Prerequisites>Bludgeoner.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you hit with a charge attack to deal nonlethal damage while using this style, your weapon deals damage as if it were one size category larger than it actually is. If you have the ability to make more than one attack on a charge, this increase applies only to your first attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cudgeler Sweep" title="Cudgeler Sweep" groups="Combat" description="Your powerful blows can knock down your opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Bludgeoner, Cudgeler Style, base attack bonus +5 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you hit with a charge attack using the Cudgeler Style feat, you can immediately attempt a single trip combat maneuver check against the target with a +2 competence bonus as a free action. This provokes an attack of opportunity as normal for a trip combat maneuver.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cudgeler Takedown" title="Cudgeler Takedown" groups="Combat" description="Opponents you batter to the ground stay down.">
		<Prerequisites>Bludgeoner, Cudgeler Style, Cudgeler Sweep, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you hit with a charge attack using the Cudgeler Style feat, your weapon deals damage as though it were one size category larger for 1 round or until it leaves your hand. When you successfully trip an opponent with the Cudgeler Sweep feat, your opponent must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + your character level + your Strength modifier) or be stunned for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cultivate Magic Plants" title="Cultivate Magic Plants" groups="Item Creation" description="You combine a natural green thumb and knowledge of magic in order to grow magic plants.">
		<Prerequisites>Brew Potion, Craft Wondrous Item; Knowledge (nature) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cultivate magic plants. Cultivating a magic plant takes 1 week per 1,000 gp in its base price.</p>
			<p>When you create a magic plant, you make the same choices that you would normally make when casting the spell. Whoever consumes the fruit of the magic plant is the target of the spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cunning Intuition" title="Cunning Intuition" groups="Combat" description="You can read your foe's body language to gauge your foe and gain an edge in combat.">
		<Prerequisites>Alertness, Improved Initiative, Lightning Reflexes, Quick Draw, Ready for Anything, base attack bonus +13 or rogue level 13th, Sense Motive 13 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you ready an action, you do not need to declare what action you will take, only the trigger for that action and an action type (either standard, move, swift, or free). If you choose the standard action type, you can take a move action instead when your readied action triggers.</p>
			<p>When the condition triggers, you can choose a specific action of the appropriate type to take.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Curative Mastery" title="Curative Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can invoke a magic item's innate conjuration magic to conjure positive energy for healing wounds.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 1 rank, base Fortitude bonus +2.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has a 1st-level or higher conjuration spell listed in its construction requirements to cast cure light wounds as a spell-like ability, using the item&apos;s caster level as the spell&apos;s caster level. You can use this feat once per day, plus one additional time per day when your base Fortitude save bonus reaches +4, +6, +8, +10, and +12.</p>
			<p>You can expend two uses of this feat to cast cure moderate wounds, three uses to cast cure serious wounds, four uses to cast cure critical wounds, and five uses to cast breath of life, provided that the item&apos;s construction requirements include a spell whose level is equal to or greater than the level of the spell-like ability to be used (2nd level for cure moderate wounds, 3rd level for cure serious wounds, 4th level for cure critical wounds, and 5th level for breath of life).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Curious Companion" title="Curious Companion" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="Heroes tend to pick up the oddest friendsbirds of the sky and beasts of the wood. Your companions are strange even by these standards.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can select a plant companion or vermin companion as your animal companion.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Curse Mastery" title="Curse Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can coax curses from necromantic magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude save bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has a necromancy spell of 3rd level or higher in its construction requirements to cast bestow curse.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day at base Fortitude save bonus +9 and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cutting Humiliation" title="Cutting Humiliation" groups="" description="You know how to cut a foe deeply with humiliation.">
		<Prerequisites>Persuasive, Intimidate 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully demoralize a target by using a verbal Intimidate check in a social situation (rather than an Intimidate check you can make via an ability such as Dazzling Display or Enforcer), you can instead humiliate the target, causing it to take a &#x2013;2 penalty on Charisma-based skill checks and Charisma ability checks for 1 hour + 1 additional hour for every 5 by which the result of your check exceeds the DC. The target can remove the effect early by taking 10 minutes to compose herself. If you fail this check, any creature who witnessed the failure is immune to your humiliation from this feat for 24 hours.</p>
			<p>If you fail by 5 or more, you become humiliated for 1 hour instead of your target.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cypher Magic" title="Cypher Magic" groups="" description="Your intimacy with runes and the mysteries of ancient arcana has taught you secret ways to draw greater power from magical writings. The Cyphermages initially devised these unusual methods, but they have since spread far and wide.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 15, Scribe Scroll.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You cast spells from scrolls at 1 caster level higher than the scroll&apos;s caster level. In addition, you gain a +2 bonus on caster level checks to activate a scroll with a higher caster level than your own.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Cypher Script" title="Cypher Script" groups="" description="Through researching lengthy, ancient, arcane scripts salvaged from ruins, you have discovered a more efficient method of recording spells.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (arcana) 1 rank, Linguistics 1 rank, Spellcraft 1 rank, spellbook class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Any spell you scribe in your spellbook costs half as much as normal and takes up only half the room it normally would (round all fractions up). It takes you only 10 minutes per spell level to scribe a spell into your spellbook (5 minutes for cantrips).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dance of Chains" title="Dance of Chains" groups="Combat" description="In your hands, a spiked chain dances like a living thing.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Chain Mastery, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (spiked chain), Weapon Finesse, Perform (dance) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a spiked chain one-handed, you can add your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier to that weapon&apos;s damage. The spiked chain must be one appropriate for your size. During your turn, you treat your reach with the spiked chain as 5 feet greater. You lose these benefits while fighting with multiple weapons or when using a shield (but not when using a buckler).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dangerous Tail" title="Dangerous Tail" groups="Combat" description="You have trained your tail into a powerful weapon, and wield it with deadly skill.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +5, Lizardfolk.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a tail swipe attack. If used as part of a full-attack action, the attack is made at your full base attack bonus - 5. If the tail swipe hits, it deals 1d4 points of damage (assuming you are Medium) + 1/2 your Strength modifier. If you confirm a critical hit against a target with your tail swipe, as a free action you can attempt a trip combat maneuver against that target.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dark Adept" title="Dark Adept" groups="" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Drow, character level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain three new spell-like abilities, each usable once per day. These spell-like abilities are detect magic, feather fall, and levitate. Your caster level for these spell-like abilities equals your total character level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dark Sight" title="Dark Sight" groups="Fetchling" description="With further modification, your eyes can pierce the gloom of even magical darkness.">
		<Prerequisites>Gloom Sight, fetchling</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the ability to see up to 15 feet clearly in magical darkness, such as that created by the deeper darkness spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Darkness Trick" title="Darkness Trick" groups="" description="You can manipulate the luminescence of magic weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 5 ranks, ability to cast darkness.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a magic weapon that sheds light or that features a luminescent quality, such as a flaming or brilliant energy weapon, you can deactivate that illumination as a swift action. You can reignite the illumination at any time as a free action. Any intrinsic magic properties that would force the weapon to shed light, such as the extra damage of a flaming weapon, do not function while the illumination is deactivated, and the &#x201C;significant portion&#x201D; of a brilliant energy weapon that is normally made of light ceases to exist.</p>
			<p>If a weapon affected by this ability ever leaves your possession (for instance, if you drop the weapon or pass it to another creature), its illumination and related abilities instantly return.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Darting Retrieval" title="Darting Retrieval" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="As your ally disarms a foe, you knock the disarmed item out of the way.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Disarm.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When an ally who also has this feat disarms an opponent and the disarmed item lands within your melee reach, as an immediate action you can move the disarmed item to another square within your melee reach. If you have at least one hand free and could carry the disarmed item, you can instead pick it up. Using this feat does not provoke an attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Darting Viper" title="Darting Viper" groups="Combat" description="When using a dorn-dergar, you can quickly attack both near and distant foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +4, proficiency with the dwarven dorn-dergar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can change whether you&apos;re using the dorn-dergar as a normal or reach weapon as a swift action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Changing whether a dorn-dergar is a normal or reach weapon is a move action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dastardly Finish" title="Dastardly Finish" groups="Combat" description="You can take advantage of an enemy's debilitated state to attempt a coup de grace.">
		<Prerequisites>Sneak attack +5d6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can deliver a coup de grace to cowering or stunned targets.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only coup de grace helpless targets.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dauntless Destiny" title="Dauntless Destiny" groups="Human" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Fearless Curiosity, Intimidate 10 ranks, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on saving throws against effects with the emotion descriptor; this bonus stacks with those granted by Fearless Curiosity and Intimidating Confidence. In addition, once per day you may reroll a natural 1 on a saving throw or an attack roll. If your reroll results in a successful saving throw or attack roll, as a free action you can make an Intimidate check to demoralize the target of your attack or the creature that forced you to make a saving throw, as long as the creature is within 30 feet and can see and hear you. This effect does not apply on saving throws against traps or other objects. This does not stack with other effects that allow you to reroll a saving throw or an attack roll. You may only make one reroll.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazing Assault" title="Dazing Assault" groups="Combat" description="You can daze foes with wild attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose to take a -5 penalty on all melee attack rolls and combat maneuver checks to daze opponents you hit with your melee attacks for 1 round, in addition to the normal damage dealt by the attack. A successful Fortitude save negates the effect. The DC of this save is 10 + your base attack bonus. You must choose to use this feat before making the attack roll, and its effects last until your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazing Fist" title="Dazing Fist" groups="Combat" description="You know just where to strike to daze your foe.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You must declare that you are using this feat before you make your attack roll (thus, a failed attack roll ruins the attempt). Dazing Fist forces a foe damaged by your unarmed attack to attempt a Fortitude saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier), in addition to dealing damage normally. A foe who fails this saving throw is dazed for 1 round, until just before your next turn. You can attempt to use Dazing Fist once per day for every 4 character levels you have, but no more than once per round. Constructs, incorporeal creatures, plants, undead, and creatures that are immune to critical hits cannot be affected by this ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazing Spell" title="Dazing Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can daze creatures with the power of your spells.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can modify a spell to daze a creature damaged by the spell. When a creature takes damage from this spell, they become dazed for a number of rounds equal to the original level of the spell. If the spell allows a saving throw, a successful save negates the daze effect. If the spell does not allow a save, the target can make a Will save to negate the daze effect. If the spell effect also causes the creature to become dazed, the duration of this metamagic effect is added to the duration of the spell.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +3 (a dazing spell uses up a spell slot three levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.Spells that do not inflict damage do not benefit from this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazzling Display" title="Dazzling Display" groups="Combat" description="Your skill with your favored weapon can frighten enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus, proficiency with the selected weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While wielding the weapon in which you have Weapon Focus, you can perform a bewildering show of prowess as a full-round action. Make an Intimidate check to demoralize all foes within 30 feet who can see your display.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadeye's Blessing Combat" title="Deadeye's Blessing Combat" groups="Combat" description="Your deity grants you prowess with a bow that far exceeds your own physical capabilities.">
Note This is associated with a specific deity.
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus (longbow), must be a worshiper of the associated deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use your Wisdom modifier instead of your Dexterity modifier on ranged attack rolls when using a bow.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadhand Initiate" title="Deadhand Initiate" groups="Combat" description="Your adulation of death not only shields you from your fears, it allows you to feed on them.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 19, Deadhand Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Knowledge (religion) 6 ranks, ki pool class feature, nongood alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Deadhand Style, as long as you have at least 1 point in your ki pool, your bonus on saving throws against fear effects increases to +4, and the DC of Intimidate checks attempted against you increases by 8.</p>
			<p>Additionally, if an enemy targets you with a fear effect, you can spend 1 point from your ki pool as an immediate action to gain a number of temporary hit points equal to twice your Hit Dice.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadhand Master" title="Deadhand Master" groups="Combat" description="Your death-infused punch drains life force from your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 23, Deadhand Initiate, Deadhand Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Knowledge (religion) 14 ranks, ki pool class feature, nongood alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Deadhand Style, when you damage a living creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 2 points from your ki pool as a swift action to inflict 2 temporary negative levels on your enemy with no saving throw. Effects that reduce the ki cost also reduce the number of negative levels you inflict on your foe, but effects that increase the ki cost do not increase the number of negative levels you inflict. As long as the foe is affected by the temporary negative levels, you can&apos;t recover the ki points you spent, effectively reducing the size of your ki pool. The Fortitude save DC to remove the negative levels and prevent them from becoming permanent is equal to 10 + 1/2 your Hit Dice + your Wisdom modifier. Once the negative levels become permanent or the foe removes them, you can recover your spent ki points. If the foe dies before either happens, you can recover the spent ki after 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadhand Style" title="Deadhand Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your study of death allow you to exploit your foes' fears.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 15, Improved Unarmed Strike, Knowledge (religion) 4 ranks, ki pool class feature, nongood alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, if you have at least 1 point in your ki pool, you gain a +2 bonus on saves against fear effects, and the DC of Intimidate checks against you increases by 4. As a swift action, you can spend 1 point from your ki pool to empower your unarmed strikes. Creatures hit with your unarmed strikes must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier) or become shaken for a number of rounds equal to your Wisdom modifier. This is a mind-affecting fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Aim" title="Deadly Aim" groups="Combat" description="You can make exceptionally deadly ranged attacks by pinpointing a foe's weak spot, at the expense of making the attack less likely to succeed.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose to take a -1 penalty on all ranged attack rolls to gain a +2 bonus on all ranged damage rolls. When your base attack bonus reaches +4, and every +4 thereafter, the penalty increases by -1 and the bonus to damage increases by +2. You must choose to use this feat before making an attack roll and its effects last until your next turn. The bonus damage does not apply to touch attacks or effects that do not deal hit point damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Dealer" title="Deadly Dealer" groups="" description="Your skill with handling a deck and your arcane talents allow you to turn mundane cards into weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Strike, Sleight of Hand 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can throw a card as though it were a dart, with the same damage, range, and other features. You must use the Arcane Strike feat when throwing a card in this way, or else the card lacks the magical force and precision to deal lethal damage. A card is destroyed when thrown in this way.</p>
			<p>Harrow cards are treated as masterwork weapons when thrown using this feat, but are still destroyed after they are thrown. A harrow deck can no longer be used as a fortune-telling device after even a single card is thrown.</p>
			<p>A spellcaster with this feat can enhance a deck of cards as though it were a ranged weapon with 54 pieces of ammunition. This enhancement functions only when used in tandem with this feat, and has no affect on any other way the cards might be used.</p>
			<p>Only a character who possesses this feat can use an enhanced deck of cards; she must still use the Arcane Strike feat to activate the cards&apos; enhancement.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Finish" title="Deadly Finish" groups="Combat" description="Your attacks don't just fell your opponentsthey kill them outright.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you hit with a melee attack and reduce your opponent to -1 or fewer hit points, you can force that opponent to succeed at a Fortitude save (DC 15 + the damage your attack dealt) or die.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Grappler" title="Deadly Grappler" groups="Combat" description="While you're grappled, you become even more dangerous.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You have learned to leverage a grappling creature&apos;s weight against it. While you&apos;re grappled, attacks you make against the grappler using armor spikes, a light or one-handed weapon, a natural weapon, or an unarmed strike deal damage as if the strike or weapon were one size category larger than it actually is.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Horns" title="Deadly Horns" groups="Combat" description="Many tieflings bear horns as an overt mark of their fiendish heritage; you have learned to use yours as a weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a gore natural attack that deals 1d6 points of damage. Due to the awkwardness of attacking this way, you can&apos;t make a gore attack and other natural weapon attacks as part of the same full attack. Treat your gore attack as a secondary attack if you also attack with a manufactured weapon as part of a full attack in a round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Stroke" title="Deadly Stroke" groups="Combat" description="With a well-placed strike, you can bring a swift and painful end to most foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Greater Weapon Focus, Shatter Defenses, Weapon Focus, proficiency with the selected weapon, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, make a single attack with the weapon for which you have Greater Weapon Focus against a stunned or flat-footed opponent. If you hit, you deal double the normal damage and the target takes 1 point of Constitution bleed (see Conditions). The additional damage and bleed is not multiplied on a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Trap" title="Deadly Trap" groups="" description="Your traps are especially deadly, either through their increased accuracy or the viciousness of their blades and bludgeons.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (traps) 8 ranks, Survival 8 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you craft a trap that requires an attack roll to hit, you can either increase the threat multiplier of the trap by 1 (&#xD7;2 becomes &#xD7;3, and so on) or grant the trap&apos;s attack a +4 bonus to confirm a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Troupe" title="Deadly Troupe" groups="Teamwork" description="You combine elements of dance and acting with your combat style to distract your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Perform (act) or Perform (dance) 3 ranks, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When at least one ally who also has this feat is threatening a foe, you gain a +4 circumstance bonus against that foe on Bluff checks to feint, Bluff checks to create a diversion to hide, and Acrobatics checks to move through that foe&apos;s threatened squares. You also gain a +2 circumstance bonus on steal and dirty trick combat maneuver checks made against that foe.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deafening Critical" title="Deafening Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits cause enemies to lose their hearing.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit against an opponent, the victim is permanently deafened. A successful Fortitude save reduces the deafness to 1 round. The DC of this Fortitude save is equal to 10 + your base attack bonus. This feat has no effect on deaf creatures. This deafness can be cured by heal, regeneration, remove deafness, or a similar ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deafening Explosion" title="Deafening Explosion" groups="Hobgoblin" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Bomb class feature, Hobgoblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may reduce your bomb damage by one die to give it the ability to deafen the creature struck by it. The bomb must deal fire, force, or sonic damage. If a creature takes a direct hit from your bomb, it must make a saving throw against the bomb&apos;s DC or be deafened for 1 minute. This deafening is in addition to any other effects the bomb would normally have.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death From Below" title="Death From Below" groups="Combat" description="You have been trained to fight flying creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 circumstance bonus against flying opponents when you have set a weapon against a charge, or when you are allowed an attack of opportunity against the flying opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death Roll" title="Death Roll" groups="Combat" description="Like an alligator, you twist and wrench your foe, forcing him to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Bite attack, reptilian subtype.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When grappling a foe of your size or smaller, you can attempt to perform a death roll. Upon a successful grapple combat maneuver check to deal damage with your bite attack, you can immediately attempt a second grapple combat maneuver check as a free action. If successful, you knock the target prone. Upon knocking the target prone, you must either release the grapple or fall prone and maintain the grapple. This doesn&apos;t count as a combat maneuver check to maintain the grapple, and doesn&apos;t add any other effects (such as constrict) beyond knocking the target prone.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death from Above" title="Death from Above" groups="Combat" description="You allow gravity to add extra force to your charges.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you charge an opponent from higher ground, or from above while flying, you gain a +5 bonus on attack rolls in place of the bonuses from charging and being on higher ground.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death or Glory" title="Death or Glory" groups="Combat" description="Even when facing a larger foe, you aren't afraid to take great risks in order to finish the fight.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Against a creature of size Large or larger, you can make a single melee attack as a full-round action, gaining a +4 bonus on the attack roll, damage roll, and critical confirmation roll. You gain an additional +1 on this bonus at base attack bonus +11, +16, and +20 (for a maximum of +7 at base attack +20). After you resolve your attack, the opponent you attack can spend an immediate action to make a single melee attack against you with the same bonuses.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can combine the full-round action attack this feat allows with the benefit of Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, or Greater Vital Strike.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death's Host" title="Death's Host" groups="" description="You become harder to kill when possessed by the undead.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Focus (necromancy).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are possessed by an undead creature that you do not directly control, you gain a +4 bonus on saving throws against death effects. You don&apos;t fall unconscious at negative hit points, and if you or the undead possessing you is forced to attempt a saving throw to resist ending the possession effect, you or your possessor gains a +4 bonus on the saving throw.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deathless Initiate" title="Deathless Initiate" groups="Combat" description="For you, impending death is a call to wrath.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Con 13, orc or half-orc, Diehard, Endurance, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You are not staggered while using the Diehard feat, but if you take a move and a standard action or a full-round action while you are at 0 or fewer hit points you take 1 point of damage. Further, while using the Diehard feat, you gain a +2 bonus on melee attacks and damage rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deathless Master" title="Deathless Master" groups="Combat" description="Even if you suffer a grievous wound, you can shrug off the damage and continue your relentless assault.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Con 15, orc or half-orc, Deathless Initiate, Diehard, Endurance, Ironhide, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are at 0 or fewer hit points, you do not lose 1 hit point when you take an action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deathless Zealot" title="Deathless Zealot" groups="Combat" description="Only the most serious wounds can stop you.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Con 17, orc or half-orc, Deathless Initiate, Deathless Master, Diehard, Endurance, Ironhide, base attack bonus +12.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever a creature rolls to confirm a critical hit against you, it must roll twice and take the lowest result.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deceitful" title="Deceitful" groups="" description="You are skilled at deceiving others, both with the spoken word and with physical disguises.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on all Bluff and Disguise skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deceitful Incompetence" title="Deceitful Incompetence" groups="Combat" description="You learn from your mistakes rapidly when others lower their guard around you.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you make an attack of opportunity in a single round after you have already made an unsuccessful attack of opportunity that round, you gain a cumulative +2 insight bonus on your attack roll for each unsuccessful attack of opportunity. For example, if you have made one unsuccessful attack of opportunity and an enemy provokes another attack of opportunity from you during that same round, you gain a +2 insight bonus on that attack roll, and if you have made two unsuccessful attacks of opportunity in a round and an enemy provokes another attack of opportunity from you during that same round, you gain a +4 insight bonus on that attack roll, and so on.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deceptive Exchange" title="Deceptive Exchange" groups="" description="You trick an adversary into grabbing an object you hand them, even in the midst of combat.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Feint.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you successfully feint an opponent, you can trick that opponent into accepting a one-handed object you are holding instead of denying that opponent its Dexterity bonus to AC against your next attack. The opponent must have appendages capable of holding the object you offer, and it must have one such appendage free to take the object.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>An alchemist who has the delayed bomb alchemist discovery can use this feat to hand an enemy a delayed bomb. Such a delayed bomb detonates at the end of the alchemist&apos;s turn. If the bomb is in a creature&apos;s square at the end of the alchemist&apos;s turn, the bomb deals that creature a direct hit.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dedicated Adversary" title="Dedicated Adversary" groups="Combat" description="Your repeated encounters with a particular type of enemy have honed your skills against that foe.">
		<Prerequisites>No levels in a class that has the favored enemy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you select this feat, choose a specific kind of creature, such as wolf, frost giant, goblin, or babau demon. You gain the ranger&apos;s favored enemy class ability against this particular type of creature with a bonus of +2.</p>
			<p>This feat does not grant the favored enemy class feature for the purposes of prerequisites. If you later gain the favored enemy class feature, you can replace this feat with a feat for which you qualify and whose prerequisites include the favored enemy class feature.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a different creature.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deep Diver" title="Deep Diver" groups="" description="You are accustomed to diving deeper than most would dare swim and can do so with less risk of drowning than even other experienced swimmers.">
		<Prerequisites>Endurance.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 bonus on Acrobatics checks to reduce falling damage when diving into water and on Perception checks in dim light or darkness underwater. When attempting a Swim check to swim downward (at least 45 degrees down from the horizontal), on a successful check you can swim half your speed as a move action, or your speed as a full-round action. If you have a swim speed, it increases by 10 feet when you spend a move action to swim only downward.</p>
			<p>In addition, you can hold your breath for a number of rounds equal to three times your Constitution score, and you gain a +4 bonus on Constitution checks to continue holding your breath after this time and to resist the effects of the cold environment underwater. Pressure damage you take from deep water is halved.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deep Drinker" title="Deep Drinker" groups="" description="You draw greater amounts of ki from your libations.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, monk level 11, drunken ki class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you gain temporary ki from drunken ki, you gain 2 temporary ki rather than just 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deepsight" title="Deepsight" groups="" description="Your senses are especially keen in the utter darkness.">
		<Prerequisites>Darkvision 60 feet.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your darkvision has a range of 120 feet.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Darkvision normally extends 60 or 90 feet.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Defending Eidolon" title="Defending Eidolon" groups="" description="You have trained your eidolon to protect you.">
		<Prerequisites>Shield ally feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are adjacent to your eidolon, you can choose for the eidolon to take a &#x2013;1 penalty on melee attack rolls and combat maneuver checks to gain a +1 dodge bonus to your Armor Class. When your eidolon&apos;s base attack bonus reaches +5, and for every +5 thereafter, the penalty increases by &#x2013;1 and the dodge bonus increases by +1. You must choose to use this feat when your eidolon is making an attack or full-attack action with melee or natural weapons, and its effect lasts until your eidolon&apos;s next turn, or until you are no longer adjacent to the eidolon, whichever occurs first.</p>
			<p>PRG:UM </p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Defensive Combat Training" title="Defensive Combat Training" groups="Combat" description="You excel at defending yourself from all manner of combat maneuvers.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat your total Hit Dice as your base attack bonus when calculating your Combat Maneuver Defense (see Combat).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Defensive Weapon Training" title="Defensive Weapon Training" groups="Combat" description="You know how to defend yourself against a certain class of weaponry.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a weapon group from the fighter&apos;s weapon training class ability list (except natural weapons). You gain a +2 dodge bonus on AC when an opponent attacks you using a weapon from that group. If you also have the weapon training class feature in the selected group, your dodge bonus from this feat increases to +3.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can select this feat more than once. Its effects do not stack. Each time you select this feat, it applies to a different weapon group.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Defiant Luck" title="Defiant Luck" groups="Human" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, after you roll a natural 1 on a saving throw or a critical hit is confirmed against you, you can either reroll that saving throw, or force the creature that confirmed the critical hit against you to reroll the critical confirmation roll. This does not stack with other effects that allow you to reroll a saving throw or an attack roll. You may only make one reroll.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are using the optional hero point system, you can also spend 1 hero point when a critical hit is confirmed against you to have the opponent reroll the critical hit confirmation roll.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deflect Arrows" title="Deflect Arrows" groups="Combat" description="You can knock arrows and other projectiles off course, preventing them from hitting you.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You must have at least one hand free (holding nothing) to use this feat. Once per round when you would normally be hit with an attack from a ranged weapon, you may deflect it so that you take no damage from it. You must be aware of the attack and not flat-footed. Attempting to deflect a ranged attack doesn&apos;t count as an action. Unusually massive ranged weapons (such as boulders or ballista bolts) and ranged attacks generated by natural attacks or spell effects can&apos;t be deflected.</p>
			<p>Editor&apos;s Note</p>
			<p>Does an attack that is &apos;deflected&apos; count as a miss?</p>
			<p>It depends on the ability that is deflecting the attack.</p>
			<p>For example, the Deflect Arrows feat says, &apos;Once per round when you would normally be hit with an attack from a ranged weapon, you may deflect it so that you take no damage from it.&apos; It doesn&apos;t say the attack is a miss or is treated as a miss&#x2014;instead, you take no damage from the attack. Because it is not a miss, effects that would trigger on a miss (such as Efreeti Style or Snake Fang) are not triggered.</p>
			<p>Likewise, the Crane Wing feat uses similar language and does not say the deflected attack is a miss or treated as a miss.</p>
			<p>Note that the Snatch Arrows feat counts as a deflected attack&#x2014;you do not take damage if you choose to catch the weapons instead of just deflecting it, and catching the weapon does not mean the attack was a miss.</p>
			<p>Update: If the attack is deflected, not only does the target take no damage, but any other effects (ability drain, negative levels, harmful conditions, and so on) associated with that attack do not occur. If the deflected attack is a touch spell or other effect that requires &apos;holding the charge,&apos; the charge is not expended. For example, if a ghoul&apos;s claw attack is deflected, the target is not subject to the ghoul&apos;s paralysis ability from the attack. If a shocking grasp touch attack is deflected, the attacker is still &apos;holding the charge.&apos;</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
			<p>How does Deflect Arrows work with Manyshot?</p>
			<p>Deflect Arrows works only once per round. Manyshot allows an archer to shoot multiple arrows, but you only make one attack roll, so Deflect Arrows would block all arrows grouped in anyone particular Manyshot attack.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deft Catcher" title="Deft Catcher" groups="" description="You possess a preternatural skill for catching items that slip from your grasp.">
		<Prerequisites>Skill Focus (Sleight of Hand).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you drop or are forced to drop an item you possess (other than by an effect that disarms or steals the item), you can attempt a DC 20 Sleight of Hand check as an immediate action to catch the item before it falls away. If you are targeted by an effect that would disarm or steal an item you&apos;re holding, such as a disarm or steal combat maneuver or the effects of a spell like telekinesis, you can also attempt a Sleight of Hand check as an immediate action to maintain possession of the errant item (DC = 10 + the combat maneuver check result if there was a combat maneuver check, or 20 + the DC of the spell if there was no combat maneuver check). In either case, if you fail the Sleight of Hand check by 10 or more, you fall prone.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deft Hands" title="Deft Hands" groups="" description="You have exceptional manual dexterity.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on Disable Device and Sleight of Hand skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deft Shootist Deed" title="Deft Shootist Deed" groups="Grit" description="You keep an eye out while focusing on your weapon, allowing you to avoid attacks while shooting and reloading firearms.">
		<Prerequisites>Grit class feature or Amateur Gunslinger feat, Dodge, Mobility.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you have at least 1 grit point, you do not provoke attacks of opportunity when shooting or reloading a firearm.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deific Obedience" title="Deific Obedience" groups="" description="Your reverence for a deity is so great that daily prayer and minor sacrifices grant you special boons.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (religion) 3 ranks, must worship a deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Each deity requires a different daily obedience, but all obediences take no more than 1 hour per day to perform. Once you&apos;ve performed the obedience, you gain the benefit of a special ability or resistance as indicated in the Obedience entry for the god to whom you performed the obedience.</p>
			<p>If you have at least 12 Hit Dice, you also gain the first boon granted by your deity upon undertaking your obedience. If you have at least 16 Hit Dice, you also gain the second boon. If you have 20 Hit Dice or more, you also gain the third boon. Unless a specific duration or number of uses per day is listed, a boon&apos;s effects are constant.</p>
			<p>If you have levels in the evangelist, exalted, or sentinel prestige classes, you gain access to these boons at lower levels as a benefit of your prestige class. If you have no levels in one of these prestige classes, you gain the boons marked as exalted boons. If you later take levels in sentinel or evangelist, you lose access to the exalted boons and gain access to the new boons appropriate to your class.</p>
			<p>If you ever fail to perform a daily obedience, you lose all access to the benefits and boons granted by this feat until you next perform the obedience.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Delay Blast" title="Delay Blast" groups="" description="You can delay your kinetic blasts.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +3, kinetic blast class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use a kinetic blast, you can specify a number of rounds between 1 and 5. When that number of rounds has passed, the kinetic blast takes effect at the beginning of your turn. In the interim, you can take a standard action that provokes attacks of opportunity to cause the blast to take effect earlier than you initially selected. If you delay another blast while you already have a delayed blast pending, the previous delayed blast dissipates harmlessly.</p>
			<p>You must make any decisions you would make about the delayed blast&#x2014;including designating target positions, choosing infusions, and determining or shaping the area&#x2014;when you first use the blast. The blast originates from your position at the time you used the blast, not your current position when the blast takes effect, and it targets the position or area you had specified (which may or may not include any targets). A delayed blast radiates an aura of magic appropriate for its spell level even while it is delayed, and during that time, it can be dispelled by dispel magic.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Delayed Spell" title="Delayed Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can set a spell to trigger on a delay.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>A delayed spell can be activated as a standard action anytime within 1 minute per spell level of being cast. Only spells that target one or more squares or grid intersections can be affected by Delayed Spell, and the target (as well as any other variables determined at the time of casting) cannot be changed once the delayed spell is cast. You can have as many delayed spells as you wish at any given time, but only one spell can be triggered in a single standard action. Though a delayed spell does not manifest until it is triggered, it emits a magical aura as normal and can be identified with Knowledge (arcana) as a spell effect in place.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a delayed spell uses up a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demon Hunter" title="Demon Hunter" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (planes) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Knowledge (planes) checks to know the powers and abilities of demons. You gain a +2 morale bonus on all attack rolls and a +2 morale bonus on caster level checks to penetrate spell resistance made against creatures with the demon subtype you recognize as demons.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When you successfully identify a demon using Knowledge (planes), you can spend up to 9 stamina points to increase the morale bonus on attack rolls and caster level checks from Demon Hunter by 1 per 3 stamina points spent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Momentum" title="Demonic Momentum" groups="Combat" description="You slam into foes with devastating force, leaving them vulnerable to your vicious strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Demonic Style, Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Demonic Style, when you successfully bull rush an opponent as part of a charge, you gain a +2 bonus on melee weapon damage rolls against that opponent for every 5 feet it was moved by your bull rush.</p>
			<p>This bonus lasts until the end of your next turn, and it stacks with the damage bonus granted by Demonic Style.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Nemesis" title="Demonic Nemesis" groups="Combat" description="You are well acquainted with the machinations of a particular demon lord. You're resistant to his tricks, and have no fear of his minions.">
		<Prerequisites>Demon Hunter, Knowledge (planes) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you take this feat, choose a demon lord. When fighting followers of that demon lord, including cultists or demons, you gain a +2 bonus on damage rolls and rolls to confirm critical hits against these creatures.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat more than once. Each time you do, you must choose a new demon lord.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Obedience" title="Demonic Obedience" groups="" description="You physically defile yourself, others, or holy objects in order to prove your blasphemous devotion to a demon lord and gain special boons.">
		<Prerequisites>3 ranks in Knowledge (planes), must worship a demon lord.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Each demon lord requires a different obedience, but all obediences take only an hour to perform. Once the obedience has been performed, you gain the benefit of a resistance to some element or attack associated with your demon lord, as indicated in the &#x201C;Obedience&#x201D; entry for the demon lord.</p>
			<p>If you have at least 12 Hit Dice, you also gain the first boon granted by your demon lord upon undertaking your obedience. If you have at least 16 Hit Dice, you also gain the demon lord&apos;s second boon. If you have 20 Hit Dice or more, you also gain the demon lord&apos;s third and final boon. Unless a specific duration or number of uses per day is listed, a boon&apos;s effects are constant.</p>
			<p>Demoniacs gain access to these boons at lower levels as a benefit of their prestige class. If you ever fail to perform a daily obedience, you lose all access to resistances and boons granted by this feat until you next perform the obedience.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Slaughter" title="Demonic Slaughter" groups="Combat" description="You punch into your foes' ranks and cut them down.">
		<Prerequisites>Cleave, Demonic Momentum, Demonic Style, Great Cleave, Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Demonic Style, when you successfully bull rush an opponent as part of a charge, you can immediately use Great Cleave as though you had used a standard action to do so. This occurs after the effect of your bull rush is fully resolved. The target of your bull rush must be the target of the first attack you make as part of Great Cleave.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Style" title="Demonic Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Self-preservation is irrelevant in the face of your fury.">
		<Prerequisites>Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, when you use the charge action, the bonus on your attack roll increases by 1 and you deal 2 additional points of damage with melee attacks made as part of the charge.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the rage or bloodrage class feature, you can enter Demonic Style&apos;s stance as part of the free action to enter a rage. If you do, the style stance ends when your rage ends.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demoralizing Lash" title="Demoralizing Lash" groups="Combat, Hobgoblin" description="You cow your enemies with the lash of a whip.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, Intimidate 1 rank, Hobgoblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>To use this feat, you must use a whip (or another weapon in the flails fighter weapon group) to attack a foe demoralized by an Intimidate check. If the attack hits, you extend the duration the creature is shaken by 1 round. This feat has no effect on creatures whose shaken conditions are from sources other than Intimidate checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demoralizing Stare" title="Demoralizing Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your painful stare inspires fear in your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 9th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you trigger your painful stare, the target must succeed at a Will Save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or become shaken for 1 round. This can&apos;t cause the target to become frightened, even if the target is already shaken.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dented Helm" title="Dented Helm" groups="Combat,Dwarf" description="Your helm protects you from hard hits.">
		<Prerequisites>Hard-Headed, base attack bonus +6, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wearing a helmet, you add +1 to your AC against critical hit confirmation rolls. When a critical hit is confirmed against you, as an immediate action, you can apply half of the damage from the attack to your helmet rather than yourself, applying hardness as normal. If the damage destroys your helmet, any leftover damage is applied to you. After using this feat, you are staggered until the end of your next turn. You may not use this feat if your helmet has the broken condition or the attack ignores armor bonuses to AC.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deny Death" title="Deny Death" groups="" description="Your ki is so strong that it can deny death.">
		<Prerequisites>Ki pool, Endurance</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you have 1 ki point in your ki pool, when you fail your Constitution check to stabilize, you do not lose 1 hit point. If you succeed at the check, you can spend 1 ki point to heal 1d6 hit points. If you roll a natural 20 on the check to stabilize, you can spend 1 ki point to heal 2d6 hit points of damage instead.</p>
			<p>PRG:UM </p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dervish Dance" title="Dervish Dance" groups="Combat" description="You have learned to turn your speed into power, even with a heavier blade.">
		<Prerequisites>Dexterity 13, Weapon Finesse, Perform (dance) 2 ranks, proficient with scimitar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a scimitar with one hand, you can use your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier on melee attack and damage rolls. You treat the scimitar as a one-handed piercing weapon for all feats and class abilities that require such a weapon (such as a duelist&apos;s precise strike ability). The scimitar must be for a creature of your size. You cannot use this feat if you are carrying a weapon or shield in your off hand.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Desert Dweller" title="Desert Dweller" groups="" description="The endless sands and waterless wastes are your home, and neither the heat nor dehydration presents as lethal of a threat to you as it does to other travelers.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored terrain (desert) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat hot environments as though they were one step less severe; if you have a similar ability from another feat, such as Torrid Tolerance, the benefits stack and you treat hot conditions as if they were two steps less severe. You need to consume only half the normal amount of water for a creature of your size, and you gain a +4 bonus on Constitution checks to resist the effects of thirst. You also gain a +4 bonus on saving throws and checks to avoid becoming blinded or dazzled by glare or being deceived by a desert mirage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Desperate Battler" title="Desperate Battler" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When no ally is within 10 feet of you and you are not receiving benefits from the aid another action, you gain a +1 morale bonus on melee attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points to gain the benefits of Desperate Battler even while an ally is within 10 feet of you (but not when receiving the benefits of the aid another action).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Desperate Swing" title="Desperate Swing" groups="Combat,Halfling" description="You land your most telling blows in desperate situations.">
		<Prerequisites>Cautious Fighter, base attack bonus +1, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can make a single melee attack while taking the total defense action. You take a &#x2013;4 penalty on attack rolls when making this attack. You also gain a +4 bonus on critical confirmation rolls made while fighting defensively or making an attack of opportunity using this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Destroy Identity" title="Destroy Identity" groups="Combat" description="You can use your weapons to mar your opponents' most distinctive characteristics.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +11, worshiper of an evil deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you confirm a critical hit against an opponent, in addition to dealing critical damage as normal, you maim your target so much that it takes 2 points of Charisma damage and becomes staggered for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When you confirm a critical hit against an opponent, you can spend 4 stamina points to increase the Charisma damage that opponent takes from Destroy Identity to 1d3+1 points.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Destroyer's Blessing" title="Destroyer's Blessing" groups="Combat" description="Breaking things adds to your power.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc or orc, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are raging and you succeed at a sunder combat maneuver, you regain 1 round of rage. If the sunder attempt causes the object to gain the broken condition, you heal 1 hit point. You can only gain these benefits once per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Destructive Dispel" title="Destructive Dispel" groups="" description="When you dispel an enemy's magical defenses, those defenses crash down with debilitating effects.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast dispel magic or greater dispel magic, caster level 11th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully make a targeted dispel check against an opponent, that opponent must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC equals the DC of the spell used to dispel) or be stunned until the start of your next turn. If the save succeeds, the opponent is instead sickened until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Destructive Persuasion" title="Destructive Persuasion" groups="Combat" description="Sometimes, you have to break things if you want people to get your point.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, Intimidate 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can attempt to smash an unattended inanimate object while attempting an Intimidate check (see Smashing an Object). If you break the object, you gain a bonus to the Intimidate check equal to half its hardness (minimum +1). If you destroy the object, the bonus is equal to its hardness (minimum +1). Creatures intimidated by this feat cannot be affected by it again for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Detect Expertise" title="Detect Expertise" groups="" description="You can detect the mystic specialty of a foe.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13; ability to cast detect chaos, detect evil, detect good, detect law, or detect magic.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use any of the spells listed in this feat&apos;s prerequisites to detect a creature&apos;s alignment or its magic, you have a chance of detecting what spellcasting expertise it has. After you observe a creature with the detect spell for 3 rounds, it must make a Will save (DC 10 + 1/2 your caster level + your Intelligence modifier). If it fails the saving throw, you learn what bloodlines, domains, hexes, schools, or mysteries (if any) the creature possesses. If the creature makes its save, it is immune to the effects of this feat for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Devastating Strike" title="Devastating Strike" groups="Combat" description="Pitting all of your strength and resolve against your enemy, you deliver a strike that is impossible to ignore.">
		<Prerequisites>Vital Strike, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, or Greater Vital Strike, you gain a +2 bonus on each extra weapon damage dice roll those feats grant (+6 maximum). This bonus damage is multiplied on a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Devotion against the Unnatural" title="Devotion against the Unnatural" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="The animal's devotion to its master allows it to stand against unnatural forces.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion, devotion special ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The animal companion gains a +2 morale bonus on saving throws against spells, spell-like abilities, and supernatural abilities of aberrations, outsiders, and undead. The animal companion is immune to the unnatural aura ability that some undead creatures (such as wraiths) have.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
</Bundles>
