<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Bundles>
	<Bundle id="Dance of Chains" title="Dance of Chains" groups="Combat" description="In your hands, a spiked chain dances like a living thing.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Chain Mastery, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (spiked chain), Weapon Finesse, Perform (dance) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a spiked chain one-handed, you can add your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier to that weapon&apos;s damage. The spiked chain must be one appropriate for your size. During your turn, you treat your reach with the spiked chain as 5 feet greater. You lose these benefits while fighting with multiple weapons or when using a shield (but not when using a buckler).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dangerous Tail" title="Dangerous Tail" groups="Combat" description="You have trained your tail into a powerful weapon, and wield it with deadly skill.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +5, Lizardfolk.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a tail swipe attack. If used as part of a full-attack action, the attack is made at your full base attack bonus - 5. If the tail swipe hits, it deals 1d4 points of damage (assuming you are Medium) + 1/2 your Strength modifier. If you confirm a critical hit against a target with your tail swipe, as a free action you can attempt a trip combat maneuver against that target.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Darting Viper" title="Darting Viper" groups="Combat" description="When using a dorn-dergar, you can quickly attack both near and distant foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +4, proficiency with the dwarven dorn-dergar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can change whether you&apos;re using the dorn-dergar as a normal or reach weapon as a swift action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Changing whether a dorn-dergar is a normal or reach weapon is a move action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dastardly Finish" title="Dastardly Finish" groups="Combat" description="You can take advantage of an enemy&apos;s debilitated state to attempt a coup de grace.">
		<Prerequisites>Sneak attack +5d6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can deliver a coup de grace to cowering or stunned targets.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only coup de grace helpless targets.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazing Assault" title="Dazing Assault" groups="Combat" description="You can daze foes with wild attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose to take a -5 penalty on all melee attack rolls and combat maneuver checks to daze opponents you hit with your melee attacks for 1 round, in addition to the normal damage dealt by the attack. A successful Fortitude save negates the effect. The DC of this save is 10 + your base attack bonus. You must choose to use this feat before making the attack roll, and its effects last until your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazing Fist" title="Dazing Fist" groups="Combat" description="You know just where to strike to daze your foe.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You must declare that you are using this feat before you make your attack roll (thus, a failed attack roll ruins the attempt). Dazing Fist forces a foe damaged by your unarmed attack to attempt a Fortitude saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier), in addition to dealing damage normally. A foe who fails this saving throw is dazed for 1 round, until just before your next turn. You can attempt to use Dazing Fist once per day for every 4 character levels you have, but no more than once per round. Constructs, incorporeal creatures, plants, undead, and creatures that are immune to critical hits cannot be affected by this ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazing Spell" title="Dazing Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can daze creatures with the power of your spells.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can modify a spell to daze a creature damaged by the spell. When a creature takes damage from this spell, they become dazed for a number of rounds equal to the original level of the spell. If the spell allows a saving throw, a successful save negates the daze effect. If the spell does not allow a save, the target can make a Will save to negate the daze effect. If the spell effect also causes the creature to become dazed, the duration of this metamagic effect is added to the duration of the spell.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +3 (a dazing spell uses up a spell slot three levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.Spells that do not inflict damage do not benefit from this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dazzling Display" title="Dazzling Display" groups="Combat" description="Your skill with your favored weapon can frighten enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus, proficiency with the selected weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While wielding the weapon in which you have Weapon Focus, you can perform a bewildering show of prowess as a full-round action. Make an Intimidate check to demoralize all foes within 30 feet who can see your display.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadeye&apos;s Blessing Combat" title="Deadeye&apos;s Blessing Combat" groups="Combat" description="Your deity grants you prowess with a bow that far exceeds your own physical capabilities.">Note This is associated with a specific deity.
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus (longbow), must be a worshiper of the associated deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use your Wisdom modifier instead of your Dexterity modifier on ranged attack rolls when using a bow.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadhand Initiate" title="Deadhand Initiate" groups="Combat" description="Your adulation of death not only shields you from your fears, it allows you to feed on them.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 19, Deadhand Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Knowledge (religion) 6 ranks, ki pool class feature, nongood alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Deadhand Style, as long as you have at least 1 point in your ki pool, your bonus on saving throws against fear effects increases to +4, and the DC of Intimidate checks attempted against you increases by 8.</p>
			<p>Additionally, if an enemy targets you with a fear effect, you can spend 1 point from your ki pool as an immediate action to gain a number of temporary hit points equal to twice your Hit Dice.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadhand Master" title="Deadhand Master" groups="Combat" description="Your death-infused punch drains life force from your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 23, Deadhand Initiate, Deadhand Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Knowledge (religion) 14 ranks, ki pool class feature, nongood alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Deadhand Style, when you damage a living creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 2 points from your ki pool as a swift action to inflict 2 temporary negative levels on your enemy with no saving throw. Effects that reduce the ki cost also reduce the number of negative levels you inflict on your foe, but effects that increase the ki cost do not increase the number of negative levels you inflict. As long as the foe is affected by the temporary negative levels, you can&apos;t recover the ki points you spent, effectively reducing the size of your ki pool. The Fortitude save DC to remove the negative levels and prevent them from becoming permanent is equal to 10 + 1/2 your Hit Dice + your Wisdom modifier. Once the negative levels become permanent or the foe removes them, you can recover your spent ki points. If the foe dies before either happens, you can recover the spent ki after 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadhand Style" title="Deadhand Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your study of death allow you to exploit your foes&apos; fears.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 15, Improved Unarmed Strike, Knowledge (religion) 4 ranks, ki pool class feature, nongood alignment.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, if you have at least 1 point in your ki pool, you gain a +2 bonus on saves against fear effects, and the DC of Intimidate checks against you increases by 4. As a swift action, you can spend 1 point from your ki pool to empower your unarmed strikes. Creatures hit with your unarmed strikes must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier) or become shaken for a number of rounds equal to your Wisdom modifier. This is a mind-affecting fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Aim" title="Deadly Aim" groups="Combat" description="You can make exceptionally deadly ranged attacks by pinpointing a foe&apos;s weak spot, at the expense of making the attack less likely to succeed.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose to take a -1 penalty on all ranged attack rolls to gain a +2 bonus on all ranged damage rolls. When your base attack bonus reaches +4, and every +4 thereafter, the penalty increases by -1 and the bonus to damage increases by +2. You must choose to use this feat before making an attack roll and its effects last until your next turn. The bonus damage does not apply to touch attacks or effects that do not deal hit point damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Finish" title="Deadly Finish" groups="Combat" description="Your attacks don&apos;t just fell your opponents&#x2014;they kill them outright.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you hit with a melee attack and reduce your opponent to -1 or fewer hit points, you can force that opponent to succeed at a Fortitude save (DC 15 + the damage your attack dealt) or die.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Grappler" title="Deadly Grappler" groups="Combat" description="While you&apos;re grappled, you become even more dangerous.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You have learned to leverage a grappling creature&apos;s weight against it. While you&apos;re grappled, attacks you make against the grappler using armor spikes, a light or one-handed weapon, a natural weapon, or an unarmed strike deal damage as if the strike or weapon were one size category larger than it actually is.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Horns" title="Deadly Horns" groups="Combat" description="Many tieflings bear horns as an overt mark of their fiendish heritage; you have learned to use yours as a weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a gore natural attack that deals 1d6 points of damage. Due to the awkwardness of attacking this way, you can&apos;t make a gore attack and other natural weapon attacks as part of the same full attack. Treat your gore attack as a secondary attack if you also attack with a manufactured weapon as part of a full attack in a round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deadly Stroke" title="Deadly Stroke" groups="Combat" description="With a well-placed strike, you can bring a swift and painful end to most foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Greater Weapon Focus, Shatter Defenses, Weapon Focus, proficiency with the selected weapon, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, make a single attack with the weapon for which you have Greater Weapon Focus against a stunned or flat-footed opponent. If you hit, you deal double the normal damage and the target takes 1 point of Constitution bleed (see Conditions). The additional damage and bleed is not multiplied on a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deafening Critical" title="Deafening Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits cause enemies to lose their hearing.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit against an opponent, the victim is permanently deafened. A successful Fortitude save reduces the deafness to 1 round. The DC of this Fortitude save is equal to 10 + your base attack bonus. This feat has no effect on deaf creatures. This deafness can be cured by heal, regeneration, remove deafness, or a similar ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deafening Explosion" title="Deafening Explosion" groups="Hobgoblin" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Bomb class feature, Hobgoblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may reduce your bomb damage by one die to give it the ability to deafen the creature struck by it. The bomb must deal fire, force, or sonic damage. If a creature takes a direct hit from your bomb, it must make a saving throw against the bomb&apos;s DC or be deafened for 1 minute. This deafening is in addition to any other effects the bomb would normally have.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death From Below" title="Death From Below" groups="Combat" description="You have been trained to fight flying creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 circumstance bonus against flying opponents when you have set a weapon against a charge, or when you are allowed an attack of opportunity against the flying opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death Roll" title="Death Roll" groups="Combat" description="Like an alligator, you twist and wrench your foe, forcing him to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Bite attack, reptilian subtype.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When grappling a foe of your size or smaller, you can attempt to perform a death roll. Upon a successful grapple combat maneuver check to deal damage with your bite attack, you can immediately attempt a second grapple combat maneuver check as a free action. If successful, you knock the target prone. Upon knocking the target prone, you must either release the grapple or fall prone and maintain the grapple. This doesn&apos;t count as a combat maneuver check to maintain the grapple, and doesn&apos;t add any other effects (such as constrict) beyond knocking the target prone.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death from Above" title="Death from Above" groups="Combat" description="You allow gravity to add extra force to your charges.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you charge an opponent from higher ground, or from above while flying, you gain a +5 bonus on attack rolls in place of the bonuses from charging and being on higher ground.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Death or Glory" title="Death or Glory" groups="Combat" description="Even when facing a larger foe, you aren&apos;t afraid to take great risks in order to finish the fight.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Against a creature of size Large or larger, you can make a single melee attack as a full-round action, gaining a +4 bonus on the attack roll, damage roll, and critical confirmation roll. You gain an additional +1 on this bonus at base attack bonus +11, +16, and +20 (for a maximum of +7 at base attack +20). After you resolve your attack, the opponent you attack can spend an immediate action to make a single melee attack against you with the same bonuses.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can combine the full-round action attack this feat allows with the benefit of Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, or Greater Vital Strike.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deathless Initiate" title="Deathless Initiate" groups="Combat" description="For you, impending death is a call to wrath.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Con 13, orc or half-orc, Diehard, Endurance, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You are not staggered while using the Diehard feat, but if you take a move and a standard action or a full-round action while you are at 0 or fewer hit points you take 1 point of damage. Further, while using the Diehard feat, you gain a +2 bonus on melee attacks and damage rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deathless Master" title="Deathless Master" groups="Combat" description="Even if you suffer a grievous wound, you can shrug off the damage and continue your relentless assault.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Con 15, orc or half-orc, Deathless Initiate, Diehard, Endurance, Ironhide, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are at 0 or fewer hit points, you do not lose 1 hit point when you take an action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deathless Zealot" title="Deathless Zealot" groups="Combat" description="Only the most serious wounds can stop you.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Con 17, orc or half-orc, Deathless Initiate, Deathless Master, Diehard, Endurance, Ironhide, base attack bonus +12.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever a creature rolls to confirm a critical hit against you, it must roll twice and take the lowest result.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deceitful Incompetence" title="Deceitful Incompetence" groups="Combat" description="You learn from your mistakes rapidly when others lower their guard around you.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you make an attack of opportunity in a single round after you have already made an unsuccessful attack of opportunity that round, you gain a cumulative +2 insight bonus on your attack roll for each unsuccessful attack of opportunity. For example, if you have made one unsuccessful attack of opportunity and an enemy provokes another attack of opportunity from you during that same round, you gain a +2 insight bonus on that attack roll, and if you have made two unsuccessful attacks of opportunity in a round and an enemy provokes another attack of opportunity from you during that same round, you gain a +4 insight bonus on that attack roll, and so on.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dedicated Adversary" title="Dedicated Adversary" groups="Combat" description="Your repeated encounters with a particular type of enemy have honed your skills against that foe.">
		<Prerequisites>No levels in a class that has the favored enemy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you select this feat, choose a specific kind of creature, such as wolf, frost giant, goblin, or babau demon. You gain the ranger&apos;s favored enemy class ability against this particular type of creature with a bonus of +2.</p>
			<p>This feat does not grant the favored enemy class feature for the purposes of prerequisites. If you later gain the favored enemy class feature, you can replace this feat with a feat for which you qualify and whose prerequisites include the favored enemy class feature.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a different creature.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Defensive Combat Training" title="Defensive Combat Training" groups="Combat" description="You excel at defending yourself from all manner of combat maneuvers.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat your total Hit Dice as your base attack bonus when calculating your Combat Maneuver Defense (see Combat).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Defensive Weapon Training" title="Defensive Weapon Training" groups="Combat" description="You know how to defend yourself against a certain class of weaponry.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a weapon group from the fighter&apos;s weapon training class ability list (except natural weapons). You gain a +2 dodge bonus on AC when an opponent attacks you using a weapon from that group. If you also have the weapon training class feature in the selected group, your dodge bonus from this feat increases to +3.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can select this feat more than once. Its effects do not stack. Each time you select this feat, it applies to a different weapon group.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Defiant Luck" title="Defiant Luck" groups="Human" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, after you roll a natural 1 on a saving throw or a critical hit is confirmed against you, you can either reroll that saving throw, or force the creature that confirmed the critical hit against you to reroll the critical confirmation roll. This does not stack with other effects that allow you to reroll a saving throw or an attack roll. You may only make one reroll.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are using the optional hero point system, you can also spend 1 hero point when a critical hit is confirmed against you to have the opponent reroll the critical hit confirmation roll.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deflect Arrows" title="Deflect Arrows" groups="Combat" description="You can knock arrows and other projectiles off course, preventing them from hitting you.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You must have at least one hand free (holding nothing) to use this feat. Once per round when you would normally be hit with an attack from a ranged weapon, you may deflect it so that you take no damage from it. You must be aware of the attack and not flat-footed. Attempting to deflect a ranged attack doesn&apos;t count as an action. Unusually massive ranged weapons (such as boulders or ballista bolts) and ranged attacks generated by natural attacks or spell effects can&apos;t be deflected.</p>
			<p>Editor&apos;s Note</p>
			<p>Does an attack that is &apos;deflected&apos; count as a miss?</p>
			<p>It depends on the ability that is deflecting the attack.</p>
			<p>For example, the Deflect Arrows feat says, &apos;Once per round when you would normally be hit with an attack from a ranged weapon, you may deflect it so that you take no damage from it.&apos; It doesn&apos;t say the attack is a miss or is treated as a miss&#x2014;instead, you take no damage from the attack. Because it is not a miss, effects that would trigger on a miss (such as Efreeti Style or Snake Fang) are not triggered.</p>
			<p>Likewise, the Crane Wing feat uses similar language and does not say the deflected attack is a miss or treated as a miss.</p>
			<p>Note that the Snatch Arrows feat counts as a deflected attack&#x2014;you do not take damage if you choose to catch the weapons instead of just deflecting it, and catching the weapon does not mean the attack was a miss.</p>
			<p>Update: If the attack is deflected, not only does the target take no damage, but any other effects (ability drain, negative levels, harmful conditions, and so on) associated with that attack do not occur. If the deflected attack is a touch spell or other effect that requires &apos;holding the charge,&apos; the charge is not expended. For example, if a ghoul&apos;s claw attack is deflected, the target is not subject to the ghoul&apos;s paralysis ability from the attack. If a shocking grasp touch attack is deflected, the attacker is still &apos;holding the charge.&apos;</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
			<p>How does Deflect Arrows work with Manyshot?</p>
			<p>Deflect Arrows works only once per round. Manyshot allows an archer to shoot multiple arrows, but you only make one attack roll, so Deflect Arrows would block all arrows grouped in anyone particular Manyshot attack.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Deft Hands" title="Deft Hands" groups="" description="You have exceptional manual dexterity.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on Disable Device and Sleight of Hand skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demon Hunter" title="Demon Hunter" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (planes) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Knowledge (planes) checks to know the powers and abilities of demons. You gain a +2 morale bonus on all attack rolls and a +2 morale bonus on caster level checks to penetrate spell resistance made against creatures with the demon subtype you recognize as demons.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When you successfully identify a demon using Knowledge (planes), you can spend up to 9 stamina points to increase the morale bonus on attack rolls and caster level checks from Demon Hunter by 1 per 3 stamina points spent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Momentum" title="Demonic Momentum" groups="Combat" description="You slam into foes with devastating force, leaving them vulnerable to your vicious strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Demonic Style, Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Demonic Style, when you successfully bull rush an opponent as part of a charge, you gain a +2 bonus on melee weapon damage rolls against that opponent for every 5 feet it was moved by your bull rush.</p>
			<p>This bonus lasts until the end of your next turn, and it stacks with the damage bonus granted by Demonic Style.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Nemesis" title="Demonic Nemesis" groups="Combat" description="You are well acquainted with the machinations of a particular demon lord. You&apos;re resistant to his tricks, and have no fear of his minions.">
		<Prerequisites>Demon Hunter, Knowledge (planes) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you take this feat, choose a demon lord. When fighting followers of that demon lord, including cultists or demons, you gain a +2 bonus on damage rolls and rolls to confirm critical hits against these creatures.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat more than once. Each time you do, you must choose a new demon lord.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Slaughter" title="Demonic Slaughter" groups="Combat" description="You punch into your foes&apos; ranks and cut them down.">
		<Prerequisites>Cleave, Demonic Momentum, Demonic Style, Great Cleave, Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Demonic Style, when you successfully bull rush an opponent as part of a charge, you can immediately use Great Cleave as though you had used a standard action to do so. This occurs after the effect of your bull rush is fully resolved. The target of your bull rush must be the target of the first attack you make as part of Great Cleave.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demonic Style" title="Demonic Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Self-preservation is irrelevant in the face of your fury.">
		<Prerequisites>Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, when you use the charge action, the bonus on your attack roll increases by 1 and you deal 2 additional points of damage with melee attacks made as part of the charge.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the rage or bloodrage class feature, you can enter Demonic Style&apos;s stance as part of the free action to enter a rage. If you do, the style stance ends when your rage ends.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demoralizing Lash" title="Demoralizing Lash" groups="Combat, Hobgoblin" description="You cow your enemies with the lash of a whip.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, Intimidate 1 rank, Hobgoblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>To use this feat, you must use a whip (or another weapon in the flails fighter weapon group) to attack a foe demoralized by an Intimidate check. If the attack hits, you extend the duration the creature is shaken by 1 round. This feat has no effect on creatures whose shaken conditions are from sources other than Intimidate checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Demoralizing Stare" title="Demoralizing Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your painful stare inspires fear in your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 9th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you trigger your painful stare, the target must succeed at a Will Save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or become shaken for 1 round. This can&apos;t cause the target to become frightened, even if the target is already shaken.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dervish Dance" title="Dervish Dance" groups="Combat" description="You have learned to turn your speed into power, even with a heavier blade.">
		<Prerequisites>Dexterity 13, Weapon Finesse, Perform (dance) 2 ranks, proficient with scimitar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a scimitar with one hand, you can use your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier on melee attack and damage rolls. You treat the scimitar as a one-handed piercing weapon for all feats and class abilities that require such a weapon (such as a duelist&apos;s precise strike ability). The scimitar must be for a creature of your size. You cannot use this feat if you are carrying a weapon or shield in your off hand.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Desert Dweller" title="Desert Dweller" groups="" description="The endless sands and waterless wastes are your home, and neither the heat nor dehydration presents as lethal of a threat to you as it does to other travelers.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored terrain (desert) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat hot environments as though they were one step less severe; if you have a similar ability from another feat, such as Torrid Tolerance, the benefits stack and you treat hot conditions as if they were two steps less severe. You need to consume only half the normal amount of water for a creature of your size, and you gain a +4 bonus on Constitution checks to resist the effects of thirst. You also gain a +4 bonus on saving throws and checks to avoid becoming blinded or dazzled by glare or being deceived by a desert mirage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Desperate Battler" title="Desperate Battler" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When no ally is within 10 feet of you and you are not receiving benefits from the aid another action, you gain a +1 morale bonus on melee attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points to gain the benefits of Desperate Battler even while an ally is within 10 feet of you (but not when receiving the benefits of the aid another action).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Destroy Identity" title="Destroy Identity" groups="Combat" description="You can use your weapons to mar your opponents&apos; most distinctive characteristics.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +11, worshiper of an evil deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you confirm a critical hit against an opponent, in addition to dealing critical damage as normal, you maim your target so much that it takes 2 points of Charisma damage and becomes staggered for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When you confirm a critical hit against an opponent, you can spend 4 stamina points to increase the Charisma damage that opponent takes from Destroy Identity to 1d3+1 points.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Destroyer&apos;s Blessing" title="Destroyer&apos;s Blessing" groups="Combat" description="Breaking things adds to your power.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc or orc, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are raging and you succeed at a sunder combat maneuver, you regain 1 round of rage. If the sunder attempt causes the object to gain the broken condition, you heal 1 hit point. You can only gain these benefits once per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Destructive Persuasion" title="Destructive Persuasion" groups="Combat" description="Sometimes, you have to break things if you want people to get your point.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, Intimidate 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can attempt to smash an unattended inanimate object while attempting an Intimidate check (see Smashing an Object). If you break the object, you gain a bonus to the Intimidate check equal to half its hardness (minimum +1). If you destroy the object, the bonus is equal to its hardness (minimum +1). Creatures intimidated by this feat cannot be affected by it again for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Devastating Strike" title="Devastating Strike" groups="Combat" description="Pitting all of your strength and resolve against your enemy, you deliver a strike that is impossible to ignore.">
		<Prerequisites>Vital Strike, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, or Greater Vital Strike, you gain a +2 bonus on each extra weapon damage dice roll those feats grant (+6 maximum). This bonus damage is multiplied on a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diabolic Humiliation" title="Diabolic Humiliation" groups="Combat" description="Your humiliating strikes decrease a foe&apos;s morale.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes, Diabolic Style; Vital Strike; Improved Unarmed Strike or Weapon Focus (unarmed strike); base attack bonus +8 or monk level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully stagger a foe with an unarmed strike using Diabolic Style, the target becomes further humiliated. The target cannot gain the benefit of any morale bonus for 1 minute after being staggered in this way, and for the duration of that minute, any additional staggered effects it suffers from your attacks of opportunity last for 2 rounds rather than 1. The durations of multiple staggered effects administered in this way stack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk of at least 10th level with this feat can select Improved Vital Strike as a monk bonus feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diabolic Judgment" title="Diabolic Judgment" groups="Combat" description="You punish your foes for every opportunity they present.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes; Diabolic Humiliation; Diabolic Style; Improved Vital Strike; Vital Strike; Improved Unarmed Strike or Weapon Focus (unarmed strike); base attack bonus +12 or monk level 11th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Diabolic Style, the first time each round that you successfully hit with an attack of opportunity, you can apply the effects of any Vital Strike feat you have to that attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk of at least 14th level with this feat can select Greater Vital Strike as a monk bonus feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diabolic Style" title="Diabolic Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You utilize combat as an opportunity to inflict humiliation upon those who provoke your attacks of opportunity.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes; Improved Unarmed Strike or Weapon Focus (unarmed strike); base attack bonus +2 or monk level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you can make an attack of opportunity with an unarmed strike to deliver a humiliating swat to the target. If you hit the target, you inflict 1 point of nonlethal damage and the target must succeed at a Will saving throw (DC = 10 + half your level + your Charisma modifier) or become staggered for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk of at least 6th level with this feat can select Vital Strike as a monk bonus feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diehard" title="Diehard" groups="" description="You are especially hard to kill. Not only do your wounds automatically stabilize when grievously injured, but you can remain conscious and continue to act even at death's door.">
		<Prerequisites>Endurance.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When your hit point total is below 0, but you are not dead, you automatically stabilize. You do not need to make a Constitution check each round to avoid losing additional hit points. You may choose to act as if you were disabled, rather than dying. You must make this decision as soon as you are reduced to negative hit points (even if it isn&apos;t your turn). If you do not choose to act as if you were disabled, you immediately fall unconscious.</p>
			<p>When using this feat, you are staggered. You can take a move action without further injuring yourself, but if you perform any standard action (or any other action deemed as strenuous, including some swift actions, such as casting a quickened spell) you take 1 point of damage after completing the act. If your negative hit points are equal to or greater than your Constitution score, you immediately die.<Normal>
			<p>A character without this feat who is reduced to negative hit points is unconscious and dying.</p>
		</Normal></p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dimensional Awareness" title="Dimensional Awareness" groups="Combat" description="Your exposure to summoned creatures allows you to predict where conjured opponents will likely appear.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Strike or Disruptive; Banishing Critical; Combat Reflexes; Spellcraft 8 ranks; arcane pool class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If a summoned or called creature materializes in a space you threaten, you can make an attack of opportunity against that creature before it acts, gaining a +2 circumstance bonus on the attack roll if you successfully identified the spell used to summon or call that creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A summoned or called creature appears instantly when the spell used to conjure it is completed, allowing for no attack of opportunity against the creature.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dimensional Disruption" title="Dimensional Disruption" groups="Combat" description="You&apos;ve become so adept at combating summoned creatures that you can interrupt the magical energies that summon them to your plane.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Strike or Disruptive; Banishing Critical; Combat Reflexes; Dimensional Awareness; Spellcraft 8 ranks; arcane pool class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Dimensional Awareness to make an attack of opportunity against a creature being summoned or called into a square you threaten, you can additionally use an immediate action to attempt to send the creature back to its home plane. Attempt a Spellcraft check (DC = 15 + the creature&apos;s CR [minimum 1] + the spell level of the spell that summoned the creature). If you succeed, the creature does not get to act and is immediately sent back to its home plane.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A summoning or calling spell can be disrupted only by a failed concentration check or by countering the spell.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Directed Disarm" title="Directed Disarm" groups="Combat" description="A weapon you pull from one enemy&apos;s grip flies toward another enemy.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Greater Disarm, Improved Disarm, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you successfully use a combat maneuver to disarm an opponent, the disarmed weapon lands up to 15 feet away from its wielder, in the direction you choose. Alternatively, you can make a ranged attack as an immediate action with the disarmed weapon against another opponent, as long as the disarmed weapon is a light or one-handed weapon. If the weapon is not a thrown weapon, you take a -4 penalty on the attack roll. You take a -4 penalty on your attack roll if you do not have a free hand.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dirty Fighting" title="Dirty Fighting" groups="Combat" description="You can take advantage of a distracted foe.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you attempt a combat maneuver check against a foe you are flanking, you can forgo the +2 bonus on your attack roll for flanking to instead have the combat maneuver not provoke an attack of opportunity. If you have a feat or ability that allows you to attempt the combat maneuver without provoking an attack of opportunity, you can instead increase the bonus on your attack roll for flanking to +4 for the combat maneuver check.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat counts as having Dex 13, Int 13, Combat Expertise, and Improved Unarmed Strike for the purposes of meeting the prerequisites of the various improved combat maneuver feats, as well as feats that require those improved combat maneuver feats as prerequisites.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dirty Trick Master" title="Dirty Trick Master" groups="Combat" description="You are adept at stifling your enemies and can expertly make a bad situation even worse.">
		<Prerequisites>Greater Dirty Trick, Improved Dirty Trick, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you successfully perform a dirty trick combat maneuver against an opponent who is still affected by a condition inflicted by a previous dirty trick (whether your own or another creature&apos;s), you can cause the condition to worsen. In addition to increasing the duration of the condition as normal, you cause an opponent who is dazzled to become dazed, entangled to become pinned, shaken to become frightened, and sickened to become nauseated. This worsened condition replaces the previous dirty trick condition, and lasts for the duration of the dirty trick (including any rounds remaining from the previous dirty trick condition) or until the opponent uses a standard action to remove the condition (whichever comes first).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disarming Strike" title="Disarming Strike" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits can disarm your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Disarm, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit with a melee attack, you can disarm your opponent, in addition to the normal damage dealt by the attack. If your confirmation roll exceeds your opponent&apos;s CMD, you may disarm your opponent as if from the disarm combat maneuver. This does not provoke an attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You must perform a disarm combat maneuver to disarm an opponent.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one of the following feats to a given critical hit: Bull Rush Strike, Disarming Strike, Repositioning Strike, Sundering Strike, or Tripping Strike. You may choose to use this feat after you make your confirmation roll.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disconcerting Stare" title="Disconcerting Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your painful stare unnerves your target, making it oblivious to its surroundings.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 5th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you trigger your painful stare, the target must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or take a -6 penalty on Disable Device and Perception checks and a -2 penalty on Reflex saves for the next minute. If the target has the trap finding or trap sense class ability and fails this save, the target also loses the benefit of that ability (or abilities) for 1 minute.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disengaging Feint" title="Disengaging Feint" groups="Combat" description="You can feint to disengage from combat.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Feint.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, use Bluff to feint against an opponent. Instead of denying that opponent his Dexterity bonus to AC, a successful feint allows you to move up to your speed without provoking an attack of opportunity from the opponent you feinted for leaving the square you start in.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disengaging Flourish" title="Disengaging Flourish" groups="Combat" description="Distracting your opponents gives you the opportunity to make a swift retreat.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Disengaging Feint, Improved Feint.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, make a Bluff check against each opponent that currently threatens you. If you succeed against at least one opponent, you can move up to your speed. This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity from any opponent you succeeded at feinting against.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disengaging Shot" title="Disengaging Shot" groups="Combat" description="You make one last attack before beating a hasty retreat.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Disengaging Feint, Dodge, Improved Feint, Mobility.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use Disengaging Feint or Disengaging Flourish, you can make a single melee attack against one opponent you succeeded at feinting against. That opponent is denied his Dexterity bonus to AC against this attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disheartening Display" title="Disheartening Display" groups="Combat" description="Your show of prowess further demoralizes others.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus, base attack bonus +6, proficiency with chosen weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully use Dazzling Display against any shaken, frightened, or panicked opponents, their fear increases by one step. An already panicked creature demoralized by this feat cowers. Once affected by this feat, a creature cannot be affected by it again (by you or anyone else) for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disorienting Blow" title="Disorienting Blow" groups="Combat" description="When you successfully strike your opponent with your Stunning Fist, you leave it in a state of confusion.">
		<Prerequisites>Stunning Fist, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You must choose to use this ability before making an attack roll with your Stunning Fist, and this effect replaces other effects or conditions that would be caused by Stunning Fist. If you successfully hit your opponent and it fails its Fortitude save, it becomes confused for 1 round. Additional disorienting blows to the confused target add to the duration of its confusion. This feat is otherwise subject to all of the limits and conditions of Stunning Fist.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dispel Mastery" title="Dispel Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can dispel magic with abjuration magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude save bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has an abjuration spell of 2nd level or higher in its construction requirements to cast dispel magic, but only to perform a targeted dispel.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day at base Fortitude save bonus +9 and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disrupting Fist" title="Disrupting Fist" groups="Combat" description="Your powerful fists can reduce undead foes to dust.">
		<Prerequisites>Channel Smite, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +9, channel positive energy 4d6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>On a confirmed critical hit using an unarmed strike against an undead creature, you can expend two uses of your channel energy ability as a swift action to destroy that undead creature. The undead creature can negate this effect with a successful Will saving throw (DC = 10 + your base attack bonus).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disrupting Shot" title="Disrupting Shot" groups="Combat" description="With a well-placed shot, you make it harder for a nearby opponent to cast spells.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Point-Blank Shot, fighter level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you ready an action to shoot an opponent casting a spell within 30 feet and successfully hit that opponent with a ranged attack, the concentration DC to successfully cast the spell is increased by +4.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disruptive" title="Disruptive" groups="Combat" description="Your training makes it difficult for enemy spellcasters to safely cast spells near you.">
		<Prerequisites>6th-level fighter.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The DC to cast spells defensively increases by +4 for all enemies that are within your threatened area. This increase to casting spells defensively only applies if you are aware of the enemy&apos;s location and are capable of taking an attack of opportunity. If you can only take one attack of opportunity per round and have already used that attack, this increase does not apply.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disruptive Companion" title="Disruptive Companion" groups="Animal Companion Feat; Combat" description="The animal's presence harries nearby enemies, making concentration difficult.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The animal companion is trained to interfere with its opponent&apos;s concentration, making even rote tasks difficult. Increase the concentration check DC of spells and spell-like abilities that opponents cast while within the animal companion&apos;s reach by +2. Additionally, opponents can&apos;t take 10 on d20 rolls or checks while within the animal companion&apos;s reach. If an opponent has an ability that allows it to always take 10 on certain skill checks while distracted (such as the skill mastery advanced talent), it gains the benefit of such abilities only if its number of skill ranks is at least 4 higher than the animal companion&apos;s Hit Dice.</p>
			<p>In addition, the animal companion counts as a fighter with a number of class levels equal to its Hit Dice for the purposes of qualifying for the Disruptive feat, as well as for any feat that lists the Disruptive feat as a prerequisite. The animal companion also adds those feats to the list of animal feats that it can choose from when gaining a new feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Disruptive Spell" title="Disruptive Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your magical energies cling to enemies, interfering with their spellcasting.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Targets affected by a disruptive spell must make concentration checks when using spells or spell-like abilities (DC equals the save DC of the disruptive spell plus the level of the spell being cast) for 1 round. Targets that avoid the spell&apos;s effects avoid this feat&apos;s effect as well.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a disruptive spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Distance Thrower" title="Distance Thrower" groups="Combat" description="You are accurate with thrown weapons at longer ranges than normal.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With a thrown weapon, you reduce your penalty on ranged attack rolls due to range by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diva Advance" title="Diva Advance" groups="Combat" description="You stride forward with confidence, trusting your performance to protect you as much as your arms and armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 17, Combat Expertise, Diva Strike, Diva Style, Improved Feint, base attack bonus +11 or bard level 11th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Diva Style, you do not provoke attacks of opportunity from creatures you have successfully feinted against. Additionally, you can feint against a creature using Diva Style from up to 30 feet away.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diva Strike" title="Diva Strike" groups="Combat" description="Those distracted by your performance leave themselves open to vicious attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 15, Combat Expertise, Diva Style, Improved Feint, base attack bonus +7 or bard level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Diva Style, the first time you hit with a melee weapon in a round, you deal an additional amount of damage equal to your Charisma modifier to a target that is denied its Dexterity bonus to AC. This damage is precision-based, and is not multiplied on a critical hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diva Style" title="Diva Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You employ song, dance, or some other method of performance to distract your enemies from the battle at hand.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13; base attack bonus +1 or bard level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you can use any Perform skill in place of Bluff to feint in combat. You can attempt a Perform check to feint as a move action when you begin a bardic performance.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Diverse Palate" title="Diverse Palate" groups="Dhampir" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Blood Drinker, dhampir.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a humanoid subtype or the monstrous humanoid type. You may use your Blood Drinker feat on creatures of this subtype or type.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you select it, choose a new humanoid subtype or the monstrous humanoid.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Divert Harm" title="Divert Harm" groups="Combat" description="You know how to throw your enemies into harm&apos;s way at the last second.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, base attack bonus +6, evasion class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are the target of an area-of-effect attack that normally deals half damage on a successful Reflex save (such as a fireball spell or dragon&apos;s breath weapon), you may, as an immediate action, wrestle an adjacent foe into harm&apos;s way. This does not alter the position of you or your opponent, but your opponent must attempt a Reflex save against the attack in your place. If your opponent fails, it takes half damage from the attack and you take none; if it succeeds, it takes no damage and you take damage as normal as though you&apos;d failed your saving throw (though this damage is still reduced by abilities such as improved evasion). This feat works even if the opponent was already in the affected area of the attack (so it is possible that an unlucky opponent could take as much as 1-1/2 times the damage normally possible from the attack). You can use this ability only on a foe within one size category of yourself.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Divine Assault" title="Divine Assault" groups="Combat" description="You were trained to apply your knowledge of religions to predicting and defeating divine servitors.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, Knowledge (religion) 1 rank, Pure Legion Recruit trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against divine spells and effects and abilities from outsiders. If you must attempt a saving throw against a divine spell, you gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls against the creature that cast the spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Divine Fighting Technique" title="Divine Fighting Technique" groups="Combat" description="Contents">Divine fighting techniques emulate the martial supremacy and approach to combat of certain gods, but do not generally require users&apos; interests and goals to be aligned with the techniques&apos; associated deities.
			<p>Although each deity&apos;s divine fighting technique is primarily preserved and passed on by her faithful, worship is not required to learn one. Instead, these fighting styles simply require a certain manner of looking at the world and specific combat training. A god&apos;s divine fighting technique has an initial benefit as well as an advanced benefit available only if you meet certain prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Any adventurer can learn a divine fighting technique by taking the Divine Fighting Technique feat. A cleric, inquisitor, or warpriest who worships a deity can always choose to give up either the first power of one of her domains or a minor blessing benefit to gain access to that god&apos;s divine fighting technique without having to meet the Divine Fighting Techniques technique&apos;s prerequisites (including the Divine Fighting Technique feat). In addition, a warpriest can always give up a major blessing to gain the advanced benefit without meeting its prerequisite. In a few cases, other classes can gain the benefits by sacrificing class features, as noted in the appropriate divine fighting techniques.</p>
			<p>The following divine fighting techniques are available to all characters who take the Divine Fighting Technique feat or who worship the appropriate deity and give up the indicated class ability.</p>
		<Prerequisites>Same alignment as chosen deity, must worship a single patron deity that has an established divine fighting technique.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select a deity. You can use that deity&apos;s fighting technique and receive any benefit for which you qualify, as described in the Divine Fighting Techniques section below.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Each time you take this feat, it applies to a new deity&apos;s divine fighting technique.</p>
		</Special>
		<Extra>
			<p>Your god teaches complex crossbow techniques.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): You can attempt a ranged stealcombat maneuver check with a crossbow, using your Dexterity modifier in place of your Strength modifier to calculate your Combat Maneuver Bonus. If you succeed, the stolen item is knocked away by the bolt; if the bolt can pierce any part of the item and the item weighs 2 pounds or less, the bolt continues past the creature and carries the item up to one range increment away, pinning it to whatever surface it lands on.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Rapid Reload, base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): When fighting a foe adjacent to a firm surface, you can attempt a ranged dirty trickcombat maneuver check with a crossbow, using your Dexterity modifier in place of your Strength modifier to calculate your Combat Maneuver Bonus. If you succeed, your bolt pins the target&apos;s clothing (or feathers, hide, or the like) to the surface, preventing the target from leaving that space until it breaks free by destroying the bolt or removing it with a successful Strength check (DC = the result of your combat maneuver check to pin it).</p>
			<p>Your god inspires creative ways to poison foes.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A chaotic neutral rogue or slayer who worships such a god can replace one talent with the following initial benefit.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): You can apply poison (your choice) to a whip as a move action. You do not risk poisoning yourself when applying poison to a whip. A whip you wield can deliver contact poison upon a successful combat maneuver check as well as upon a successful attack roll, regardless of whether you deal damage.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Whip Mastery, base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A chaotic neutral rogue or slayer who worships such a god can replace one advanced talent with the following advanced benefit even if she doesn&apos;t meet the prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): You can apply poison to a whip as a swift action.</p>
			<p>You can apply up to 3 doses of the same poison to a whip at a time. Foes are exposed to only 1 dose of poison from any one attack.</p>
			<p>Your god is famous for wading into battle with a tankard in his off-hand.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A chaotic good fighter or swashbuckler who worships such a god can replace proficiency with shields or bucklers with the following initial benefit.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): You can wield a tankard (or mug) as a weapon, treating it in all ways as a light mace appropriate for your size. If you engage in two-weapon fighting with a rapier or light weapon in one hand and a tankard in the other, you can drink a potion or other liquid from the tankard or attempt to toss liquid from the tankard as a dirty trickcombat maneuver (such as to blind a foe) in place of attacking with it. You do not provoke attacks of opportunity for attempting a dirty trick maneuver with a tankard.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Two-Weapon Fighting, Improved Two-Weapon Fighting, base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A chaotic good fighter or swashbuckler of at least 10th level who worships such a god can replace a bonus feat or deed with the following advanced benefit, even if he doesn&apos;t meet the prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): You can refill your tankard with a beverage, potion, or other liquid from a bottle or vial as a swift action. You gain a +2 bonus on combat maneuver checks to perform dirty tricks with tankards. The effects of such a dirty trick lasts for 1d4 rounds + 1 round for every 5 points by which the result of your combat maneuver check exceeds the target&apos;s CMD; a standard action is required for the target to remove this penalty.</p>
			<p>Your god teaches devastating greatsword techniques.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A chaotic neutral barbarian or fighter who worships such a god can replace a bonus feat or rage power with the following initial benefit.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): If you have the Vital Strike feat, you can apply its effect to an attack you make with a greatsword at the end of a charge. If you don&apos;t have the Vital Strike feat, that attack deals 1 additional point of damage instead. The first time you make an attack of opportunity with a greatsword after using Vital Strike with a greatsword on your turn, you can apply Vital Strike to that attack of opportunity.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Str 13, Cleave, Power Attack, Vital Strike, base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A chaotic neutral barbarian or fighter of at least 10th level who worships such a god can replace a bonus feat or rage power with the following advanced benefit, even if she doesn&apos;t meet the prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): When you use Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, or Greater Vital Strike with a greatsword, the damage counts as continuous damage from an injury for the purpose of determining whether a target must attempt a concentration check to cast spells.</p>
			<p>Your god demonstrates how to turn a longsword into a shining beacon of hope.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A paladin who worships such a god can replace a mercy with this initial benefit, even if she doesn&apos;t meets its prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): While wielding a longsword, you can perform an impressive display of prowess as a full-round action. All allies within 30 feet who can see your display gain a +2 sacred bonus on attack rolls, saving throws, and skill checks for 1 round + 1 round per 5 points of base attack bonus you have.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus (longsword), base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Optional Replacement: A paladin of at least 9th level who worships such a god can replace a mercy with the following advanced benefit, even if she doesn&apos;t meet the benefit&apos;s prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): As a standard action or at the end of a charge, you can make an attack against a foe with a longsword. If you succeed, you grant all allies who can see your attack a +2 sacred bonus on attack rolls, saving throws, and skill checks for 1 minute.</p>
			<p>Your god invites all mortals to join in inflicting and suffering pain.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): Once per round, when you hit a foe with a spiked chain, you can twist the chain so it painfully flenses both of you. You and your target are both sickened for 1 round, and the target must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom bonus) or be sickened for an additional 1d4+1 rounds.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): Whenever you sicken a foe with pain using a spiked chain (whether by flensing, as a dirty trick combat maneuver, or otherwise), the victim must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom bonus) or be nauseated for the first round of the duration.</p>
			<p>The following divine fighting techniques (in addition to those described on page 10 of Pathfinder Player Companion: Weapon Master&apos;s Handbook) are available to all characters with the Divine Fighting Technique feat or who meet the optional prerequisites.</p>
			<p>You can use your patron deity&apos;s fighting technique and receive any benefit associated with that technique for which you qualify, as described in the Divine Fighting Techniques section below.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): As a standard action, you can make a single attack with a falchion or a kukri in order to deal bleed damage to the target. When you make this attack, you do not apply your ability modifier (normally Strength, but potentially other modifiers) to the hit point damage dealt by your attack&#x2014;instead, add an amount of bleed damage equal to this modifier. The bleeding can be stopped by a successful DC 15 Heal check or any amount of magical healing. Bleed damage from this benefit doesn&apos;t stack with itself.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Str 13, Dazing Assault, Divine Fighting Technique, Power Attack.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): Whenever you hit a bleeding creature with a melee attack using a falchion or a kukri, that creature must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + your base attack bonus) or become staggered for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Multiple attacks do not cause this condition to stack, and a creature that successfully saves against this staggering effect is immune to this effect for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Optional Prerequisites: A lawful good ranger can choose Divine Fighting Technique as the bonus feat granted by his combat style if he chooses archery as his combat style.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): As a standard action, you can fire a distracting shot from your longbow or shortbow; when you do, select one ally who is adjacent to the creature you are targeting with the distracting shot. If you hit the creature, the chosen ally gains a +2 bonus to her Armor Class against that creature. This bonus to her Armor Class lasts until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Dex 17, Divine Fighting Technique, Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot, base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Optional Advanced Prerequisites: A lawful good ranger has the Divine Fighting Technique feat can replace the bonus feat granted by his combat style at 10th level with the following advanced benefit without meeting its prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): When you fire a distracting shot at a creature and hit the creature, you grant a +4 Armor Class bonus to the selected adjacent ally and a +2 Armor Class bonus to all other allies within 30 feet of the selected adjacent ally against attacks by the targeted creature.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): A number of times per day equal to your Wisdom bonus, you can feast upon the life essence of a creature that you hit with a scythe. Activating this ability is a swift action. When you do so, you gain a number of temporary hit points equal to the damage you dealt with the scythe attack. These temporary hit points last for 1 minute and don&apos;t stack.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Divine Fighting Technique, Heal 10 ranks, base attack bonus +7.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): A number of times per day equal to your Wisdom bonus, you can exacerbate any lingering contagions within a target&apos;s body upon making a successful melee attack with a scythe. Activating this ability is a swift action, and causes the target to immediately attempt additional saving throws against all diseases with which it is currently afflicted. Any failed saves cause the target to immediately take the effects of that disease, while a successful save does not count toward the number of consecutive saves that the target must succeed at in order to cure the disease.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): Whenever you threaten a critical hit with a light mace or heavy mace on a foe, that foe becomes sickened for 1 round. If you confirm the critical hit, the sickened effect lasts for 2 rounds. The duration of the sickened effect doesn&apos;t stack with multiple critical threats.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Int 13; Combat Expertise; Divine Fighting Technique; Improved Feint; base attack bonus +10 or Bluff 10 ranks.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): An opponent that you hit with a light mace or heavy mace who is denied his Dexterity bonus to AC is also hindered by the attack. You can attempt a dirty trickcombat maneuver check as a swift action that doesn&apos;t provoke an attack of opportunity immediately after damage from the attack is resolved.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): You take no penalty on attack rolls for using a scimitar to deal nonlethal damage. If your attack with the scimitar would normally deal additional damage (such as via sneak attack, the f laming weapon special ability, or the like), this additional damage can be nonlethal damage. You can also alter spells with the fire, good, or light descriptor and inflict spells so that the damage they deal is nonlethal damage instead. You can choose to apply this effect as the spell is cast.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Great Fortitude, Weapon Focus (scimitar), Heal 10 ranks.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): Once per round as you strike a foe with a weapon and deal nonlethal damage with that attack, you regain 1d6 hit points.</p>
			<p>If the attack that dealt nonlethal damage was from a scimitar, you instead regain 2d6 hit points. You can gain the benefit of this healing only once per round, regardless of how many successful attacks you make with the weapon.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): Whenever you wield a warhammer, add your Wisdom bonus to the total number of attacks of opportunity that you can make per round. These additional attacks of opportunity don&apos;t stack with those granted by Combat Reflexes, but this benefit counts as Combat Reflexes for the purpose of satisfying feat prerequisites and prestige class requirements. In addition, you can make attacks of opportunity while you&apos;re flat-footed.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Divine Fighting Technique, Vital Strike, Weapon Focus (warhammer), base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): Once per round, before you make an attack of opportunity with a warhammer, you can declare an opportunistic strike. If the attack hits, you can apply the effects of your Vital Strike feat. You can apply the Improved Vital Strike or Greater Vital Strike feat instead if you have either of those feats. If you confirm a critical hit with an opportunistic strike, you can attempt a disarm or tripcombat maneuver check against the target as a free action&#x2014;this combat maneuver does not provoke an attack of opportunity.</p>
			<p>Optional Prerequisites: A lawful neutral brawler or monk can replace a bonus feat with the following initial benefit.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): You can take a -2 penalty on all attack rolls made with your unarmed strikes in order to deal the average amount of damage with each successful attack instead of rolling your weapon damage. For instance, if your unarmed strike would normally deal 1d4 points of weapon damage, you instead deal 2 points of weapon damage. Apply bonuses and modifiers to this result as if you had rolled your damage normally. You must choose to use this benefit before making an attack roll, and its effects last until your next turn. You do not average additional damage dice (such as those granted by a sneak attack) when using this ability.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Critical Focus; Divine Fighting Technique; Weapon Focus (unarmed strike); base attack bonus +10 or monk level 10th.</p>
			<p>Advanced Optional Prerequisites: A lawful neutral brawler or monk of at least 10th level and has the Divine Fighting Technique feat can replace a bonus feat with the following advanced benefit without meeting its prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): You no longer take a -2 penalty on attack rolls with your unarmed strikes when you choose to deal the average amount of damage. If you critically hit a creature when using this ability, you automatically inflict maximum weapon damage for that critical hit (although you must still roll sneak attackdice or any other dice-based additional damage).</p>
			<p>Optional Prerequisites: A chaotic good bard of at least 2nd level can replace a versatile performance with the following initial benefit.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): You can add your Charisma bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls when wielding a starknife. If you do so, you don&apos;t modify attack rolls and damage rolls with your starknife with your Strength modifier, your Dexterity modifier (if you have Weapon Finesse), or any other ability score (if you have an ability that allows you to modify attack rolls and damage rolls with that ability score).</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Dex 17; Divine Fighting Technique; Point-Blank Shot; Rapid Shot; base attack bonus +11 or Sleight of Hand 11 ranks.</p>
			<p>Optional Advanced Prerequisites: A chaotic good bard of at least 10th level can replace a versatile performance with the following advanced benefit without meeting its prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): You can impart a powerful spin to a thrown starknife so that multiple blades strike the target rather than just a single blade of the four, dealing extra damage with the other blades. As a full-round action, you can make a single attack with a thrown starknife, rolling 1d4 to determine how many effective strikes you gain with the attack (if you roll a 1, then only one blade strikes). If the attack hits, all of the effective strikes damage the target. Apply precision-based damage (such as sneak attack damage) and critical hit damage only once for this attack. The damage bonus from your appropriate ability score modifier applies to each strike, as do other damage bonuses, such as a bard&apos;sinspire competence bonus. Damage Reduction and resistances apply separately to each strike.</p>
			<p>Optional Prerequisites: A neutral evil rogue of at least 2nd level can replace a rogue talent with the following initial benefit.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): Whenever you attack an opponent that is completely unaware of your presence (such as when you are using the Stealth skill or invisible), your attack deals damage as if you were one size category larger. This benefit applies only to the first attack that you make against the target, and only with attacks made with light or one-handed weapons intended for creatures of your size (including thrown attacks).</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Divine Fighting Technique, Stealth 10 ranks.</p>
			<p>Optional Advanced Prerequisites: A neutral evil rogue of at least 10th level can replace an advanced rogue talent with the following advanced benefit without meeting its prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): At the start of each round, choose one opponent that you can see and attempt a Stealth check as a swift action. If the result of your check exceeds the target&apos;s CMD, treat the target as if it were completely unaware of your presence for the purpose of the initial benefit of this divine fighting technique. If you beat the target&apos;s CMD by 5 or more, you also treat it as being completely unaware of your presence for the purposes of all class features and feats you have.</p>
			<p>Initial Benefit(s): Whenever you succeed at a dirty trickcombat maneuver check against an opponent, you deal an amount of nonlethal damage equal to 1d6 + your Charisma modifier. In addition, whenever your dirty trickcombat maneuver check beats an opponent&apos;s CMD by 5 or more, you can forgo increasing the duration of your condition by 1 or more rounds to instead impose a -2 penalty on all of that opponent&apos;s Charisma-based checks. This penalty doesn&apos;t stack with itself, and it lasts for a number of minutes equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 minute) or until the target receives any form of magical healing.</p>
			<p>Advanced Prerequisite(s): Power Attack, Divine Fighting Technique, base attack bonus +10.</p>
			<p>Optional Advanced Prerequisite(s): A chaotic evil barbarian of at least 10th level can replace a rage power with the following advanced benefit without meeting its prerequisites.</p>
			<p>Advanced Benefit(s): Anytime you use Power Attack with a great axe or a natural attack, you ignore an amount of the target&apos;s hardness or damage reduction equal to the penalty Power Attack imparts to your attack roll.</p>
			<p>This benefit stacks with Penetrating Strike and Greater Penetrating Strike.</p>
		</Extra>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Djinni Spin" title="Djinni Spin" groups="Combat" description="You can surround yourself with the power of the storm, spinning like a hurricane to unleash a violent blast of electrical energy.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 15, Wis 17, Djinni Style, Djinni Spirit, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 11th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Djinni Style, as a standard action you can spend two Elemental Fist attempts to surround yourself with a whirlwind of electrified air. Creatures adjacent to you take your unarmed strike damage plus the electricity damage from your Elemental Fist and are deafened for 1d4 rounds. A successful Fortitude save (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wis modifier) reduces the damage by half and prevents a target from being deafened.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Djinni Spirit" title="Djinni Spirit" groups="Combat" description="By calling upon the spirits of storms, you can manipulate lightning to protect yourself and buffet your enemies with peals of thunder.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 15, Wis 15, Djinni Style, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +11 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Elemental Fist attempt per day. While using Djinni Style, you gain electricity resistance equal to your base attack bonus or monk level, whichever is higher. While denied your Dexterity bonus to AC you are also denied this resistance. Creatures that take electricity damage from your Elemental Fist attack must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wis modifier) or be deafened for 1d4 rounds. Those who take damage from your Djinni Spin are deafened, even on a successful saving throw.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Djinni Style" title="Djinni Style" groups="Combat" description="Your hands sheathed in an auras of lightning, you move like the wind.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Wis 15, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Elemental Fist attempt per day. While you are in this style you must use Elemental Fist to deal electricity damage and you gain a bonus on electricity damage rolls equal to your Wisdom bonus. Further, while you are using this style and have remaining Elemental Fist attempts, you also gain a +2 dodge bonus to Armor Class against attacks of opportunity. A condition that makes you lose your Dexterity bonus to AC also makes you lose this dodge bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dodge" title="Dodge" groups="Combat" description="Your training and reflexes allow you to react swiftly to avoid an opponents&apos; attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 dodge bonus to your AC. A condition that makes you lose your Dex bonus to AC also makes you lose the benefits of this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dolphin Circle" title="Dolphin Circle" groups="Combat" description="You circle your foes like dolphins, forcing them to play into your attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Dolphin Dart, Dolphin Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Swim 10 ranks, base attack bonus +10 or monk level 10th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While in Dolphin Style, as a full-round action underwater you can choose a circular path starting and ending in your current space whose length is no longer than you could swim with a single move action. You circle around that path until your next turn, and this movement doesn&apos;t provoke attacks of opportunity. You are considered to be in every space along the path for the purpose of threatening squares and providing flanking for other allies (but not yourself), as well as whether you are in the area of an area effect. Other creatures can attack you (and touch you with beneficial touch spells) as if you were in every space along the path. However, you don&apos;t count as being in any of the spaces for the purpose of other creatures moving through an occupied space. At the beginning of your next turn, choose any space along the path to stop circling.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dolphin Dart" title="Dolphin Dart" groups="Combat" description="Like a dolphin, you can quickly dart at a foe and retreat.">
		<Prerequisites>Dolphin Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Swim 6 ranks, base attack bonus +6 or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While in Dolphin Style, as a standard action underwater you can move up to half your swim speed, make a single melee attack against a creature within your reach, and then retreat back to your previous position. Your movement and attack don&apos;t provoke attacks of opportunity, even if your foe has an ability that allows attacks of opportunity with triggers other than moving out of a threatened area.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dolphin Style" title="Dolphin Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You fight like a dolphin, bunching your enemies up together to make it easier to pick them off.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Swim 3 ranks, base attack bonus +3 or monk level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on melee attack rolls against any creature adjacent to at least two of its other allies as long as you aren&apos;t flanking that creature, and your melee attacks ignore any bonus to AC gained by use of the aid another action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Domain Strike" title="Domain Strike" groups="Combat" description="You unleash a domain power upon your enemy as part of your unarmed strike.">
		<Prerequisites>Domain class feature, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you gain this feat, choose one domain-granted power that you can use to affect no more than one opponent. If you make a successful unarmed strike against an opponent, in addition to dealing your unarmed strike damage, you can use a swift action to deliver the effects of the chosen granted power to that opponent. Doing so provokes no attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you take it, you apply it to a different qualifying domain power.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Domino Crash" title="Domino Crash" groups="Combat" description="You knock your opponents into each other, using one enemy to shove aside another.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Reposition, Whipcrack, base attack bonus +6 or monk level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully reposition an opponent, if you attempt to reposition it into a square already occupied by another creature, you can attempt a combat maneuver check as an immediate action to reposition that creature.</p>
			<p>You take a -4 penalty on this check. If you are successful, the second creature is pushed 5 feet in the direction of your original target&apos;s movement. You can move the secondary target an additional 5 feet for every 5 by which you exceed the secondary target&apos;s CMD. The secondary target does not provoke attacks of opportunity because of this movement unless you have the Greater Reposition feat. If you fail your combat maneuver check, the movement of your original target ends in front of the secondary target.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can&apos;t reposition a creature into a square that is occupied by a solid object or obstacle.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dorn-Dergar Master" title="Dorn-Dergar Master" groups="Combat" description="You can use a dorn-dergar with only one hand.">
		<Prerequisites>Two-Weapon Fighting, base attack bonus +4, proficiency with the dwarven dorn-dergar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use a dorn-dergar as a one-handed weapon. When using it one-handed, changing whether it&apos;s a normal or reach weapon is a full-round action. If you have the Darting Viper feat, changing its reach is a move action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A dorn-dergar requires two hands to wield.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Double Slice" title="Double Slice" groups="Combat" description="Your off-hand weapon while dual-wielding strikes with greater power.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Two-Weapon Fighting.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Add your Strength bonus to damage rolls made with your off-hand weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You normally add only half of your Strength modifier to damage rolls made with a weapon wielded in your off-hand.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Draconic Aspect" title="Draconic Aspect" groups="Kobold" description="You possess some of the qualities of your dragon ancestors.">
		<Prerequisites>Kobold.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your scales take on the color and some of the resistances of one of the chromatic dragons. Choose one of the following chromatic dragon types: black (acid), blue (electricity), green (acid), red (fire), or white (cold). Your scales take on the color of that dragon, and you gain resistance 5 to the dragon color&apos;s corresponding energy type.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the dragon-scaled racial trait, your scale color does not change and you gain a +1 natural armor bonus instead.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Draconic Paragon" title="Draconic Paragon" groups="Kobold" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Draconic Aspect, Draconic Breath, Draconic Glide, character level 10th, kobold.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain an additional +2 bonus against sleep and paralysis effects. You can use your breath weapon twice per day and your breath weapon damage increases to 4d6 points of energy damage. Your wings from the Draconic Glide feat grow stronger, granting you a fly speed of 20 feet (average maneuverability).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Drag Down" title="Drag Down" groups="Combat" description="When you are knocked prone, you are skilled at bringing your opponent down with you.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Trip.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever an opponent successfully trips you, you can attempt to trip that opponent as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragon Ferocity" title="Dragon Ferocity" groups="Combat" description="You attack with the strength of a dragon, your telling blows striking fear into your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Improved Unarmed Strike, Dragon Style, Stunning Fist, Acrobatics 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Dragon Style, increase your Strength bonus on unarmed strike damage rolls by an additional one-half your Strength bonus, to a total of double your Strength bonus on the first attack and 1-1/2 times your Strength bonus on the other attacks.</p>
			<p>When you score a critical hit or a successful Stunning Fist attempt against an opponent while using this style, that opponent is also shaken for a number of rounds equal to 1d4 + your Strength bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Taking this feat allows you to qualify for the Elemental Fist feat even if you do not meet that feat&apos;s prerequisites. If you do not meet that feat&apos;s prerequisites, you must choose one of the damage types that feat offers, and you can use only that damage type with your Elemental Fist attacks until you meet the feat&apos;s normal prerequisites. A monk with this feat can use Elemental Fist as if he were a monk of the four winds.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragon Roar" title="Dragon Roar" groups="Combat" description="The spirit of the dragon wells up inside you and bursts forth in a mighty roar.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Improved Unarmed Strike, Dragon Style, Stunning Fist, Acrobatics 8 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Stunning Fist attempt per day. While using Dragon Style, as a standard action you can expend two Stunning Fist attempts to unleash a concussive roar in a 15-foot cone. Creatures caught in the cone take your unarmed strike damage and become shaken for 1d4 rounds. A successful Will save (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wis modifier) reduces the damage by half and prevents a target from being shaken.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the Elemental Fist feat, you can expend a daily use of that feat to deal your Elemental Fist damage to those caught in the cone. This damage is not halved even on a save.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragon Shot" title="Dragon Shot" groups="Combat, Grit" description="You instinctively channel your latent magical abilities through your firearm.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Gunslinger feat or grit class feature, Spellcraft 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can spend 1 grit point to convert your gun&apos;s damage into acid, fire, electricity, or cold damage for 1 round. You can choose a different damage type each time you use this ability. This still counts as a ranged weapon attack for critical hit multipliers and abilities such as Deadly Aim.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragon Style" title="Dragon Style" groups="Combat" description="You call upon the spirit of dragonkind, gaining greater resilience, mobility, and fierceness from the blessing of these great beings.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against sleep effects, paralysis effects, and stunning effects. You ignore difficult terrain when you charge, run, or withdraw. You can also charge through squares that contain allies. Further, you can add 1-1/2 times your Strength bonus on the damage roll for your first unarmed strike on a given round.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You cannot charge or run through difficult terrain, and you cannot charge through a square that contains an ally. With an unarmed strike, you usually add your Strength bonus on damage rolls.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragonfly Flight" title="Dragonfly Flight" groups="Combat" description="You can fly short distances through the air.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Wis 15, Dragonfly Style, Dragonfly Wings, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 10 ranks, Climb 10 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Dragonfly Style, you can attempt an Acrobatics check to high jump as a move action, and then immediately glide as the spell for 1 round. If you have not used your standard action after using Dragonfly Flight to make a high jump and start gliding, you can charge while gliding. This charge follows the rules for charging when you are only able to take a standard action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragonfly Style" title="Dragonfly Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You can leap off walls and objects to strike from above.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 2 ranks, Climb 2 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You add your Wisdom modifier to Acrobatics checks in addition to your Dexterity modifier. While using this style, when you are adjacent to a vertical surface or object capable of supporting your weight, such as a wall or a tree, you gain a +1 bonus on melee attack rolls against opponents your size or smaller, as if you were on higher ground.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragonfly Wings" title="Dragonfly Wings" groups="Combat" description="You can jump off willing allies and unwilling opponents to attack creatures from above.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Wis 15, Dragonfly Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 5 ranks, Climb 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Dragonfly Style, the bonus on your melee attacks increases to +2 and applies to opponents up to two size categories larger than you. In addition, you can substitute a creature your size or larger in place of a vertical surface. You can freely use a willing creature in such a manner, but using a hostile creature requires a successful Acrobatics check with a DC equal to the creature&apos;s CMD. If you fail this check by 5 or more, you provoke an attack of opportunity from the hostile creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dragonslayer" title="Dragonslayer" groups="Combat" description="You have been trained to fight dragons.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (arcana) 4 ranks, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you confirm a critical hit against an opponent that has a breath weapon, you can forgo the extra critical damage to instead prevent your foe from using its breath weapon for a number of rounds equal to twice the critical multiplier of your attack, in addition to any normal delay mentioned in the breath weapon effect&apos;s description.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Draining Strike" title="Draining Strike" groups="Combat" description="With a well-aimed strike, you cause your target to become fatigued or exhausted.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You must declare that you are using this feat before you make your attack roll (thus, a failed attack roll ruins the attempt). Draining Strike forces a foe that was damaged by your unarmed attack to attempt a Fortitude saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier), in addition to dealing damage normally. A defender who fails this saving throw is fatigued for 1 minute or until the foe is subject to any spell or effect that heals hit point damage. If you have a base attack bonus of +14 or higher, the target is exhausted for the same duration instead. You can attempt to use Draining Strike once per day for every 4 character levels you have, but you can use it no more than once per round. Constructs, incorporeal creatures, plants, undead, and creatures that are immune to critical hits cannot be affected by this ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dramatic Display" title="Dramatic Display" groups="Combat, Performance" description="Your skill with your weapon is obvious to enemies and onlookers alike.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you spend a swift action to make a performance check, you exude an aura of awe-inspiring skill. You gain a +2 bonus on your performance check, and gain a +2 bonus on all attack rolls and combat maneuver checks until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dramatic Slam" title="Dramatic Slam" groups="Combat" description="Your brutal maneuvers shock any who would dare to stand against you.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike, Savage Slam, Weapon Focus, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Savage Slam, if you succeed at your grapple combat maneuver check to knock the opponent prone, you can spend a swift action to attempt an Intimidate check to demoralize foes within 30 feet who could see your attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dreadful Carnage" title="Dreadful Carnage" groups="Combat" description="Slaying an enemy demoralizes your other nearby foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Power Attack, Furious Focus, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you reduce an enemy to 0 or fewer hit points, you can make an Intimidate check to demoralize all enemies within 30 feet as a free action. Enemies that cannot see both you and the enemy you reduced to 0 or fewer hit points are unaffected.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Drow Nobility" title="Drow Nobility" groups="Drow" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Able to use drow spell-like abilities, drow.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You may use detect magic as a spell-like ability at will, and add feather fall and levitate to the spell-like abilities that you may use once each per day. Your caster level is equal to your character level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Drunken Brawler" title="Drunken Brawler" groups="Combat" description="You have learned how to fight effectively while drunk.">
		<Prerequisites>Endurance, worshiper of a good deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you drink a tankard of ale or strong alcohol, you take a -2 penalty on Reflex saving throws, but gain a number of temporary hit points equal to your character level, and gain a +2 alchemical bonus on Fortitude and Will saving throws. These bonuses last 1 hour or until the temporary hit points gained by this effect are lost, whichever occurs first. Regardless, the penalty lasts for a full hour.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dueling Cape Deed" title="Dueling Cape Deed" groups="Combat, Panache" description="You can use a simple cape to guard yourself and confound your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Sleight of Hand 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a move action, you can wrap a cape that you&apos;re wearing around your arm (removing it if necessary), and treat it as a buckler. If you are using the cape in this way, and an opponent misses you with a melee attack, as an immediate action you can spend 1 panache point to release your cape from your arm and entangle your foe in it. The foe can free it by using a full-round action to escape or by destroying the cape; a typical cape has hardness 1 and 3 hit points. You can use this feat with items similar in shape and weight to a cape, such as a cloak or a curtain.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dueling Disciple" title="Dueling Disciple" groups="Combat" description="Your pride and prowess in the art of swordplay grants you both bravery and bravado.">
		<Prerequisites>Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 morale bonus on all Intimidate checks to demoralize opponents, and the DC of any attempt to demoralize you increases by 2. When you&apos;re participating in a duel, these bonuses increase to +4.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: During any combat that is not a duel, you can spend 1 stamina point at the start of your turn to treat the combat as a duel until the start of your next turn for the purpose of gaining the benefits of the Dueling Discipline feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dueling Mastery" title="Dueling Mastery" groups="Combat" description="You have mastered the impenetrable fighting style.">
		<Prerequisites>Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Quick Draw, Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on initiative checks as long as you start combat with a dueling sword in your hand. As long as you wield only a single dueling sword in one hand (not using a shield, an off-hand weapon, armor spikes, unarmed strikes, or natural weapons), you gain a +2 shield bonus to your AC. If you wield the sword in two hands, this bonus drops to a +1 shield bonus to AC. Although the dueling sword deals slashing damage, you treat it as if it were also a piercing weapon when determining the effects of weapons used by a duelist or swashbuckler.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dueling Style" title="Dueling Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You have learned the classic dueling stance.">
		<Prerequisites>Alertness, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Style and wielding only a single dueling sword in one hand (not using a shield, an off-hand weapon, armor spikes, unarmed strikes, or natural weapons), when you fight defensively or use Combat Expertise, you gain a +2 bonus on weapon damage rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dueling Style Aegis" title="Dueling Style Aegis" groups="Combat" description="The dueling style is at its strongest when employed in one-on-one duels. Adjusting to a reverse grip and keeping your blade in motion, you parry your rival&apos;s strikes with ease.">
		<Prerequisites>Alertness, Combat Reflexes, Dueling Style, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Style, at the beginning of your turn, you can designate a focused target as a swift action. This designation lasts until the beginning of your next turn, and you take a -2 penalty to your AC against all other creatures&apos; attacks for that duration. As an immediate action while using Combat Expertise or fighting defensively, you can attempt to parry the focused target&apos;s attack. This functions as the swashbuckler&apos;s opportune parry and riposte deed, except that it does not cost panache and you cannot riposte.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dueling Style Conquest" title="Dueling Style Conquest" groups="Combat" description="Defense is now second nature to you, and your blade punishes those who try to attack and fail.">
		<Prerequisites>Dueling Style, Dueling Style Aegis, Alertness, Combat Reflexes, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you attempt to parry an attack using Dueling Style Aegis, you do not take any penalties on the attack roll incurred from using Combat Expertise or fighting defensively.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Duelist" title="Duelist" groups="Combat" description="You trained at an elite fighting school and are skilled at fighting with the falcata and buckler.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (falcata), Shield Proficiency (buckler), Weapon Focus (falcata).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When fighting with the falcata and buckler, your shield bonus to AC increases by +1 and you gain a +2 bonus on Acrobatics checks.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When you make an attack with a falcata using two hands while wearing a buckler, you can spend 3 stamina points to ignore the -1 penalty on attack rolls for using your shield arm to wield a weapon while wearing a buckler and to retain the buckler&apos;s shield bonus for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Duelist of the Falls" title="Duelist of the Falls" groups="Combat" description="You have embraced a method of swordplay known for its elegant, sweeping strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dueling Disciple, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword), base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use a dueling sword to deal damage to a shaken, frightened, or panicked foe, you can add your Dexterity bonus to damage rolls instead of your Strength bonus. If you can already add your Dexterity bonus to damage rolls, you instead gain a +1 competence bonus on damage rolls made with a dueling sword.</p>
			<p>When you attempt a dueling parry during a duel, the penalty on your attack roll to parry is reduced from -5 to -3. To gain these benefits, you must be wielding only a dueling sword (not using a shield, an off-hand weapon, armor spikes, unarmed strikes, or natural weapons).</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When you hit a foe with a melee attack made using a dueling sword, you can spend 4 stamina points to treat that foe as being shaken for the purpose of gaining a bonus from Duelist of the Roaring Falls until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Duelist of the Shroud" title="Duelist of the Shroud" groups="Combat" description="You have embraced a style of swordplay known for circuitous footwork.">
		<Prerequisites>Dueling Disciple, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword), base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When attempting to bull rush or reposition a foe, you gain a +1 insight bonus on the combat maneuver check and a +4 dodge bonus to your AC against attacks of opportunity you provoke. You also gain a +1 insight bonus to your CMD against bull rush and reposition attempts. When you attempt a dueling dodge during a duel, your bonus to AC increases to +6. To gain these benefits, you must be wielding only a dueling sword (not using a shield, an off-hand weapon, armor spikes, unarmed strikes, or natural weapons).</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: By spending 5 stamina points when you attempt a combat maneuver check with a dueling sword, you gain a +4 bonus to your AC against attacks made by that target until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Duelist&apos;s Discipline" title="Duelist&apos;s Discipline" groups="Combat" description="You&apos;ve learned to defend yourself against spell and storm with dazzling flourishes of your weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Alertness, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Focus (dueling sword), base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use Combat Expertise, fight defensively, or take the total defense action, choose a type of saving throw. (You can choose a different type each time you take such an action.) Once per round before attempting a saving throw using the selected save, you gain a +2 bonus on that save. If you have a base attack bonus of +11 or higher, this bonus increases to +3. If you have a base attack bonus of +16 or higher, the bonus instead increases to +4.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Duelist&apos;s Masterstroke" title="Duelist&apos;s Masterstroke" groups="Combat" description="When bypassing a foe&apos;s defenses while feinting, you can deal devastating damage.">
		<Prerequisites>Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Focus (dueling sword), base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per round when you hit a foe you have successfully feinted against via a melee attack using a dueling sword, you deal an extra 2d6 points of precision damage. When your base attack bonus reaches +11, this damage bonus increases to +3d6, and at base attack bonus +16, it increases to +4d6. This precision damage does not stack with damage from sneak attack, a vigilante&apos;s sudden strike, or similar effects. Any effect which protects against sneak attack damage also protects against this additional damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dwarf Blooded" title="Dwarf Blooded" groups="Oread" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Oread.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your dwarven heritage manifests in two ways. First, your speed is never modified by armor or encumbrance, as the dwarf slow and steady racial trait. Second, you gain the stonecunning dwarf racial trait.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dwarven Fury" title="Dwarven Fury" groups="Combat" description="You can channel your hatred against many opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Dwarven Hatred Style, Dwarven Seething, base attack bonus +7, defensive training and hatred racial traits, Medium size.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Dwarven Seething, you can maintain bonuses from both your defensive training racial trait and hatred racial trait&apos;s against any number of opponents.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dwarven Hatred Style" title="Dwarven Hatred Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You harness hatred into ferocity.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, defensive training and hatred racial traits, Medium size.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You apply your hatred racial trait&apos;s bonus on both attack rolls and weapon damage rolls against creatures of the appropriate type or subtype and increase the bonus to +2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Dwarven Seething" title="Dwarven Seething" groups="Combat" description="Your hatred drives every swing of your weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Dwarven Hatred Style, base attack bonus +5, defensive training and hatred racial traits, Medium size.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Dwarven Hatred Style, when an opponent hits you with an attack (including a spell that requires an attack roll), you can apply your defensive training or your hatred racial trait bonus (your choice) against that target, regardless of the opponent&apos;s type or subtype, as an immediate action.</p>
			<p>This ability lasts until the opponent dies, the combat ends, you change styles, or you designate a different opponent with this ability, whichever occurs first.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Earth Child Binder" title="Earth Child Binder" groups="Combat" description="Even the greatest giants fear your technique.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, dwarf or gnome, defensive training racial trait, Earth Child Style, Earth Child Topple, Greater Trip, Improved Trip, Improved Unarmed Strike, Stunning Fist, Acrobatics 9 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can trip a creature of the giant subtype no matter its size. While you are using Earth Child Style, when a prone creature of the giant subtype stands up and provokes an attack of opportunity from you, if you make an unarmed strike, you can declare you are making a Stunning Fist attempt after the attack hits. You gain a +4 bonus to the DC of any Stunning Fist effect you deliver in this way.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only trip opponents who are one size category larger than you.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Earth Child Style" title="Earth Child Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your martial training makes you a dangerous and elusive target for giants.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, dwarf or gnome, defensive training racial trait, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, your defensive training dodge bonus to AC increases to +6. Further, against creatures of the giant subtype, you can add your Wisdom bonus on your unarmed strike damage rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Earth Child Topple" title="Earth Child Topple" groups="Combat" description="Your mastery of balance and momentum allows you to bring down giants with your bare hands.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, dwarf or gnome, defensive training racial trait, Earth Child Style, Improved Trip, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can trip a creature of the giant subtype of up to Huge size. While using Earth Child Style, you add your Wisdom bonus on combat maneuver checks made to trip a creature of the giant subtype, as well as on attack rolls to confirm a critical hit against such a creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can trip only those opponents that are one size category larger than you.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Eclectic" title="Eclectic" groups="Human" description="You have a talent for picking up different vocations.">
		<Prerequisites>Human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose an additional favored class and gain either +1 hit point or +1 skill point whenever you take a level in that class. If you choose a class in which you already have levels, the benefits of this feat are retroactive.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Eclipsed Spell" title="Eclipsed Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You alter how your spells affect illumination.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Only spells that create areas of light or darkness can be eclipsed spells. If the eclipsed spell creates an area that shines like a torch or raises the light level by one step, you can choose to have the spell lower the illumination level in the affected area by one step, functioning like darkness. If the eclipsed spell creates an area that shines like daylight or raises the light level by two steps, you can choose to have the spell lower the illumination level in the affected area by two steps and create an area of magical darkness, functioning like deeper darkness.</p>
			<p>If the eclipsed spell lowers the illumination level in the affected area by one step, you can choose to have the spell cause the affected area to glow with normal light, functioning like light. If the eclipsed spell lowers the illumination level in the affected area by two steps, you can choose to have the spell cause the affected area to shed bright light, functioning like daylight.An eclipsed spell does not use up a higher-level spell slot than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Efreeti Stance" title="Efreeti Stance" groups="Combat" description="Calling upon the burning spirits of incarnate flame, you can manipulate fire to protect yourself and immolate your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 15, Wis 15, Efreeti Style, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +11 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Elemental Fist attempt per day. While using Efreeti Style, you gain fire resistance equal to your base attack bonus or your monk level plus any base attack bonus gained from levels in classes other than monk, whichever is higher. While denied your Dexterity bonus to AC you are also denied this resistance. Creatures that take fire damage from your Elemental Fist attack must succeed at a Reflex save (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wis modifier) or catch on fire.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Efreeti Style" title="Efreeti Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your mastery of the unpredictable power of flames allows you to unleash scorching strikes that burn your enemies even when you fail to make contact.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Wis 15, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Elemental Fist attempt per day. While using this style and Elemental Fist to deal fire damage, you gain a bonus on fire damage rolls equal to your Wisdom bonus. Further, if your Elemental Fist melee attack misses while you are using it to deal fire damage, you still deal 1d6 points of fire damage to your target.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Efreeti Touch" title="Efreeti Touch" groups="Combat" description="Your knowledge of the secrets of the burning wind and blazing sun allows you to collect flames into your hands and unleash them in a gout of elemental fire.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 15, Wis 17, Efreeti Style, Efreeti Stance, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 11th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Efreeti Style, as a standard action, you can spend two Elemental Fist attempts to unleash a 15-foot cone-shaped burst of flame. Creatures caught in the cone take your unarmed strike damage plus the fire damage from your Elemental Fist and catch on fire. A successful Reflex save (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wis modifier) reduces the damage by half and prevents a target from catching on fire.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Eidolon Mount" title="Eidolon Mount" groups="Combat" description="Your eidolon is capable of carrying you into combat with great skill.">
		<Prerequisites>Eidolon able to choose quadruped or serpentine as a base form.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your eidolon is capable of serving you as a combat-trained mount. If the eidolon&apos;s base form is not quadruped or serpentine, it also gains the ability to transmute its physical body into a form suitable for you to ride. This functions as the change shape ability, except the eidolon&apos;s base form changes to either quadruped or serpentine and its size changes to be one size category larger than its summoner&apos;s base size. Unlike other changes to size, this ability doesn&apos;t increase the eidolon&apos;s ability scores, reach, or weapon damage beyond that of its true form. (However, if the eidolon&apos;s size is reduced by this ability, its reach and weapon damage are adjusted accordingly.) If the eidolon&apos;s base form is not quadruped or serpentine when it gains this feat, it chooses which base form (quadruped or serpentine) to assume when using this ability. The eidolon cannot choose a base form that is not available to its subtype with this ability. If both base forms are available to the eidolon&apos;s subtype, it can change which base form it assumes when using this ability whenever it gains a new Hit Die. The eidolon can select evolutions that have either base form as a requirement, but any evolutions that require one of the base forms (but not the other) provide no benefit while the eidolon is assuming the shape of its other base form.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Eldritch Claws" title="Eldritch Claws" groups="Combat" description="Who needs magic weapons? Eldritch tricks are no match for your bestial ferocity.">&quot;
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, natural weapons, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your natural weapons are considered both magic and silver for purpose of overcoming damage reduction.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Electric Eel Conduit" title="Electric Eel Conduit" groups="Combat" description="You can establish an ongoing electrical charge between you and a target you have grabbed.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 17, Electric Eel Shock, Electric Eel Style, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Elemental Fist attempt per day. When you successfully grapple a creature, you may expend two uses of Elemental Fist as a swift action to set up an electric charge between yourself and the creature. If you do, the target takes electricity damage equal to 1d6 plus your Wisdom modifier each round you maintain the grapple. This damage ceases when you are no longer grappling the target.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Electric Eel Shock" title="Electric Eel Shock" groups="Combat" description="You can stagger your opponents with jolts of electricity.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 15, Electric Eel Style, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +11 or monk level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Elemental Fist attempt per day. Creatures that take electricity damage from your Elemental Fist attack must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC 10 + half your character level + your Wisdom modifier) or be staggered for 1 round. This also applies to creatures that take electricity damage from your Electric Eel Conduit feat while grappled.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Electric Eel Style" title="Electric Eel Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You have learned how to harness electrical energy to momentarily disorient your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Elemental Fist, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain one additional Elemental Fist attempt per day. While you are in this style, your Elemental Fist attack deals electricity damage. When a creature takes electricity damage from your Elemental Fist attack, you gain a +4 bonus for 1 round on combat maneuver checks to grapple the creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elemental Fist" title="Elemental Fist" groups="Combat" description="You empower your strike with elemental energy.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Elemental Strike pick one of the following energy types: acid, cold, electricity, or fire. On a successful hit, the attack deals damage normally plus 1d6 points of damage of the chosen type. You must declare that you are using this feat before you make your attack roll (thus a failed attack roll ruins the attempt). You may attempt an Elemental Fist attack once per day for every four levels you have attained (see Special), and no more than once per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk of the four winds receives Elemental Fist as a bonus feat at 1st level, even if he does not meet the prerequisites. A monk may attempt an Elemental Fist attack a number of times per day equal to his monk level, plus one more time per day for every four levels he has in classes other than monk.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elemental Jaunt" title="Elemental Jaunt" groups="Ifrit/Oread/Sylph/Undine" description="The spirits of your ancestral home call to you, beckoning you to return.">
		<Prerequisites>Character level 15th, Ifrit, Oread, Sylph, or Undine.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can cast plane shift as a spell-like ability with a caster level equal to your level to transport yourself and willing targets to an elemental plane that is appropriate to your race (ifrits to the Plane of Fire, oreads to the Plane of Earth, sylphs to the Plane of Air, and undines to the Plane of Water). While on that plane, you (but not anyone transported with you) are treated as though under the effect of the spell planar adaptation.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elemental Spell" title="Elemental Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can manipulate the elemental nature of your spells.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one energy type: acid, cold, electricity, or fire. You may replace a spell&apos;s normal damage with that energy type or split the spell&apos;s damage, so that half is of that energy type and half is of its normal type.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (an elemental spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Each time you must choose a different energy type.</p>
		</Special></p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elemental Strike" title="Elemental Strike" groups="Combat" description="You draw upon your extraplanar heritage to imbue your weapons with elemental energies.">
		<Prerequisites>Ifrit, oread, sylph, or undine.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can imbue your weapons with elemental energy. For 1 round, your weapons deal an additional 1 point of energy damage. The type of energy damage depends on your race: acid for oread, electricity for sylph, fire for ifrit, or cold for undine. For every 5 levels you possess, this bonus increases by 1, to a maximum of +5 at 20th level.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can use this feat instead of Arcane Strike to qualify for or attack with the Deadly Dealer feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elephant Stomp" title="Elephant Stomp" groups="Combat" description="You deliver a crushing blow to downed enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, Improved Overrun, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you overrun an opponent and your maneuver check exceeds your opponent&apos;s CMD by 5 or more, instead of moving through your opponent&apos;s space and knocking her prone, you may stop in the space directly in front of the opponent (or the nearest adjacent space) and make one attack with an unarmed strike or a natural weapon against that opponent as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When your overrun maneuver check exceeds your opponent&apos;s CMD by 5 or more, you move through the target&apos;s space and she is knocked prone.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elusive Redirection" title="Elusive Redirection" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Elusive target class feature, Combat Expertise, Improved Unarmed Strike, flowing monk level 12th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully use your elusive target class feature to avoid taking damage, you can spend an immediate action and an additional point from your ki pool to redirect that attack back at your attacker or toward any other opponent adjacent to you and your attacker. This attack uses the same attack roll as the original attack, but it targets the opponent you choose.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elven Accuracy" title="Elven Accuracy" groups="Combat" description="Your sharp eyesight makes difficult shots easier.">
		<Prerequisites>Elf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you miss due to concealment when making a ranged attack with a longbow or shortbow (including composite bows), you can reroll your miss chance roll one time to see if you actually hit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elven Battle Focus" title="Elven Battle Focus" groups="Combat" description="Your fighting style is enhanced by your keen intellect.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Elven Battle Style, Elven Battle Training, Weapon Finesse, base attack bonus +4, weapon familiarity racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Elven Battle Style, you can add your Intelligence modifier to that weapon&apos;s damage (instead of any other ability bonus or modifier you can add to your weapon damage). The weapon must be one appropriate for your size.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elven Battle Style" title="Elven Battle Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You wield traditional elven weapons with grace.">
		<Prerequisites>Elven Battle Training, Weapon Finesse, base attack bonus +1, weapon familiarity racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While wielding a longsword, a rapier, or any melee weapon that has &apos;elven&apos; in its name, combat maneuver checks attempted with that weapon as attacks of opportunity don&apos;t themselves provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elven Battle Torrent" title="Elven Battle Torrent" groups="Combat" description="You rapidly counter enemy attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Elven Battle Focus, Elven Battle Style, Elven Battle Training, Weapon Finesse, base attack bonus +10, weapon familiarity racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Elven Battle Style, any opponent that makes an attack against you and misses while you are fighting defensively or using total defense or the Combat Expertise feat provokes an attack of opportunity from you.</p>
			<p>Even if you have Combat Reflexes, you can&apos;t benefit from this feat more than once per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elven Battle Training" title="Elven Battle Training" groups="Combat, Elf" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, elf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You have received special training with traditional elven weapons (longbows, composite longbows, longswords, rapiers, shortbows, composite shortbows, and any weapon with the word &apos;elven&apos; in its name). You receive a +2 bonus to your CMD against disarm and sunder maneuvers directed at one of these weapons you are wielding. In addition, if you are wielding one of these melee weapons, you may make an additional attack of opportunity each round (this bonus stacks with Combat Reflexes).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Elven Spirit" title="Elven Spirit" groups="Half-Elf" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Half-elf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You possess the elven magic racial trait of the elves, granting you a +2 racial bonus on caster level checks made to overcome spell resistance. In addition, you receive a +2 racial bonus on Spellcraft checks made to identify the properties of magic items. Alternatively, you can instead gain any one racial trait that elves can exchange for the elven magic racial trait.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only take this feat at 1st level. If you take this feat, you cannot take the Human Spirit feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Empty Quiver Flexibility" title="Empty Quiver Flexibility" groups="Combat" description="You can apply your ranged fighting feats to melee attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Empty Quiver Style, Rapid Shot, Stabbing Shot, Weapon Focus with the chosen weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Empty Quiver Style, you can apply any feats and class abilities you possess that modify your ranged attack rolls and damage rolls with the chosen weapon to melee attack rolls and damage rolls made with that weapon. Additionally, you are considered to be threatening the area around you as if you were wielding a melee weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Empty Quiver Flurry" title="Empty Quiver Flurry" groups="Combat" description="You can use your ranged weapons to make melee attacks that keep foes at bay as you shoot them.">
		<Prerequisites>Empty Quiver Flexibility, Empty Quiver Style, Rapid Shot, Stabbing Shot, Weapon Focus with the chosen weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Empty Quiver Style or Stabbing Shot to make melee attacks with a ranged weapon, if you successfully hit a foe, any ranged attacks you make with the same weapon until the beginning of your next turn do not provoke attacks of opportunity from that foe.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the Rapid Reload feat in addition to this feat, your chosen weapon is a crossbow or firearm, that weapon is unloaded, and you successfully hit a foe in melee with it, you can automatically load it as a free action.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Empty Quiver Style" title="Empty Quiver Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You can fight in melee with your bow, crossbow, or firearm.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with the chosen weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you can make melee attacks with the chosen weapon as if it were a heavy mace (or a light mace for melee attack made with a hand crossbow or one-handed firearm), though you don&apos;t automatically threaten the area around you as if you were wielding a melee weapon.</p>
			<p>You can switch between melee and ranged attacks with this weapon without penalty, even during the same round. In addition, you ignore the elf prerequisite for the Stabbing Shot feat.</p>
			<p>If you have the Stabbing Shot feat, you can use it with a crossbow or firearm, substituting a loaded bolt or firearm ammunition for an arrow.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>In addition to the chosen weapon, a character with this feat and the weapon training (bows, crossbows, or firearms) class feature can use Empty Quiver Style with any bow, crossbow, or firearm, respectively.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Encouraging Spell" title="Encouraging Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your inspiration provides your allies with greater support.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Diplomacy 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Any morale bonus granted by an encouraging spell is increased by 1.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (an encouraging spell uses up a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Enforcer" title="Enforcer" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at causing fear in those you brutalize.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidate 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you deal nonlethal damage with a melee weapon, you can make an Intimidate check to demoralize your target as a free action. If you are successful, the target is shaken for a number of rounds equal to the damage dealt. If your attack was a critical hit, your target is frightened for 1 round with a successful Intimidate check, as well as being shaken for a number of rounds equal to the damage dealt.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Engulf Horror" title="Engulf Horror" groups="Combat, Monster" description="The repulsive horror of your smothering attack nearly incapacitates most foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Engulf Revulsion; engulf or smother universal monster ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully engulf or smother an opponent, successfully maintain a grapple combat maneuver on a smothered opponent, the opponent must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your Hit Dice + your Strength modifier) or become staggered for 1 round. This is a mind-affecting fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Engulf Revulsion" title="Engulf Revulsion" groups="Combat, Monster" description="The stomach-churning terror of your smothering attack leaves creatures sick and weakened.">
		<Prerequisites>Engulf or smother universal monster ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully engulf or smother an opponent, or successfully maintain a grapple combat maneuver on an engulfed or smothered opponent, that opponent must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your Hit Dice + your Strength modifier) or become shaken for 1 round. This is a mind-affecting fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Enhanced Ki Throw" title="Enhanced Ki Throw" groups="Combat" description="You enhance the force of your ki throws, enabling you to devastate your opponents as you slam them to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Ki pool class feature, Ki Throw.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using the Ki Throw feat, you can expend 1 ki point to amplify the force of your attack. If your ki throw succeeds, when the target hits the ground, it takes damage as if you had hit it with an unarmed strike.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Enrage Opponent" title="Enrage Opponent" groups="Combat, Panache" description="With a quip or a suggestive gesture, you send your enemy into a tizzy.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Amateur Swashbuckler or panache class feature, Persuasive.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can spend 1 panache point to enrage a creature with an Intelligence of 4 or more within 60 feet that can see or hear you. Attempt an Intimidate check as if to demoralize the creature. If you succeed, the creature takes a -2 penalty to its AC until it has made at least one attack against you (including area effects that include you) or until it can no longer see or hear you.</p>
			<p>You can have only one opponent enraged at you with this feat at a time, and once you&apos;ve enraged a creature, you can&apos;t enrage it again for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Equipment Trick" title="Equipment Trick" groups="Combat" description="Contents">You understand how to use equipment in combat.
		<Prerequisites>
			<p>Base attack bonus +1.</p>
			<p>Choose a piece of equipment, such as anvil, boots, a cloak, rope, a shield, a heavy blade scabbard, a sunrod, or wondrous item.</p>
		</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use any equipment trick relating to the chosen item as long as you meet the trick&apos;s prerequisites. If the item would normally be considered an improvised weapon, you can treat it as either a normal weapon or an improvised weapon, depending on which is more beneficial for you.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain Equipment Trick multiple times. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of equipment.</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (piece of equipment) feat.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:MM</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (anvil) feat. You may use these tricks with any anvil weighing 50 pounds or more.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:DTT</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill prerequisites for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (boots) feat. A pair of boots refers to any set of footwear that has hard soles. These equipment tricks can be used with either magic or mundane boots.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:DTT</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill prerequisites for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (cloak) feat. At the GM&apos;s discretion, you can use these tricks with any cloth object that is roughly the same size and shape as a cloak for a creature of your size (such as a curtain).</p>
			<p>Source PPZO9410</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirement listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (heavy blade scabbard) feat to use a trick. You may use these tricks with any sword scabbard designed for a heavy blade (see the fighter weapon groups). At your GM&apos;s discretion, you may be able to use some of these tricks with a scabbard intended for a light blade, but that requires a separate Equipment Trick feat and may be less effective.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>Bards and other musicians must sometimes improvise more than their music. These instrument tricks expand any musical instrument&apos;s uses and supplement the Equipment Trick feat presented on page 2. Some tricks might be unusable for certain instruments at the GM&apos;s discretion; for example, an organ is too unwieldy to use as an improvised weapon. In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (instrument) feat to use a trick.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>Ladders are not a common adventuring staple due to their cumbersome size.</p>
			<p>Yet some adventurers who take ladders with them into the field use them to great effect. In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (ladder) feat to use a trick.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>Lanterns come in a variety of shapes and sizes. Each of these tricks can be performed with any sort of lantern or lamp, except when a specific kind of lamp is indicated in the description. In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (lantern) feat to use a trick.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>Adventurers carry mirrors for many unconventional uses.</p>
			<p>You may perform the following tricks with a mirror or, at the GM&apos;s discretion, with a similarly reflective handheld item, such as a highly polished piece of metal. In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (mirror) feat to use a trick.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:DTT</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill prerequisites for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (net) feat. To use any of these equipment tricks, you must be proficient with nets.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>Each of these tricks can be done with a pole or balancing pole, but specific poles have further abilities. In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (pole) feat to use a trick.</p>
			<p>Source PCS:PSFG</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirement listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (rope) feat to use rope tricks. Rope tricks can be performed with hemp rope or silk rope, or with similar rope-like items at the GM&apos;s discretion.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO9410</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirement listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (shield) feat and proficiency in (non-tower) shields to use a trick. You may use these tricks with any light or heavy shield. At your GM&apos;s discretion, you may be able to use some of these tricks with a tower shield or buckler, but that requires a separate Equipment Trick feat for that kind of shield and may add a penalty on the associated roll.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:HotF</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (sling) feat.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>Often overlooked for alchemist&apos;s fire, smokesticks can provide versatile tactical advantage in the right hands. In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (smokestick) feat to use the following trick.</p>
			<p>Source PCS:PSFG</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirement listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (sunrod) feat to use a trick.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>Tanglefoot bags can be a versatile and even deadly tool in the hands of a skilled user. In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (tanglefoot bag) feat to use a trick. At your GM&apos;s discretion, you may be able to use some of these tricks with a tangleburn bag, but at the risk of dealing fire damage to connected items or creatures.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:DTT</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill prerequisites for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (thieves tools) feat. Indispensable to a rogue or any other adventurer who wishes to crack open a lock or disable a trap, a set of thieves&apos; tools contains a number of sharp picks and coarse files.</p>
			<p>Source PPZO94102</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirements listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (thunderstone) feat to use the following tricks.</p>
			<p>Source PPC:DTT</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat or skill prerequisites for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (wondrous items) feat. You can use these tricks with any wondrous item that can be worn in a specific magic item slot, such as the body or wrists.</p>
			<p>3rd Party Publisher Bonus Content!</p>
			<p>Source Kitsune Compendium</p>
			<p>In addition to the feat, skill, or other requirement listed for each of these tricks, you must have the Equipment Trick (kitsune star gem) feat to use kitsune star gem tricks. Kitsune star gem tricks can be performed with any kitsune star gem.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Eroding Strikes" title="Eroding Strikes" groups="Combat, Combination" description="With careful, repeated blows, you weaken your foe&apos;s defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with bludgeoning weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you deal damage with a melee attack with a bludgeoning weapon to an opponent you have already damaged this round, you can also reduce the value of that target&apos;s damage reduction by 1 until the beginning of your next turn. This reduction stacks with itself.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Exceptional Pull" title="Exceptional Pull" groups="Combat" description="You have mastered techniques to get the most out of composite bows.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Deadly Aim, base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you wield a ranged weapon that you are proficient with and that has a strength rating, add 2 to the weapon&apos;s strength rating. You don&apos;t take a penalty on attack rolls for having a Strength modifier lower than the strength rating of a weapon, provided you&apos;re proficient with that weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Excoriating Stare" title="Excoriating Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your painful stare burns through your opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 11th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you trigger a painful stare, the target must succeed at a Will saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or become sickened by the pain for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Exhausting Critical" title="Exhausting Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits cause opponents to become exhausted.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, Tiring Critical, base attack bonus +15.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you score a critical hit on a foe, your target immediately becomes exhausted. This feat has no effect on exhausted creatures.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess the Critical Mastery feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Exotic Weapon Proficiency" title="Exotic Weapon Proficiency" groups="Combat" description="Choose one type of exotic weapon, such as the spiked chain or whip. You understand how to use that type of exotic weapon in combat, and can utilize any special tricks or qualities that exotic weapon might allow.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You make attack rolls with the weapon normally.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A character who uses a weapon with which he is not proficient takes a -4 penalty on attack rolls.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain Exotic Weapon Proficiency multiple times. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of exotic weapon.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Expanded Fiendish Resistance" title="Expanded Fiendish Resistance" groups="Tiefling" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Pick one of the following energy types that you do not already have resistance to: acid, cold, electricity, or fire. You gain resistance 5 to that energy type.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you do, pick another energy type you do not have resistance to. You gain resistance 5 to that energy type.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Expanded Hunter Tactics" title="Expanded Hunter Tactics" groups="Combat" description="You&apos;re able to train your allies as you do your animal companion.">
		<Prerequisites>Hunter tactics class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a move action, you can grant a teamwork feat you know to a single ally within 30 feet who can see and hear you. The selected ally gains the benefits of this bonus feat for 1 round plus 1 additional round for every 2 character levels you have, but only while the ally is adjacent to you or your animal companion. A given ally can benefit from this feat only once per day.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Expert Sniper" title="Expert Sniper" groups="Combat" description="Your quick ranged attacks make you difficult to locate.">
		<Prerequisites>Stealth 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You reduce the penalty on your Stealth checks to stay hidden while sniping by 10.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You take a -20 penalty on Stealth checks to stay hidden while sniping.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Explosive Escape" title="Explosive Escape" groups="Combat" description="When you break a grapple, you can send your assailants flying away from you.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Str 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you succeed at a combat maneuver check to break a grapple, you can choose to throw back any enemies participating in the grapple who are up to one size category larger than you. Such foes are thrown 5 feet directly away from you and take an amount of nonlethal damage equal to that of your unarmed attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Explosive Weapon" title="Explosive Weapon" groups="Combat" description="You can channel magical power through your weapon to devastating effect.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcing Weapon, diverse training class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can cast a spell with an area of effect and a duration of instantaneous, such as fireball, and release it through your melee weapon as part of a melee attack. This functions as the magus spellstrike ability, except the spell damage does not multiply on a critical hit, the spell effect is centered on you, and you are excluded from its effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Exsanguinate" title="Exsanguinate" groups="Combat, Monster" description="You drink blood from the living at a furious rate, often draining creatures dry in a matter of seconds.">
		<Prerequisites>Blood drain universal monster ability, grab universal monster ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per round, when you successfully pin an opponent, that opponent takes double the normal damage from your blood drain.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extend Spell" title="Extend Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can make your spells last twice as long.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>An extended spell lasts twice as long as normal. A spell with a duration of concentration, instantaneous, or permanent is not affected by this feat.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (an extended spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extended Combat Meditation" title="Extended Combat Meditation" groups="Combat" description="You are able to glean insight from your momentary meditation for longer than most can.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Combat Meditation, Meditation Master, character level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Add your Wisdom bonus (if any) to the number of rounds that you gain the benefits of your meditation feats when using Combat Meditation.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extra Gnome Magic" title="Extra Gnome Magic" groups="" description="The raw magic that flows through your gnome blood is stronger than normal.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain an additional three uses per day of your gnome spell-like abilities (dancing lights, ghost sound, prestidigitation). You can use these in any combination; for example, you can use dancing lights four times in one day (taking all three additional uses for the same spell), or you can cast ghost sound twice, prestidigitation twice, speak with animals twice, and dancing lights once. If you have a feat, trait, or other ability that changes your racial 0-level spell-like abilities to other 0-level spells, this feat applies to them instead.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extra Grit" title="Extra Grit" groups="Grit" description="You have more grit than the ordinary gunslinger.">
		<Prerequisites>Grit class feature or the Amateur Gunslinger feat.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain 2 extra grit points at the start of each day, and your maximum grit increases by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>If you are a gunslinger, you gain your Wisdom modifier in grit points at the start of each day, which is also your maximum grit. If you have the Amateur Gunslinger feat, you gain 1 grit point at the start of each day, and your maximum grit is equal to your Wisdom modifier.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>If you possess levels in the gunslinger class, you can take this feat multiple times.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extra Hail of Arrows" title="Extra Hail of Arrows" groups="Combat" description="You are a master at raining arrows upon your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Hail of arrows class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use your hail of arrows ability one additional time per day.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you take the feat, you can use this ability one additional time per day.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extra Item Slot" title="Extra Item Slot" groups="" description="You are able to wear magic items more easily than other creatures of your kind.">
		<Prerequisites>Non-humanoid body shape.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one magic item slot not normally available to creatures with your shape. You can now use magic items in that slot.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Feats that are meant for familiars can be switched out for a familiar&apos;s default feats (as listed in the familiar&apos;s statistics) if the familiar meets the prerequisites. Such feat replacements must be made when the PC first acquires a new familiar, and-like all new feats from supplemental sources-the new feats should be approved by the GM before being integrated into play.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extra Panache" title="Extra Panache" groups="Panache" description="You have more panache than the ordinary swashbuckler.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Swashbuckler or panache class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain two more panache points at the start of each day, and your maximum panache increases by two.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have levels in the swashbuckler class, you can take this feat multiple times. Its effects stack.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Extreme Prejudice" title="Extreme Prejudice" groups="Combat" description="Your hatred of a particular type of creature has honed your killer instinct.">
		<Prerequisites>Seething Hatred, sneak attack +3d6, studied target class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you succeed at a sneak attack against a creature you selected as the target of your Seething Hatred feat, you use d8s to roll sneak attack damage instead of d6s.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fabulist" title="Fabulist" groups="Grit" description="You enjoy telling tall tales and gain confidence when others believe them.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Gunslinger feat or grit class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on Perform (act, comedy, oratory, and sing) skill checks, and Perform is a class skill for you. In addition, each time you make a successful Bluff check to convince someone of a far-fetched or impossible story, you regain 1 grit point. Successfully lying to a friendly or helpful creature, or a creature that has fewer Hit Dice than half your character level, doesn&apos;t restore grit.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fabulous Figments" title="Fabulous Figments" groups="Mythic" description="Your illusions are astonishingly realistic.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Focus (illusion).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Non-mythic creatures can&apos;t identify your illusion spells with Spellcraft, including checks attempted as part of arcane sight, detect magic, or similar effects. When mythic creatures attempt to identify your illusions, add your tier to the DC of those Spellcraft checks. Mythic creatures informed by their allies that one of your illusions isn&apos;t real gain only a +2 bonus on their Will saves to disbelieve. Non-mythic creatures gain no bonus to disbelieve.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Faerie&apos;s Strike" title="Faerie&apos;s Strike" groups="Combat" description="Ephemeral wisps of nature spirits dance about those you strike.">
		<Prerequisites>Nature Magic or the ability to cast druid or ranger spells; Vital Strike, Knowledge (nature) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Vital Strike (or Improved Vital Strike or Greater Vital Strike), the creature you hit with the attack must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier) or be illuminated as if by faerie fire for 1 minute. You can use this benefit a number of times per day equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Falling Water Gambit" title="Falling Water Gambit" groups="Combat" description="You have integrated both the Roaring Falls and Shrouded Lake techniques of swordplay into a seamless union.">
		<Prerequisites>Dueling Disciple, Duelist of the Falls, Duelist of the Shroud, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (dueling sword), base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When attacking a creature denied its Dexterity bonus to AC because of your successful feint, you increase the threat range of your dueling sword by 1 (typically to 18-20/x2), and gain a +2 bonus on attack rolls to confirm critical hits. After you make a dueling dodge or succeed at a dueling parry during a duel, you can make an attack of opportunity against the foe who attacked you if that foe is shaken, frightened, or panicked. To gain these benefits, you must be wielding only a dueling sword (not using a shield, an off-hand weapon, armor spikes, unarmed strikes, or natural weapons).</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: By spending 4 stamina points, you gain the ability to attempt a dueling dodge or a dueling parry against attacks made by a shaken, frightened, or panicked opponent, even if you aren&apos;t participating in a duel.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="False Opening" title="False Opening" groups="Combat" description="When you make a ranged attack while threatened, you can fool your opponent into thinking he has an opening.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Dodge, Close Quarters Thrower or Point-Blank Master, Weapon Focus with selected ranged weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a ranged weapon or a thrown weapon. When you make a ranged attack using that weapon, you can choose to provoke an attack of opportunity from one or more opponents who threaten you. You gain a +4 dodge bonus against such attacks. An opponent that makes such an attack and misses you loses his Dexterity bonus to AC against you until the end of your turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Far Shot" title="Far Shot" groups="Combat" description="You are more accurate at longer ranges.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You only suffer a -1 penalty per full range increment between you and your target when using a ranged weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You suffer a -2 penalty per full range increment between you and your target.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fatiguing Stare" title="Fatiguing Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your painful stare fatigues your opponent.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 7th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When a target takes damage from your painful stare, it must succeed at a Fortitude saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or become fatigued for 1 round. This can&apos;t cause the target to become exhausted, even if the target is already fatigued.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fearless Curiosity" title="Fearless Curiosity" groups="Human" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on saving throws against effects with the emotion descriptor. In addition, for any round in which you begin your turn affected by a fear effect, you gain a new save at the beginning of your turn to reduce the severity of the fear effect, from panicked to frightened, frightened to shaken, and shaken to unaffected.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fearsome Finish" title="Fearsome Finish" groups="Combat" description="When you slay enemies, you frighten other opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidating Prowess, worshiper of an evil deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Upon reducing an enemy to 0 or fewer hit points, for the remaining duration of the combat encounter, you gain a +4 bonus on any Intimidate checks made to demoralize opponents who can see both you and the opponent you dropped.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fearsome Spell" title="Fearsome Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells inspire great fear in those harmed by them.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When a creature takes damage from a fearsome spell, if that creature failed its save against the spell, it becomes shaken for a number of rounds equal to the spell&apos;s original level. If the spell doesn&apos;t allow a save, creatures harmed by it can attempt a Will save (against the same DC the spell would have if it did allow a save) to negate the shaken effect. If the spell effect already causes creatures to become shaken, on a failed save, add the duration of this metamagic effect to the duration of the shaken condition imposed by the spell. A fearsome spell can&apos;t cause a creature to become frightened, even if that creature is already shaken.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (a fearsome spell uses up a spell slot 2 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feinting Flurry" title="Feinting Flurry" groups="Combat" description="Your subtle flourishes mislead your enemy, tricking it into changing its footing.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, flurry of blows class feature, Combat Expertise.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using flurry of blows to make melee attacks, you can forgo your first attack to make a Bluff check to feint.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Felling Escape" title="Felling Escape" groups="Combat" description="Through the use of fluid contortions and manipulations of leverage, you can throw your opponent to the ground after escaping a grapple.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Trip.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you break an opponent&apos;s grapple with a combat maneuver check or Escape Artist check, you can spend a swift action to make a trip attempt against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Felling Smash" title="Felling Smash" groups="Combat" description="You commit all your focus to a devastating blow, trying to crush your opponent to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Str 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Trip, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you use the attack action to make a single melee attack at your highest base attack bonus while using Power Attack and you hit an opponent, you can spend a swift action to attempt a trip combat maneuver against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fencing Grace" title="Fencing Grace" groups="Combat" description="Your dashing style and fluid rapier forms allow you to use agility rather than brute force to fell your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Weapon Finesse, Weapon Focus (rapier).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When wielding a rapier one-handed, you can add your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier to that weapon&apos;s damage. The rapier must be one appropriate for your size. You do not gain this benefit while fighting with two weapons or using flurry of blows, or anytime another hand is otherwise occupied.</p>
			<p>In addition, if you have the panache class feature, you gain a +2 bonus to your CMD against attempts to disarm you of your rapier while you have at least 1 panache point.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feral Combat Training" title="Feral Combat Training" groups="Combat" description="You were taught a style of martial arts that relies on the natural weapons from your racial ability or class feature.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Weapon Focus with selected natural weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of your natural weapons. While using the selected natural weapon, you can apply the effects of feats that have Improved Unarmed Strike as a prerequisite.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are a monk, you can use the selected natural weapon with your flurry of blows class feature.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Feral Grace" title="Feral Grace" groups="Animal Companion Feat; Combat" description="The animal's grace and agility are honed for battle, making it a deadly combatant.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Finesse, base attack bonus +3, animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of the animal companion&apos;s natural attack. When the animal companion makes a melee attack with the chosen natural attack using its Dexterity bonus on attack rolls and its Strength bonus on damage rolls, it adds 1/4 of its Hit Dice as a bonus on damage rolls. This bonus damage doesn&apos;t increase or decrease based upon whether the natural attack is a primary or secondary natural attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can select this feat multiple times. Its effects don&apos;t stack. Each time you select this feat, choose a different natural attack to apply its benefit to.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Action" title="Ferocious Action" groups="Orc" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Ferocity racial trait, orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you fall to 0 hit points or fewer, you lose 2 hit points each round, but you are not staggered. If you are in a rage (such as that caused by the barbarian rage class feature), you instead only lose 1 hit point per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Feint" title="Ferocious Feint" groups="Animal Companion Feat; Combat" description="Through training or inborn ability, the animal is naturally skilled at feinting against its foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The animal companion uses half its master&apos;s class level (minimum 1) in place of its Charisma bonus on Bluff checks to feint an opponent. In addition, the animal companion can use Bluff to feint an opponent as a move action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ferocious Tenacity" title="Ferocious Tenacity" groups="Combat, Orc/Half-Orc" description="You spit in the face of death.">
		<Prerequisites>Ferocity racial trait, half-orc or orc, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day when raging, if you are hit by an attack that would deal enough hit points of damage to kill you (negative hit points equal to your Constitution score), as an immediate action you may expend 1 or more rounds of rage to negate some of this damage and keep yourself alive. Each round of rage you spend reduces the attack&apos;s damage by 1 point, but cannot reduce the damage taken below 1 hit point.</p>
			<p>For example, if you are raging, have a raging Constitution score of 18, are currently at 2 hit points, and take 20 hit points of damage from a hit (which is enough to bring you to &#x2013;18 hit points, thereby killing you), you may spend 1 round of rage to reduce the damage by 1 hit point (leaving you perilously close to death at &#x2013;17 hit points); if you spend 17 rounds of rage, you reduce the damage to 1 (the minimum), leaving you with 1 hit point.Note: If this damage still makes you fall unconscious, your rage ends just like it normally would, lowering your Constitution to its normal value and reducing your hit point total as normal. Therefore, it is possible to use this feat to prevent yourself from instantly dying, yet you still die because your negative hit points exceed your normal Constitution score&#x2014;take your normal Constitution into account when deciding how many rounds of rage to spend with this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fiend Sight" title="Fiend Sight" groups="Tiefling" description="Your eyes develop keener sight in dim light and darkness.">
		<Prerequisites>Darkvision 60 ft., tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain low-light vision and your darkvision improves to 120 ft.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat twice. When you take it a second time, you gain the see in darkness universal monster ability.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fiendish Facade" title="Fiendish Facade" groups="" description="You are easily mistaken for a member of another race. Your fiendish physical traits are normally hidden by clothing or appear to be markings of another race.">
		<Prerequisites>Must be taken at 1st level, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +5 racial bonus on Disguise checks when attempting to impersonate a particular race. You must select the race you are able to impersonate when you select this feat, and thereafter you cannot change the race you have chosen. That race must be Medium size.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Filthy Weapons" title="Filthy Weapons" groups="Combat" description="You spread contagion with your weapons by covering their business ends in virulent muck and sewage.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (dungeoneering) 1 rank, Knowledge (nature) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can take a standard action to cover a weapon in decomposing waste, slimy filth, or other virulent agent.</p>
			<p>The next attack with that weapon that succeeds against a foe exposes the target to filth fever. If the attack is a critical hit, the filth fever has an onset time of 1 round, and a save DC equal to 10 + 1/2 your base attack bonus + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Final Embrace" title="Final Embrace" groups="Combat" description="Your coils are particularly deadly, allowing you to constrict opponents of your size or smaller.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Int 3; naga, serpentfolk, or creature that has the constrict special attack as a racial ability; base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the constrict and grab special attacks. Your constrict attack deals damage equal to your unarmed strike or primary natural weapon melee attack. Further, you can grab and constrict opponents up to your size.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can grab and constrict creatures one size smaller than you.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Final Embrace Horror" title="Final Embrace Horror" groups="Combat" description="Your constricting attack has become stronger and more lethal.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Int 3; naga, serpentfolk, or creature that has the constrict special attack; Final Embrace; base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A creature that takes damage from your constrict attack is also shaken until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Final Embrace Master" title="Final Embrace Master" groups="Combat" description="Few creatures can survive the crushing horror of your Final Embrace.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 17, Int 3; naga, serpentfolk, or creature that has the constrict special attack; Ability Focus (constrict); Final Embrace; Final Embrace Horror; base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Double the number of damage dice for your constrict special attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Finishing Cascade" title="Finishing Cascade" groups="Combat, Combination" description="Your blows set up your opponents for a devastating finish.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +11 or monk level 11th; at least one combination feat.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The first time in a round you use a combination feat to apply a reduction or penalty to yourself or an enemy, you can double the feat&apos;s numerical modifier. For example, you can double the reduction granted by Combat Rhythm to -2. This does not double any other effects of combination feats, such as damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fire Tamer" title="Fire Tamer" groups="Goblin" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on saves against spells with the fire descriptor. Additionally, your scars mark you as a talented fire tamer, granting you a +2 circumstance bonus on Diplomacy and Intimidate checks when dealing with other goblins.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Firebrand" title="Firebrand" groups="Combat" description="You can make use of a torch as a deadly, macelike weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Worshiper of Asmodeus</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat a torch as a light weapon that deals bludgeoning damage equal to that of a light mace of its size, plus 1 point of fire damage, and you do not incur penalties as you would for using it as an improvised weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A torch used in combat is treated as a one-handed improvised weapon that deals bludgeoning damage equal to that of a gauntlet of its size, plus 1 point of fire damage.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flagbearer" title="Flagbearer" groups="Combat" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 15.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you hold your clan, house, or party&apos;s flag, members of that allegiance within 30 feet who can see the flag (including yourself ) gain a +1 morale bonus on attack rolls, weapon damage rolls, and saving throws against fear and charm effects. You must hold the flag in one hand in order to grant this bonus. If the standard is taken by the enemy or destroyed, this bonus becomes a penalty, affecting all creatures that the bonus previously affected for 1 hour (or until you reclaim the lost flag).</p>
			<p>A flag is a colorful banner that bears the heraldry or symbol of a nation or organization. A character with the Flagbearer feat who bears a flag can grant additional combat bonuses to nearby allies. Carrying a flag in combat requires a free hand.</p>
			<p>Cost: 10 gp Weight 3 lbs.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: Whenever you can see your flag but aren&apos;t holding it, you can spend 1 stamina point to gain the benefits of Flagbearer for 1 minute as if you were holding it.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flame Blade Dervish Combat" title="Flame Blade Dervish Combat" groups="Combat" description="You move effortlessly when wielding a flame blade.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast flame blade as a spell or spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast flame blade, you gain a +10 enhancement bonus to your base speed as long as the spell persists, along with a +4 competence bonus on all Acrobatics checks. You add your Charisma modifier to damage rolls with your flame blade, and ignore the first 10 points of fire resistance possessed by a creature you hit with the flame blade for the purposes of determining the damage dealt by the flame blade. Against undead foes, you ignore the first 30 points of fire resistance. Immunity to fire still completely protects against damage from your flame blade.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flanking Foil" title="Flanking Foil" groups="Combat" description="Fighting multiple foes is easy for you.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you hit an adjacent opponent with a melee attack, until the start of your next turn, that opponent does not gain any flanking bonus on attack rolls while it is flanking you and cannot deal sneak attack damage to you. It can still provide a flank for its allies.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flaying Critical" title="Flaying Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits weaken your opponents&apos; defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit, your opponent takes a -1 penalty to its natural armor bonus for the duration of the encounter. This penalty is cumulative, but cannot reduce an opponent&apos;s natural armor bonus below 0.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fleeting Spell" title="Fleeting Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells vanish with unusual speed.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>A fleeting spell&apos;s duration becomes dismissible, if it is not already. You can dismiss your own fleeting spell as a swift action. When you dismiss a fleeting spell, its lingering aura cannot be detected by magic unless the caster succeeds at a caster level check against a DC equal to 11 + your caster level. The DC of dispel checks to counter a fleeting spell is reduced by 2, and once active, dispel magic removes a fleeting spell without a caster level check. A fleeting spell has half its normal duration (with an extended fleeting spell, these duration adjustments cancel out). Only spells with a duration of at least 2 rounds can be made fleeting, and instantaneous or permanent spells cannot be fleeting spells.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>It is a standard action to dismiss a dismissible spell, and only spells whose Duration entry is marked with a D are dismissible.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +0 (a fleeting spell does not use up a higher-level spell slot than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flensing Strike" title="Flensing Strike" groups="" description="Your slashing sneak attacks tend to slice away swaths of skin and natural armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Sneak attack +3d6, bleeding sneak attack rogue trick or bleed universal monster ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully inflict sneak attack damage on a foe with a slashing weapon, your attack doesn&apos;t go particularly deep, but you do carve away a significant portion of skin and flesh. If this sneak attack inflicts bleed damage, the victim of the sneak attack is sickened by the pain and has its natural armor bonus (if any) reduced by a number of points equal to the number of sneak attack dice you possess. These penalties persist as long as the bleed damage persists. Multiple strikes on the same foe do not stack the bleed damage, but the penalty to natural armor does stack, to a maximum penalty equal to the target&apos;s normal full natural armor score.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flight Mastery" title="Flight Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can coax the magic of flight from transmutation magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude save bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can cause an item that has a transmutation spell of 2nd level or higher listed in its construction requirements to cast fly. If the item is a suit of armor you are wearing, you can use the item&apos;s enhancement bonus in place of your Dexterity modifier on Fly skill checks while the spell lasts.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat once per day, plus an additional time per day at base Fortitude save bonus +9 and +12.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Flinging Charge" title="Flinging Charge" groups="Combat" description="You hurl a weapon during your charge before drawing a new one to strike, enabling you to make another attack at the expense of the latter attack&apos;s accuracy.">
		<Prerequisites>Quick Draw, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you have a thrown weapon in hand when you begin charging, you can make a ranged attack with that weapon against the target of your charge at any point during your charge. You gain the +2 bonus for charging on the attack roll for this ranged attack. You can then immediately draw a melee weapon during your charge. You take a -5 penalty on the melee attack made at the end of the charge. When charging this way, you cannot use any effect that would grant you more than one attack at the end of your charge (such as pounce), nor can you use abilities that grant you other ranged attacks on a charge, such as the hurling charge rage power.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Aberration Expertise" title="Focused Aberration Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You hold strong against aberrations.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (aberration) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose either Fortitude saves against transformation effects (including transmutation spells and spell-like abilities) or Will saves against mind-affecting effects. You gain a bonus on the selected saving throw equal to half your favored enemy (aberration) bonus. Against aberrations&apos; spells and abilities, you gain this bonus on Fortitude saves against transmutation effects and on Will saves against mind-affecting effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Animal Expertise" title="Focused Animal Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You&apos;re skilled at patiently hiding from your favored enemies, particularly animals.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (animal) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on Stealth checks equal to half your favored enemy (animal) bonus. Against animals, this bonus is equal to your full favored enemy bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Construct Expertise" title="Focused Construct Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at breaking the defenses of constructs and other creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (construct) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your weapon attacks ignore a number of points of damage reduction or hardness equal to half your favored enemy (construct) bonus. This feat allows you to only ignore damage reduction that is normally bypassed by adamantine, bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing weapons. Against constructs, the amount of damage reduction and hardness you ignore is equal to your full favored enemy bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Discipline" title="Focused Discipline" groups="Combat" description="Familiarity with the military traditions of your homeland inspires uncommon valor in you.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on all saving throws against fear effects. Whenever a fear effect targets you and fails to affect you (either because of a successful saving throw or because of immunity to fear), you gain a +2 morale bonus on attack rolls, weapon damage rolls, and CMB checks against the creature that attempted to use the fear affect on you for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points in order to gain the benefit of Focused Discipline for 1 round as if you had been targeted by a fear effect that failed to affect you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Dragon Expertise" title="Focused Dragon Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your understanding of dragons helps you to easily avoid breath weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (dragon) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on saving throws against breath weapons and fear effects equal to half your favored enemy (dragon) bonus. Whenever you succeed at a Reflex saving throw against a dragon&apos;s extraordinary or supernatural ability that would deal half damage, you instead take no damage. If you already have the evasion class feature, you instead gain an inquisitor&apos;s stalwart ability against dragons&apos; extraordinary and supernatural abilities.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Fey Expertise" title="Focused Fey Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your attacks strike true against capricious targets like fey.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (fey) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on attack rolls to confirm critical hits equal to half your favored enemy (fey) bonus. You treat your weapon attacks against fey as cold iron for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction and regeneration.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Magical Beast Expertise" title="Focused Magical Beast Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You move in ways that confound creatures that would strike you repeatedly.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (magical beast) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If a creature makes three or more attacks with natural weapons against you during its turn, you gain partial cover against the third and subsequent natural attacks from that creature. If the creature makes five or more attacks against you with natural weapons, you gain cover (instead of partial cover) against the fifth and subsequent natural attacks. If the attacker is a magical beast, reduce by one the number of natural attacks it must make in order for you to gain cover or partial cover.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Ooze Expertise" title="Focused Ooze Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You&apos;ve learned to avoid and overcome the engulfing attacks of your studied prey.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (ooze) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus to your CMD equal to half your favored enemy (ooze) bonus. You also gain acid resistance equal to half your favored enemy (ooze) bonus. Against oozes, you instead apply your full favored enemy (ooze) bonus for both benefits.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Outsider Expertise" title="Focused Outsider Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You&apos;ve learned to attack in a way that stymies the natural resistances common in outsiders.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (outsider) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your weapon attacks ignore a number of points of damage reduction equal to half your favored enemy (outsider [any one]) bonus. This feat allows you to ignore only damage reduction that is normally bypassed by chaotic-, evil-, good-, or lawful-aligned weapons. Against outsiders that match your favored enemy subtype, the amount of damage reduction and hardness you ignore is equal to your full favored class bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Plant Expertise" title="Focused Plant Expertise" groups="Combat" description="You are quick to dodge and slash anything that would ensnare you.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (plant) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus equal to half your favored enemy (plant) bonus on Reflex saves to avoid being entangled and to your CMD whenever an opponent attempts to grapple you. Your weapons&apos; critical hit multipliers increase by one against creatures with the plant type.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Shot" title="Focused Shot" groups="Combat" description="Your anatomical insight adds deadliness to your shots.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Point Blank Shot, Precise Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you may make an attack with a bow or crossbow and add your Intelligence modifier on the damage roll. You must be within 30 feet of your target to deal this extra damage. Creatures immune to critical hits and sneak attacks are immune to this extra damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Starting at 2nd level, a ranger with the archery combat style may select Focused Shot as a combat style feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Target" title="Focused Target" groups="Combat" description="You pour your entire focus into slaying your chosen target.">
		<Prerequisites>Studied target class feature (second studied target).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you study a target, you can reduce the number of additional targets you can maintain as a studied target. For each target reduced in this way, you increase your studied target bonus by 1 for either attack rolls, damage rolls, skill checks, or the DCs of your abilities. Each such increase must be applied to a different category (attack rolls, damage rolls, skill checks, or DCs). You can end the effects of this feat as a free action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Undead Expertise" title="Focused Undead Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your knowledge of the undead makes you especially effective when fighting them.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (undead) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus equal to half your favored enemy (undead) bonus on saving throws against ability damage, ability drain, energy drain, and negative energy effects. Once per day, when an undead creature&apos;s natural attack against you deals ability damage, deals ability drain, or bestows 1 or more negative levels, you can negate the damage, drain, or negative levels as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Focused Vermin Expertise" title="Focused Vermin Expertise" groups="Combat" description="Your experience with vermin resists the attacks of swarms.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored enemy (vermin) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain DR/&#x2014; equal to half your favored enemy (vermin) bonus against vermin and creatures with the swarm subtype. When attempting Fortitude saves against a swarm&apos;s distraction ability, you gain a bonus on the save equal to the damage prevented by this feat. Against vermin with the swarm subtype, the amount of damage reduction is equal to your full favored enemy (vermin) bonus. This damage reduction does not stack with that from other sources.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Follow-Up Strike" title="Follow-Up Strike" groups="Combat" description="You bat away an opponent&apos;s weapon, creating an opening for a punch or kick.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Disarm, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6 or monk level 6th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you succeed at a combat maneuver check to disarm an opponent, you can spend a swift action to make an unarmed strike attack at your highest base attack bonus against the target you disarmed.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Following Step" title="Following Step" groups="Combat" description="You can repeatedly close the distance when foes try to move away, without impeding your normal movement.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Step Up.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using the Step Up feat to follow an adjacent foe, you may move up to 10 feet. You may still take a 5-foot step during your next turn, and any movement you make using this feat does not subtract any distance from your movement during your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only take a 5-foot step to follow an opponent using Step Up.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Footslasher" title="Footslasher" groups="Combat" description="You are trained to strike at a large foe&apos;s feet to impede its movement and cause great pain.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you damage a foe that is of a larger size category than you with a weapon that does piercing or slashing damage, you can attempt to damage the creature&apos;s feet in a way that impedes its movement. Attacking a foe in this way is a standard action&#x2014;you cannot use Footslasher as part of a full-attack action. When you use Footslasher, you take a -2 penalty on your attack roll, but if you hit and deal at least 1 point of damage to the target, it is affected as if by caltrops&#x2014;its speed is reduced by half. This penalty lasts for 24 hours, or until the creature is successfully treated with a DC 15 Heal check or receives at least 1 point of magical healing. Footslasher does not stack with itself&#x2014;once a foe has been wounded by this attack, its speed cannot be further reduced by additional attacks (or by damage from caltrops).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Forge Ring" title="Forge Ring" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create magic rings.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create magic rings. Crafting a ring takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. To craft a ring, you must use up raw materials costing half of the base price.</p>
			<p>You can also mend a broken ring if it is one that you could make. Doing so costs half the raw materials and half the time it would take to forge that ring in the first place.See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fortified Armor Training" title="Fortified Armor Training" groups="Combat" description="You have learned to let your armor bear the brunt of the worst attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficient with armor or shield.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If an opponent scores a critical hit against you, you can turn the critical hit into a normal hit. If you do, either your armor or your shield gains the broken condition (your choice).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fortuitous Vigor" title="Fortuitous Vigor" groups="Combat" description="Your determination and enthusiasm help you shake off the most grievous wounds and soldier on against your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, Combat Vigor, character level 4th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your vigor pool gains 1 vigor point.</p>
			<p>Whenever you roll a natural 20 on an ability check, attack roll, saving throw, or skill check, and whenever you threaten a critical hit with an attack, you can spend 1 or more vigor points as a swift action to regain hit points as described in the Combat Vigor feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fortunate One" title="Fortunate One" groups="Halfling" description="You have an even greater knack than most halflings for adaptable luck.">
		<Prerequisites>Adaptable luck racial trait, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The number of times per day you can use the adaptable luck racial trait increases by 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Insight" title="Fox Insight" groups="Combat" description="Your foxlike movements protect you from your opponents&apos; attempts to manipulate you.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Fox Style.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Fox Style, you can use your base attack bonus in place of your ranks in Sense Motive to determine your Sense Motive skill bonus when foes attempt to feint against you, and creatures attempting to demoralize you don&apos;t gain a bonus for being bigger than you (though they still take a penalty for being smaller). If your Intelligence score is at least 19, the DC to demoralize or feint you increases by 4.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Shape" title="Fox Shape" groups="Kitsune" description="You can change into a fox in addition to your other forms.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, base attack bonus +3, kitsune.</Prerequisites>
		<Special>
			<p>A kitsune may select this feat any time she would gain a feat.</p>
		</Special>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can take the form of a fox whose appearance is static and cannot be changed each time you assume this form. Your bite attack&apos;s damage is reduced to 1d3 points of damage on a hit, but you gain a +10 racial bonus on Disguise checks made to appear as a fox. Changing from kitsune to fox shape is a standard action. This ability otherwise functions as beast shape II, and your ability scores change accordingly.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Style" title="Fox Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your martial training helps you manipulate foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you can use your base attack bonus in place of your ranks in Bluff on Bluff checks to feint in combat and to create a distraction to hide. If your Intelligence is at least 19, you gain a +4 bonus on such Bluff checks when adding your Charisma modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fox Trickery" title="Fox Trickery" groups="Combat" description="Whenever a foes drops his guard, you can make him suffer with a dirty trick.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise, Fox Insight, Fox Style, Improved Dirty Trick.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Fox Style, you can perform dirty trick combat maneuvers as attacks of opportunity. If your Intelligence is at least 19, you gain a +4 bonus on dirty trick combat maneuver checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Freeze in Place" title="Freeze in Place" groups="Combat" description="You become an expert of hiding in plain sight.">
		<Prerequisites>Stealth 5 ranks, wyrwood.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the freeze universal monster ability, allowing you to appear as an ordinary statue. If you attack a creature unaware of you while using this ability, you double your critical threat range.</p>
			<p>This effect doesn&apos;t stack with any other effect that expands the threat range of your attacks or weapons.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Friendly Face" title="Friendly Face" groups="Animal Companion Feat" description="Other animals of your species adore you. No matter how territorial, ill-tempered, wounded, or hungry they are, they see you as a friend, not an enemy. They'll give your two-legged friend the benefit of the doubt as well.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Other animals of roughly the same kind as you (cats to felines, eagles to raptors, frogs to amphibians, etc.) have their starting attitudes toward you improved by two steps. Their attitudes towards your master are likewise improved by one step.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If your master has the animal focus class feature, this feat also applies to any animals of roughly the same kind as your active animal focus.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Frightening Ambush" title="Frightening Ambush" groups="Combat" description="You are able to leap from hiding and strike great fear in your opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidate 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a free action, you can attempt an Intimidate check to demoralize a flat-footed opponent you attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Furious Focus" title="Furious Focus" groups="Combat" description="Even in the midst of fierce and furious blows, you can find focus in the carnage and your seemingly wild blows strike home.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are wielding a two-handed weapon or a one-handed weapon with two hands, and using the Power Attack feat, you do not suffer Power Attack&apos;s penalty on melee attack rolls on the first attack you make each turn. You still suffer the penalty on any additional attacks, including attacks of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Furious Spell" title="Furious Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spells seethe with the ferocious intensity of your blood-red rage.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>A furious spell that deals hit point damage adds twice the spell&apos;s original level to the amount of damage dealt by the spell. Spells that affect multiple targets deal the extra damage once to each target, regardless of whether the spell deals its damage all at once or in multiple hits (in the latter case, add the extra damage to the first hit against each target). In addition, a furious spell can be cast while the caster is enraged, including during a barbarian rage or while affected by a rage spell. Even a furious spell that requires an emotion component can be cast while enraged. The caster gains a +2 circumstance bonus on concentration checks and caster level checks related to casting a furious spell if she is enraged.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a furious spell uses up a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fury&apos;s Fall" title="Fury&apos;s Fall" groups="Combat" description="You can use strength and agility to send foes crashing to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Trip.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When making a trip attack, add your Dexterity bonus to your CMB.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Fury&apos;s Snare" title="Fury&apos;s Snare" groups="Combat" description="You entangle your foe in your weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Fury&apos;s Fall, Improved Trip.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you successfully use a whip to trip a foe, you can choose to drop your whip. Your tripped target gains the entangled condition. The target can break free of the whip by making a DC 10 Strength check or a DC 15 Escape Artist check (add the enhancement bonus of the whip to these DCs), or by using a full-round action to disentangle himself. Escaping the whip by making a Strength check means the whip gains the broken condition. If the whip has a magical quality such as flaming, apply this quality&apos;s damage to the target every round on your turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gang Up" title="Gang Up" groups="Combat" description="You are adept at using greater numbers against foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Combat Expertise.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You are considered to be flanking an opponent if at least two of your allies are threatening that opponent, regardless of your actual positioning.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You must be positioned opposite an ally to flank an opponent.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gate Breaker" title="Gate Breaker" groups="Combat" description="Your strikes against objects are especially vicious.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Sunder, Power Attack, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you would deal damage to an object, you deal normal damage plus an additional amount equal to your Strength modifier. This applies to both unattended objects and those you damage as part of a successful sunder combat maneuver check.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ghostslayer" title="Ghostslayer" groups="Combat" description="Your blade is keen enough to hew incorporeal creatures.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, Knowledge (religion) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can imbue a weapon you wield with spiritual energies for 1 round. An imbued weapon damages incorporeal creatures as though it were magical. If the imbued weapon has an enhancement bonus of +2 or greater, it functions as a ghost touch weapon.</p>
			<p>A weapon imbued in this way can deal precision damage (such as sneak attack damage) to incorporeal creatures.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Giant-Killer Stance" title="Giant-Killer Stance" groups="Combat" description="You can prepare a crippling strike against larger foes that rush into your weapon&apos;s reach.">
		<Prerequisites>Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can treat any reach weapon you wield as having the brace property against creatures that are Large or larger. If your readied attack hits, the creature takes a -2 penalty on melee attack rolls for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gloom Sight" title="Gloom Sight" groups="Fetchling" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Fetchling</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain darkvision 90 ft., but gain the light sensitivity weakness.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gloomstorm" title="Gloomstorm" groups="Combat, Conduit" description="An inexhaustible arsenal lies in the Shadow Plane, waiting to be unleashed.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (planes) 4 ranks, shadow weapon class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can thin the barriers between yourself and the Shadow Plane, allowing you to create shadow weapons more easily. While this effect is active, you can create new shadow weapons as a free action.</p>
			<p>This does not increase the number of shadow weapons you can maintain at a single time.</p>
			<p>You can use this feat&apos;s benefit for a number of rounds per day equal to your ranks in Knowledge (planes). These rounds need not be consecutive.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Goblin Cleaver" title="Goblin Cleaver" groups="Combat, Dwarf" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Cleave, Power Attack, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Cleave or Great Cleave, if your initial attack hits, you may take your additional attacks against any creature smaller than you that you threaten; your targets need not be adjacent to one another. Additional attacks you make against humanoids (goblinoid) gain a +2 circumstance bonus on attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gore Fiend" title="Gore Fiend" groups="Orc/Half-Orc, Combat" description="Horrible wounds, whether on yourself or your enemies, make your blood sing.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc or orc, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are raging and you confirm a critical hit with a melee weapon or a critical hit is confirmed on you (whether by a melee weapon, spell, or ranged weapon), you regain 1 round of rage (up to your maximum for the day). You can only gain this benefit once per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gorgon&apos;s Fist" title="Gorgon&apos;s Fist" groups="Combat" description="With one well-placed blow, you leave your target reeling.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Scorpion Style, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, make a single unarmed melee attack against a foe whose speed is reduced (such as from Scorpion Style). If the attack hits, you deal damage normally and the target is staggered until the end of your next turn unless it makes a Fortitude saving throw (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wis modifier). This feat has no effect on targets that are staggered.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Gory Finish" title="Gory Finish" groups="Combat" description="By drawing upon wells of savagery, you can slay your foe in creative and horrifyingly gruesome manners, intimidating nearby foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use the attack action, you can use a weapon with which you have Weapon Focus to make a single attack at your highest base attack bonus. If you reduce your target to negative hit points, you can spend a swift action to make an Intimidate check to demoralize all foes within 30 feet who could see your attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
</Bundles>
