<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Bundles>
	<Bundle id="Aberrant Tumor" title="Aberrant Tumor" groups="" description="To the surprise of others, that strange growth on you is actually your spellcasting companion.">
		<Prerequisites>Aberrant bloodline.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a tumor familiar, as the tumor familiar alchemist discovery, with an effective alchemist level equal to the level of the class that grants your aberrant bloodline for determining the tumor familiar&apos;s abilities. If multiple classes grant you the aberrant bloodline, those class levels stack for determining your effective alchemist level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ability Mastery" title="Ability Mastery" groups="Item Mastery" description="You can augment your inherent abilities with transmutation magic items.">
		<Prerequisites>Use Magic Device 3 ranks, base Fortitude saving throw bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can focus your thoughts for 10 minutes on a suit of magic armor or a wondrous item that has a transmutation spell of 2nd level or higher listed in its construction requirements and that occupies a slot on your body. At the end of the meditation, you gain a +2 enhancement bonus to one ability score of your choice. This benefit lasts for 24 hours. You must wear the item in order to gain this benefit; if the item is removed before this feat&apos;s benefit ends, the benefit is immediately lost and cannot be regained until 24 hours have passed since the feat&apos;s last activation. You can gain only one benefit from this feat at a time.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Absorb Spirit" title="Absorb Spirit" groups="" description="You absorb restless spirits into your body at the cost of your own life force and sanity.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, must have died at least once or been possessed by an undead creature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When an incorporeal undead with the rejuvenation special ability or a haunt is reduced to 0 or fewer hit points within 30 feet of you, you can attempt to absorb its spirit into your body as an immediate action. You must attempt a Will save with a DC equal to 5 + twice the CR of the undead creature or haunt. If you are a medium with the haunt channeler class feature, you receive a +2 bonus on this saving throw. If you succeed, you harbor the undead or haunt&apos;s essence, and it cannot continue to rejuvenate or manifest until you release it. For every 24 hours that you harbor the entity, you must attempt a Constitution check (DC = 10 + the CR of the undead or haunt). If you are a medium with the haunt channeler class feature, you receive a +2 bonus on this check. If you fail the check, you take 1d4 points of Constitution and Wisdom damage. If you succeed, you take 1 point of Constitution and Wisdom damage. No effect can prevent or reduce this ability damage, nor can the ability damage be healed or suppressed by any means until you release the spirit. You can release the spirit at any time as a standard action, at which point the spirit returns to its former location and begins rejuvenating or manifesting again as normal. If you die from the Constitution damage, the spirit is released, and if you become comatose from the Wisdom damage, the spirit gains control of your body (and can release itself whenever it desires).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you are using the sanity system and fail your Constitution check while harboring the spirit, you take sanity damage equal to 1/2 the spirit&apos;s CR (minimum 1) instead of 1d4 points of Wisdom damage. If you succeed at the Constitution check, you take sanity damage equal to 1/4 the spirit&apos;s CR instead of 1 point of Wisdom damage.</p>
			<p>Either way, you still take the normal amount of Constitution damage. No effect can prevent or reduce the damage, nor can it be healed or suppressed by any means until you release the spirit.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Abundant Revelations" title="Abundant Revelations" groups="" description="You can plumb the depths of your mystery to use your revelations more often.">
		<Prerequisites>Mystery class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of your revelations that has a number of uses per day. You gain 1 additional use per day of that revelation.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new revelation.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Accomplished Sneak Attacker" title="Accomplished Sneak Attacker" groups="" description="Your strikes against a foe's vital spots are extra deadly.">
		<Prerequisites>Sneak attack class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6.</p>
			<p>Your number of sneak attack dice cannot exceed half your character level (rounded up).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Accursed Critical" title="Accursed Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your spells carry an embedded curse that manifests when they strike true.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, ability to cast bestow curse or major curse, caster level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you confirm a critical hit with a spell or spell-like ability, you may cast bestow curse or major curse on that target as an immediate action. This works even with ranged spells. You must have bestow curse or major curse prepared or otherwise available to cast, and using this ability casts the corresponding spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Accursed Hex" title="Accursed Hex" groups="" description="You can make a second attempt at failed hexes.">
		<Prerequisites>Hex class feature</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you target a creature with a hex that cannot target the same creature more than once per day, and that creature succeeds at its saving throw against the hex&apos;s effect, you can target the creature with the same hex a second time before the end of your next turn. If the second attempt fails, you can make no further attempts to target that creature with the same hex for 1 day. </p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can only target a creature with these hexes once per day.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Acrobatic" title="Acrobatic" groups="" description="You are skilled at leaping, jumping, and flying.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on all Acrobatics and Fly skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Acrobatic Spellcaster" title="Acrobatic Spellcaster" groups="Combat" description="Your skillful movements prevent foes from disrupting your spells.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Casting, Skill Focus (Acrobatics).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you succeed at an Acrobatics check to move through a threatened square without provoking attacks of opportunity or to move through an enemy&apos;s space, creatures denied attacks of opportunity by your Acrobatics check also cannot make attacks of opportunity against you when you cast spells for the remainder of your turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Casting a spell within an enemy&apos;s reach provokes attacks of opportunity even after you succeed at an Acrobatics check to move through a threatened square.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Acrobatic Steps" title="Acrobatic Steps" groups="" description="You can easily move over and through obstacles.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Nimble Moves.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you move, you may move through up to 15 feet of difficult terrain each round as if it were normal terrain. The effects of this feat stack with those provided by Nimble Moves (allowing you to move normally through a total of 20 feet of difficult terrain each round).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Acute Shot" title="Acute Shot" groups="" description="When magic aids your ranged attacks, you rarely miss.">
		<Prerequisites>Far Shot, Precise Shot.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you gain a magic bonus on an attack roll with a ranged weapon, you can deduct any range penalties from your damage roll, instead of your attack roll.</p>
			<p>Additionally, when you gain a magic bonus on a ranged attack roll, you can deal sneak attack damage to a target that has concealment (but not total concealment) as long as the attack otherwise qualifies to deal sneak attack damage. The maximum number of sneak attack dice you can use in this way is equal to the value of your magic bonus on attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Adaptive Fortune" title="Adaptive Fortune" groups="Halfling" description="Your luck takes on almost legendary proportions.">
		<Prerequisites>Fortunate One, adaptable luck racial trait, character level 10th, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Increase the number of times per day you can use the adaptable luck racial trait by 1. Furthermore, when you use adaptable luck, increase the luck bonus for each type of use by 2.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Adder Strike" title="Adder Strike" groups="Combat" description="You can quickly apply poison to gloved hands, protected feet, or other protected body parts, delivering the poison with your unarmed strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Poison use class feature, Craft (alchemy) 1 rank, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can apply one dose of contact or injury poison to two body parts that you use for unarmed strikes. You must still protect yourself against exposure to contact poisons you apply in this way.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Applying poison to a weapon or single piece of ammunition is a standard action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Additional Traits" title="Additional Traits" groups="" description="You have more traits than normal.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain two character traits of your choice. These traits must be chosen from different lists, and cannot be chosen from lists from which you have already selected a character trait. You must meet any additional qualifications for the character traits you choose &#x2014; this feat cannot enable you to select a dwarf character trait if you are an elf, for example.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Adept Champion" title="Adept Champion" groups="" description="You can alter your smite ability, channeling the power of your deity into divine inspiration that grants you greater aptitude for performing combat maneuvers.">
		<Prerequisites>Smite evil class feature, base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using your smite evil class feature, as a swift action at the start of your turn, you can forgo the bonus on damage rolls and instead gain half that bonus as a bonus oncombat maneuver checks against the target of your smite. The effects of your smite evil feature return to normal at the start of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Adept Channel" title="Adept Channel" groups="" description="Some orc adepts enjoy a greater connection to their gods, and can channel their faith through their unholy symbols. You gain the ability to channel energy as a cleric.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the channel energy class feature, as a cleric, usable 2 times per day. This ability otherwise functions like the cleric&apos;s channel energy ability, except that your effective cleric level is equal to your divine spellcasting class level &#x2013;3. Unlike a cleric, however, the number of times per day you may channel energy is not affected by your Charisma modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Advanced Armor Training" title="Advanced Armor Training" groups="Combat" description="You are specially trained to use your armor proficiencies in new ways.">
		<Prerequisites>Armor Training class feature, fighter level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one advanced armor training option.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat can be taken more than once, but at most once per 3 fighter levels.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Advanced Defensive Combat Training" title="Advanced Defensive Combat Training" groups="Combat,Faction" description="You are a master at defending yourself from all manner of combat maneuvers.">
		<Prerequisites>Defensive Combat Training, Faction membership 10 TPA.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +4 bonus to your CMD.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Advanced Ranger Trap" title="Advanced Ranger Trap" groups="" description="Your ranger traps are especially difficult to notice and avoid.">
		<Prerequisites>Trap class feature, ranger level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Add +1 to the Difficulty Class on all Perception and Disable Device skill checks to find or disable the traps you make with your trap class feature. Add a +1 to the Difficulty Class on all saving throws against the effects of the trap you make with your trap class feature.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Advanced Weapon Training" title="Advanced Weapon Training" groups="Combat" description="You are specially trained to use your weapon skills in new ways.">
		<Prerequisites>Fighter level 5th, weapon training class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one advanced weapon training option, applying it to one fighter weapon group you have already selected with the weapon training class feature.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat can be taken more than once, but at most once per 5 fighter levels.</p>
			<p>Fighters that have the weapon master archetype can select this feat beginning at 4th level. The benefits of a weapon master&apos;s advanced weapon training options apply only to his selected weapon rather than all weapons in the same fighter weapon group, and he can&apos;t select the weapon specialist advanced weapon training option. A weapon master can select this feat as a bonus feat; if he does so, it doesn&apos;t count for the purpose of the requirement that it can be taken at most once per 5 fighter levels.</p>
			<p>If an archetype replaces a class ability with a more specific version of that ability (or one that works similarly to the replaced ability), does the archetype&apos;s ability count as the original ability for the purpose of rules that improve the original ability?</p>
			<p>It depends on how the archetype&apos;s ability is worded. If the archetype ability says it works like the standard ability, it counts as that ability. If the archetype&apos;s ability requires you to make a specific choice for the standard ability, it counts as that ability. Otherwise, the archetype ability doesn&apos;t count as the standard ability. (It doesn&apos;t matter if the archetype&apos;s ability name is different than the standard class ability it is replacing; it is the description and game mechanics of the archetype ability that matter.)</p>
			<p>Example: The dragoon (fighter) archetype (Ultimate Combat) has an ability called &apos;spear training,&apos; which requires the dragoon to select &apos;spears&apos; as his weapon training group, and refers to his weapon training bonus (even though this bonus follows a slightly different progression than standard weapon training). Therefore, this ability counts as weapon training for abilities that improve weapon training, such as gloves of dueling (Advanced Player&apos;s Guide), which increase the wearer&apos;s weapon training bonus.</p>
			<p>Example: The archer (fighter) archetype gets several abilities (such as &apos;expert archer&apos;) which replace weapon training and do not otherwise refer to the weapon training ability. Therefore, this ability does not count as weapon training for abilities that improve weapon training (such as gloves of dueling). This is the case even for the &apos;expert archer,&apos; ability which has a bonus that improves every 4 fighter levels, exactly like weapon training.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aerial Roll" title="Aerial Roll" groups="Combat" description="By spinning through the air, you are able to avoid your opponents' attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Fly 10 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can perform a defensive roll while in the air. As an immediate action, you can attempt a Fly check when you are attacked while flying. If the result of the check is greater than the result of the attack roll, you dodge the attack, causing it to miss automatically. Whether you succeed or fail at the Fly check, the barrel roll leaves you off-balance and vulnerable, causing you to take a -10 penalty on Fly checks until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Agent of Fear" title="Agent of Fear" groups="" description="You inspire fear so powerful that it's hard to shake off.">
		<Prerequisites>Persuasive, frightening appearance class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you target a creature with your frightening appearance or stunning appearance class feature, it does not become immune to the effects of those features for 24 hours, but does gain a +2 bonus on the saving throws against those class features for 24 hours.</p>
			<p>This bonus stacks with itself if you use those abilities against the same creature multiple times in the same 24-hour period. Because these abilities alert the creature to your presence, you still can&apos;t use them on the creature again until after the end of that specific combat.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A creature targeted by frightening appearance or stunning appearance becomes immune to the feature&apos;s effect for 24 hours.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Agent of Purity" title="Agent of Purity" groups="Story" description="You have devoted your life to purging blight from the world.">
		<Prerequisites>A friend or ally must have been significantly corrupted by a specific natural or supernatural blight, or you must have a regional background trait tied to a specific blight.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one type of terrain affiliated with the relevant blight. You gain a +1 bonus on Knowledge (geography) and Knowledge (nature) checks regarding the blighted terrain and can attempt those Knowledge checks untrained. You also gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls against creatures corrupted by the relevant blight, and you gain a +1 bonus on saving throws against the abilities of such creatures.</p>
			<p>Goal: Slay or cure at least 50 creatures corrupted by the relevant blight, and then slay a challenging foe closely connected to spreading the blight.</p>
			<p>Completion Benefit: Once per day, you can cast any one of the following spells as a spell-like ability, using your character level as your caster level: consecrate, neutralize poison, remove curse, or remove disease.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Agile Maiden" title="Agile Maiden" groups="Combat" description="Your armor hinders you less than others.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13; Dex 13; Endurance or armor training class feature; proficiency with heavy armor.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>For the purpose of class features (such as a ranger&apos;s combat style, a barbarian&apos;s fast movement, or a magus&apos;s spellcasting), you treat Gray Maiden plate as medium armor or heavy armor, whichever is more beneficial to a given ability. This does not affect the armor&apos;s statistics, and it is still considered heavy armor for all other purposes.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Agile Maneuvers" title="Agile Maneuvers" groups="Combat" description="You've learned to use your quickness in place of brute force when performing combat maneuvers.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You add your Dexterity bonus to your base attack bonus and size bonus when determining your Combat Maneuver Bonus instead of your Strength bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You add your Strength bonus to your base attack bonus and size bonus when determining your Combat Maneuver Bonus.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Agile Tongue" title="Agile Tongue" groups="Grippli" description="Your long pink tongue is capable of manipulating small items and even stealing objects.">
		<Prerequisites>Grippli.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You have a prehensile tongue with a range of 10 feet. You can pick up items weighing no more than 5 pounds, make Sleight of Hand checks, perform the steal or disarm combat maneuvers, or make melee touch attacks with your tongue.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Agonizing Obedience" title="Agonizing Obedience" groups="" description="Contents">
	You physically defile yourself out of zealous devotion to pain in order to gain special boons.
		<Prerequisites>3 ranks in Heal.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you take this feat, select an agony.</p>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times, each time selecting a different agony, but you can perform an obedience for only a single agony in a 24-hour period.</p>
			<p>Each agony requires a different obedience, but all obediences take only an hour to perform. Once the obedience has been performed, you take a number of minor penalties and gain the benefit of a resistance to some element or attack associated with your agony, as indicated below. Additionally, you gain the ability to make an agony strike. A number of times per day equal to 1 + 1 per every 5 Hit Dice you possess, when you deal damage to a creature, you can declare that attack as an agony strike. In addition to the normal damage dealt by the attack, you cause the target to take the penalties associated with your agony for 1 minute. Incorporeal creatures and creatures that are immune to critical hits are immune to agony strikes.</p>
			<p>If you have at least 12 Hit Dice, you also gain the first boon granted by your agony upon undertaking your obedience. If you have at least 16 Hit Dice, you gain the agony&apos;s second boon as well. If you have 20 Hit Dice or more, you also gain the agony&apos;s third boon. Unless a specific duration or number of uses per day is listed, a boon&#x2018;s effects are constant.</p>
			<p>If you ever fail to perform a daily obedience, or if you are healed of damage, conditions, or penalties caused in the course of performing your obedience, you lose all access to resistances and boons granted by this feat until you next perform the obedience.</p>
			<p>Pain is a fact of life. It&apos;s unavoidable, inevitable, and unpleasant. However, for most creatures, pain is also an important warning system, helping creatures correctly judge their abilities and physical needs, as well as a necessary side effect of growth and evidence of progress.</p>
			<p>Though most view pain as an obstacle to overcome or avoid if possible, for those individuals who practice mortification, pain is a vehicle for self-perfection.</p>
			<p>Mortification is an umbrella term for a number of practices that involve intentional self-harm, including blinding, deprivation trials, amputation, and a host of other practices. Mortification can be a vehicle for magical power, sexual pleasure, or simple aesthetics, depending on the practice. While most associate mortification rituals with evil cults, ascetic traditions involving practices like self-flagellation, fasting, and deprivation are not uncommon among zealous sects of nonevil faiths (including some mystery cults devoted to empyreal lords). To these believers, mortification is a demonstration of transcendence or dedication, or a means of purging the body of impurity. These faiths classify mortification as evil only when it is used to cause suffering or harm to an unwilling subject.</p>
			<p>Members of many cults that revere deformity and monstrosity demonstrate their devotion by mutilating their bodies to resemble the forms of their divine patrons. Others pursue pain for its own sake, engaging in contests of self-mutilation to display mastery over pain and settle status disputes within the group. Followers of other gods instead pursue painful trials to prove their steadfastness, whether through fasting, sleep deprivation, or more intense practices like the mortification rituals of mystery cultists. Such trials are often intended to empty the body of all worldly influence so it can be filled with divine power.</p>
			<p>There is also a category of ritual behavior that achieves gains not through self-harm, but by inflicting pain on others without their consent. Followers of gods who revel in both receiving and giving pain, practice torture rituals. Sacrifices of humanoids and other intelligent creatures are common among nihilistic cults who venerate destruction for its own sake. Several cults whose worship involves the eroticization of pain perform ritual sadism that involves inflicting pain or degradation on others for the purpose of achieving pleasure.</p>
			<p>For many practitioners of mortification, pain is an almost religious experience. Even those who do not practice self-mutilation at the behest of gods can nevertheless gain benefits for performing ritualizing physical sacrifices.</p>
			<p>Characters who take the Agonizing Obedience feat can choose a path of pain called an agony; by performing that agony&apos;s obedience, they gain boons.</p>
			<p>Spellcasting practitioners can integrate their obedience completely with their normal hour-long rituals and methods of preparing or regaining spells; others are free to perform obediences at any point during the day.</p>
			<p>You have amputated a digit on one of your hands and treated the wound such that it will never fully heal.</p>
			<p>Obedience: Manipulate the scabs, scar tissue, and open wound of your amputated digit, preventing it from closing and forcing bits of metal and glass into the wound. Take a &#x2013;2 penalty on Disable Device, Disguise, Escape Artist, and Sleight of Hand skill checks, as well as to your CMD against disarm maneuvers. When attempting to cast a spell with somatic components, succeed at a caster level check whose DC is equal to 5 + twice the spell level or lose the spell slot with no effect. Gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against transmutation spells; this bonus increases to +4 against spells in the polymorph subschool.</p>
			<p>You temporarily blind yourself with blood to heighten your other senses.</p>
			<p>Obedience: Scratch at your eyes with your fingernails, jagged metal shavings, and thorny branches, allowing the blood from your wounds to form thick scabs over your eyelids and tear ducts. Take a &#x2013;4 penalty on vision-based Perception checks, and anytime you make an attack against a target benefiting from concealment, increase the miss chance by 10% (maximum 50%). Gain a +4 bonus on saving throws against illusions in the pattern subschool and against gaze attacks.</p>
			<p>Practitioners of the agony of flensing are adept at finely removing the skin from living flesh, revealing the vulnerable tissue beneath.</p>
			<p>Obedience: Remove a patch of your own skin measuring at least 3 square inches with a flensing knife, while carefully avoiding damage to the muscles, veins, and other tissues underneath. Leave this patch of exposed nerves uncovered by clothing or armor, allowing it to be exposed to the elements and displaying your sacrifice to all you meet.</p>
			<p>Take a &#x2013;2 penalty on saving throws against disease, and take 1 extra point of damage per die from sneak attacks. Gain a +4 bonus on saving throws against pain effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Airy Step" title="Airy Step" groups="Sylph" description="The air responds to your innate elemental nature, protecting you from harm and cushioning your falls.">
		<Prerequisites>Sylph.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against effects with the air or electricity descriptors and effects that deal electricity damage. You may ignore the first 30 feet of any fall when determining falling damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Alchemical Strike" title="Alchemical Strike" groups="Combat" description="By focusing all your attention into a single attack, you vastly increase the effectiveness of thrown alchemical items.">
		<Prerequisites>Throw Anything, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can throw a single alchemical item as a full-attack action, increasing the effectiveness of the alchemical agent thrown. When throwing a single alchemical item as a full-attack action, you increase the DC of any effects associated with that alchemical item by 2. When your base attack bonus reaches +11 and every 5 points of bonus thereafter, increase the saving throw DC of the alchemical item by an additional 2. This feat does not apply to an alchemist&apos;s bombs.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>An alchemist can take this feat in place of an alchemist discovery. He does not need to meet its prerequisites. The alchemist uses his class level, rather than the base attack bonus granted by the alchemist class, to calculate his total base attack bonus for the purposes of determining the bonus granted by this feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Alertness" title="Alertness" groups="" description="You often notice things that others might miss.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on Perception and Sense Motive skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Alien Mindpaths" title="Alien Mindpaths" groups="Teamwork" description="When you're in the company of other aliens, your thoughts become difficult to follow.">
		<Prerequisites>Android, kasatha, lashunta, or triaxian.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you&apos;re adjacent to at least one other android, kasatha, lashunta, or triaxian ally who also has this feat, you gain a +4 circumstance bonus on saves against mind-affecting effects and divination (scrying) effects, unless the effect comes from an android, kasatha, lashunta, or triaxian.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Align Equipment" title="Align Equipment" groups="" description="You gain the ability to bless equipment with abilities that make them more effective against outsiders.">
		<Prerequisites>Alignment Channel, Bless Equipment, caster level 3rd, channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>In addition to the blessings provided by Bless Equipment, you can imbue weapons, shields, and suits of armor with the special abilities listed in the following table. If a special ability is followed by an alignment set in parentheses, you must be able to channel energy capable of healing or harming outsiders of that alignment subtype with Alignment Channel. For example, a cleric must have Alignment Channel (good) to bless a weapon with the holy special ability, Alignment Channel (law) to bless a shield with the vigilant special ability, and so on. Aligned equipment blessings otherwise follow all the same rules as the equipment blessings granted by Bless Equipment.</p>
			<p>* You must be capable of channeling energy that heals or harms outsiders of the chosen alignment subtype.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aligned Crafting" title="Aligned Crafting" groups="" description="Your magical creations reject those you oppose.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft Magic Arms and Armor or Craft Wondrous Item.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you craft a magic weapon, magic armor, a magic shield, or a wondrous item, you can infuse it with a bit of your convictions. Creatures that are more than one alignment step away from you are sickened while using or wearing this item. An item that has been infused with your alignment can never have an opposing special ability added to it later (for example, a longsword infused with your lawful good alignment cannot later gain the anarchic weapon special ability). Infusing the item with your alignment in this way increases the items total construction cost by 10%.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Alignment Channel" title="Alignment Channel" groups="" description="Choose chaos, evil, good, or law. You can channel divine energy to affect outsiders that possess this subtype.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to channel energy.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Instead of its normal effect, you can choose to have your ability to channel energy heal or harm outsiders of the chosen alignment subtype. You must make this choice each time you channel energy. If you choose to heal or harm creatures of the chosen alignment subtype, your channel energy has no effect on other creatures. The amount of damage healed or dealt and the DC to halve the damage is otherwise unchanged.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take this feat, it applies to a new alignment subtype. Whenever you channel energy, you must choose which type to effect.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="All-Consuming Swing" title="All-Consuming Swing" groups="Combat" description="You deliver unchecked destruction when you stand against multiple foes, sometimes to your own detriment.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, Cleave, Vital Strike, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use Cleave or Great Cleave, you can apply the additional damage you would gain from Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, or Greater Vital Strike to the initial target of your attack. When you do so, the strain on your body causes you to take an amount of damage equal to the extra damage dealt by your Vital Strike feat. This self-inflicted damage is not reduced by damage reduction.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Alter Binary Mindscape" title="Alter Binary Mindscape" groups="" description="You can shift and change a binary mindscape to your advantage during a psychic duel.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, ability to cast instigate psychic duel.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you cast instigate psychic duel and create a binary mindscape, the arena you create puts your enemy at a disadvantage. Your opponent must spend 1 more manifestation point than normal when creating any defensive manifestations.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Altitude Affinity" title="Altitude Affinity" groups="" description="You have hardened your body against the grueling rigors of surviving at high altitudes.">
		<Prerequisites>Endurance.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You are automatically acclimated at high altitudes. In addition, you gain a +2 competence bonus on all Survival checks made at altitudes of 5,000 feet or higher.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Amateur Gunslinger" title="Amateur Gunslinger" groups="Combat" description="Although you are not a gunslinger, you have and can use grit.">
		<Prerequisites>You have no levels in a class that has the grit class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a small amount of grit and the ability to perform a single 1st-level deed from the gunslinger deed class feature.</p>
			<p>At the start of the day, you gain 1 grit point, though throughout the day you can gain grit points up to a maximum of your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1).</p>
			<p>You can regain grit using the rules for the gunslinger&apos;s grit class feature. You can spend this grit to perform the 1st-level deed you chose upon taking this feat, and any other deed you have gained through feats or magic items.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you gain levels in a class that grants the grit class feature, you can immediately trade this feat for the Extra Grit feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Amateur Investigator" title="Amateur Investigator" groups="" description="Your knowledge is more than plain smarts—it's inspired.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, 1 rank in at least one Knowledge skill, no levels in a class that has the inspiration class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Like an investigator, you have the ability to augment your Knowledge, Linguistics, and Spellcraft skill checks. You gain a pool of inspiration equal to your Intelligence modifier. You can expend one use of inspiration as a free action to add 1d6 to the result of a Knowledge, Linguistics, or Spellcraft check, as long as you are trained in that skill (even if you take 10 or 20 on that check). You make this choice after the check is rolled and before the results of the roll are revealed. You can use inspiration only once per skill check. Your pool of inspiration refreshes each day, typically after you get a restful night&apos;s sleep.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you gain levels in a class that has the inspiration class feature, you can immediately trade this feat for the Extra Inspiration feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Amateur Swashbuckler" title="Amateur Swashbuckler" groups="Combat" description="Though not a swashbuckler, you have and can use panache.">
		<Prerequisites>No levels in a class that has the panache class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a small amount of panache and the ability to perform a single 1st-level swashbuckler deed. </p>
			<p>Choose a 1st-level deed from the swashbuckler&apos;s deeds class feature (you can&apos;t select opportune parry and riposte). Once chosen, this deed can&apos;t be changed.</p>
			<p>At the start of each day, you gain 1 panache point. Throughout the day, you can gain a number of panache points up to a maximum of your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). You can regain panache points as the swashbuckler&apos;s panache class feature. You can spend these panache points to perform the 1st-level deed you chose upon taking this feat as well as any other deeds you have gained through feats or magic items.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you gain levels in a class that has the panache class feature, you can immediately trade this feat for the Extra Panache feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ambush Awareness" title="Ambush Awareness" groups="Combat" description="You are always on your toes and are rarely caught off-guard for long, even when an enemy gets the jump on you.">
		<Prerequisites>Alertness.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you are unable to act in the surprise round because you failed a Perception check, you can still act on your initiative count in the surprise round, but only to take the total defense action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>If you are unable to act in the surprise round because you failed a Perception check, you can&apos;t take any actions during the surprise round.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ambush Sense" title="Ambush Sense" groups="Combat" description="You live in dangerous times, and are alert for betrayal or unexpected attack.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, trap sense class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on Perception checks made to determine awareness for the surprise round of combat, and a dodge bonus to AC in any surprise round in which you get to act. These bonuses are equal to the bonus you gain from trap sense.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ambush Squad" title="Ambush Squad" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You know that the keys to victory are sudden attacks and even more sudden retreats.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, kobold.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you&apos;re adjacent to an ally who also has this feat at the beginning of a surprise round, and both you and that ally can act during that surprise round, you can take both a standard action and a move action during that surprise round.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You can take only a standard action or a move action during a surprise round.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ammo Drop" title="Ammo Drop" groups="Combat" description="Your coordination is so perfect that you can simply drop ammunition from your hand at the exact moment required for it to fall into an open sling as your twirl it around.">
		<Prerequisites>Sleight of Hand 1 rank, proficient with sling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can load a sling or one end of a double sling with one hand as a swift action or move action. This does not provoke an attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Amplified Radiance" title="Amplified Radiance" groups="Teamwork" description="The vicinity of another of your kind ignites your inner light into a shining aurora.">
		<Prerequisites>Aasimar, daylight racial spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you are within 15 feet of an aasimar ally who has both the daylight racial spell-like ability and this feat, you gain an aura of radiance. You and your ally must both have at least one use of your daylight racial spell-like ability available to gain this benefit. This aura functions as per the daylight spell, except that it&apos;s a 10-foot-radius emanation centered on you without additional areas of weaker illumination. Creatures within this aura who take penalties in bright light double those penalties.</p>
			<p>The effects of overlapping auras of radiance don&apos;t stack.</p>
			<p>You can activate or suppress this aura as a swift action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Anatomical Savant" title="Anatomical Savant" groups="Combat" description="You know how to perform deadly strikes against even the most nebulous of targets.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus, base attack bonus +12.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one weapon with which you have the Weapon Focus feat. When you strike an opponent that has a chance of negating critical hits or sneak attacks, such as from the fortification armor special ability, reduce that chance by 25%. Treat creatures that are normally immune to critical hits and sneak attacks as instead having a 75% chance to negate the critical hit or sneak attack, taking only the attack&apos;s normal damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a different weapon.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ancestral Enmity" title="Ancestral Enmity" groups="Combat" description="You can counter the special defensive training the stouter races have against your kind.">
		<Prerequisites>Giant subtype.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on melee attack rolls against dwarves and gnomes.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You may select this feat twice. Its effects stack.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ancestral Scorn" title="Ancestral Scorn" groups="" description="The fury you harbor for your fiendish ancestors gives evil outsiders great reason to fear you.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidate 5 ranks, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you successfully demoralize an outsider of the evil subtype with an Intimidate check, it becomes sickened for 1 round in addition to being affected by the normal effects of being demoralized. If you beat the DC by 5 or more, the creature is nauseated for 1 round instead.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Demoralizing a foe with a successful Intimidate check causes it to become shaken for 1 round, +1 round for every 5 by which you beat the DC.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ancestral Weapon Mastery" title="Ancestral Weapon Mastery" groups="Combat" description="You have mastered ancient techniques that increase the effectiveness of your race's ancestral weapons.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, weapon familiarity racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You&apos;re proficient with all of your race&apos;s racial weapons (the weapons mentioned in your race&apos;s weapon familiarity racial trait). If you&apos;re already proficient with any of those weapons, you instead gain Weapon Focus for one of those weapons as a bonus feat. Furthermore, if you gain Weapon Focus as a bonus feat with one of your racial weapons as a result of this feat, you can change which racial weapon your bonus Weapon Focus feat applies to by engaging in 10 minutes of practice with the new weapon.</p>
			<p>The benefits of this bonus Weapon Focus feat last until you choose to practice and apply it to a different racial weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Angel Wings" title="Angel Wings" groups="Aasimar" description="Feathered wings sprout from your back.">
		<Prerequisites>Angelic Blood, aasimar, character level 10th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a pair of gleaming feathered wings that grant a fly speed of 30 feet (average maneuverability) if wearing light armor or unencumbered, or 20 feet (poor maneuverability) with a medium or heavy load or medium or heavy armor. Fly is a class skill for you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Angelic Blood" title="Angelic Blood" groups="Aasimar" description="Your blood is infused with holy power.">
		<Prerequisites>Con 13, aasimar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on saving throws against effects with the evil descriptor and on Constitution checks to stabilize when you are reduced to negative hit points (but not dead). Furthermore, each time you take bleed or blood drain damage, each undead creature or creature with the evil subtype that is currently adjacent to you also takes 1 point of damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Angelic Flesh" title="Angelic Flesh" groups="Aasimar" description="Your skin shines like burnished metal.">
		<Prerequisites>Angelic Blood, aasimar.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You take a &#x2013;2 penalty on Disguise and Stealth checks but gain one of the following benefits, depending on the metallic affinity of your flesh (choose one).</p>
			<p>Brazen: You gain fire resistance 5 and a +2 bonus on saves against fire effects.Golden: You gain a +2 bonus on saves against blindness, dazzling, patterns, and effects with the light descriptor. When you cast spells or use spell-like abilities that are from the illusion (pattern) subschool or have the light descriptor, you do so at +1 caster level.Silver: You gain a +2 bonus on saves against paralysis, petrification, and poison, and your unarmed strikes or natural weapons count as silver for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction.Steel: You gain a +1 natural armor bonus to AC, and your unarmed strikes or natural weapons count as cold iron for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Animal Affinity" title="Animal Affinity" groups="" description="You are skilled at working with animals and mounts.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on all Handle Animal and Ride skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Animal Ally" title="Animal Ally" groups="" description="Your respect for nature is so great that you can form a deep and lasting friendship with an animal.">
		<Prerequisites>Nature Soul, character level 4th, must not have an animal companion or mount that advances as an animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain an animal companion as if you were a druid of your character level &#x2013;3 from the following list: badger, bird, camel, cat (small), dire rat, dog, horse, pony, snake (viper), or wolf. If you later gain an animal companion through another source (such as the Animal domain, divine bond, hunter&apos;s bond, mount, or nature bond class features), the effective druid level granted by this feat stacks with that granted by other sources.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Animal Call" title="Animal Call" groups="" description="You've learn how to replicate a number of animal calls native to wilderness environments.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, Knowledge (nature) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Pick one of the ranger&apos;s favored terrains. You can use your Bluff skill to mimic the calls of animals native to that terrain. Creatures with ranks in Knowledge (nature) can use that skill in place of Sense Motive to detect your mimicry and realize that the sound is false.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you do, select an additional favored terrain to which this feat applies.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Animal Disguise" title="Animal Disguise" groups="" description="With a little work, you can convincingly disguise yourself as an animal.">
		<Prerequisites>Disguise 6 ranks, Knowledge (nature) 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use Disguise to disguise yourself as an animal of your size category. You must have an appropriate pelt and any other animal parts needed to complete the disguise. You also gain a +2 bonus on Disguise checks when you disguise yourself as an animal. Creatures with ranks in Knowledge (nature) can use that skill in place of Sense Motive to detect this type of disguise.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Animal Ferocity" title="Animal Ferocity" groups="Combat" description="When cornered and wounded, you fight like a feral beast.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +3, ferocity racial ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When your hit points are reduced below 0, you can still take the full attack action [Source], but you take a -5 penalty on each attack roll.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Animal Soul" title="Animal Soul" groups="" description="Your close bond with an animal allows you to ignore harmful magic that cannot affect your wild side.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion or mount class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose not to allow spells and effects to affect you if they would not be capable of affecting both your original creature type and the animal creature type.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ankle Biter" title="Ankle Biter" groups="Combat" description="You know how take a mouthful out of anyone who tries to overpower you.">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin, Escape Artist 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you are the target of a combat maneuver you can, as an immediate action, attempt to bite your opponent in addition to any attacks of opportunity or other consequences your opponent might incur from attacking you. This bonus natural attack does not provoke an attack of opportunity itself and deals base damage appropriate for a creature of your current size (usually 1d4 for Small creatures). If grappled or pinned, you can continue to make this additional bite attack each round as swift action on your turn. You gain a bonus on any attempt to break the grapple equal to the damage you dealt with your bite that round.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You cannot make this bite attack when you are the aggressor, including if you manage to reverse a grapple or make any other attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Antagonize" title="Antagonize" groups="" description="Whether with biting remarks or hurtful words, you are adept at making creatures angry with you.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can make Diplomacy and Intimidate checks to make creatures respond to you with hostility. No matter which skill you use, antagonizing a creature takes a standard action that does not provoke attacks of opportunity, and has a DC equal to 10 + the target&apos;s Hit Dice + the target&apos;s Wisdom modifier. You cannot make this check against a creature that does not understand you or has an Intelligence score of 3 or lower. Before you make these checks, you may make a Sense Motive check (DC 20) as a swift action to gain an insight bonus on these Diplomacy or Intimidate checks equal to your Charisma bonus until the end of your next turn. The benefits you gain for this check depend on the skill you use. This is a mind-affecting effect.</p>
			<p>Diplomacy: You fluster your enemy. For the next minute, the target takes a &#x2013;2 penalty on all attacks rolls made against creatures other than you and has a 10% spell failure chance on all spells that do not target you or that have you within their area of effect.</p>
			<p>Intimidate: The creature flies into a rage. On its next turn, the target must attempt to make a melee attack against you, make a ranged attack against you, target you with a spell, or include you in the area of a spell. The effect ends if the creature is prevented from attacking you or attempting to do so would harm it (for example, if you are on the other side of a chasm or a wall of fire). If it cannot attack you on its turn, you may make the check again as an immediate action to extend the effect for 1 round (but cannot extend it thereafter). The effect ends as soon as the creature attacks you. Once you have targeted a creature with this ability, you cannot target it again for 1 day.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Anticipate Dodge" title="Anticipate Dodge" groups="Combat" description="Your knowledge of mobility and your attack prowess allow you to thwart elusive opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Mobility; base attack bonus +7, brawler level 4th, or monk level 4th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You automatically know whether a creature you can see has a dodge bonus to its AC. You gain up to a +2 bonus on attack rolls against a target that has a dodge bonus. This bonus cannot exceed the dodge bonus of the creature you attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Apocalyptic Spell" title="Apocalyptic Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your spell becomes infused with the devastating horror personified by the Horsemen of the Apocalypse, temporarily transforming reality into a treacherous ruin.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can alter a spell with an area of effect and a duration of instantaneous to become an apocalyptic spell.</p>
			<p>When you cast the spell, the area affected by the spell&apos;s instantaneous effect becomes ruined and devastated in appearance. All surfaces in the area are treated as difficult terrain, and Climb, Fly, and Swim checks attempted in the area take a penalty equal to the spell&apos;s original spell level.The difficult terrain and skill penalties last for a number of rounds equal to the spell&apos;s original spell level. An apocalyptic spell gains the evil descriptor.An apocalyptic spell uses a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s normal spell level. Spells with the good descriptor can&apos;t be apocalyptic spells.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aquadynamic Focus" title="Aquadynamic Focus" groups="Combat" description="Your skill with your chosen weapons is so great that you can use them underwater without impediment.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus, base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You don&apos;t take additional penalties on attack and damage rolls for fighting underwater with bludgeoning and slashing melee weapons for which you have taken the Weapon Focus feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When using bludgeoning and slashing melee weapons underwater, you take a -2 penalty on attack rolls and deal half damage.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aquadynamic Shot" title="Aquadynamic Shot" groups="Combat" description="You use projectiles and special trick shots that lose less accuracy when underwater.">
		<Prerequisites>Far Shot, Point-Blank Shot, base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your projectile attacks take a -1 penalty per 5 feet of water between you and the target. You still can&apos;t use thrown weapons effectively underwater except in special circumstances.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Projectile attacks underwater take a -2 penalty per 5 feet of water between the shooter and the target.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aquatic Ancestry" title="Aquatic Ancestry" groups="Undine" description="You favor your outsider ancestry and are better adapted to life in the water.">
		<Prerequisites>Undine.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain the amphibious special quality. Your swim speed increases by +10 feet.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aquatic Combatant" title="Aquatic Combatant" groups="Combat" description="You have trained to fight while submerged in water.">
		<Prerequisites>Swim 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Swim checks and don&apos;t take the usual penalties on melee attack rolls made underwater. Your slashing melee attacks and unarmed bludgeoning attacks deal full damage underwater.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When you&apos;re underwater, most of your melee attacks take a -2 penalty and deal only half damage.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aquatic Spell" title="Aquatic Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can cast your spells underwater or into water with little difficulty.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>An aquatic spell functions normally underwater and requires no caster level check to cast, even if it has the fire descriptor. In addition, the spell can be cast from the surface into water and still be effective.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (an aquatic spell uses up a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arc Slinger" title="Arc Slinger" groups="Combat" description="You can twirl your sling in a way that maximizes its effectiveness.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot, proficient with sling or half ling sling staff.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using a sling or sling staff, you reduce your penalty on ranged attack rolls due to range by 2. Point-Blank Shot&apos;s damage bonus applies within the first normal range increment of your sling (50 feet) or sling staff (80 feet).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Armor Mastery" title="Arcane Armor Mastery" groups="Combat" description="You have mastered the ability to cast spells while wearing armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Armor Training, Medium Armor Proficiency, caster level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, reduce the arcane spell failure chance due to the armor you are wearing by 20% for any spells you cast this round. This bonus replaces, and does not stack with, the bonus granted by Arcane Armor Training.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Armor Training" title="Arcane Armor Training" groups="Combat" description="You have learned how to cast spells while wearing armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Light Armor Proficiency, caster level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, reduce the arcane spell failure chance due to the armor you are wearing by 10% for any spells you cast this round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Blast" title="Arcane Blast" groups="" description="You can convert any spell into an attack.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane spellcaster, caster level 10th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can sacrifice a prepared spell or unused spell slot of 1st level or higher and transform it into a ray, targeting any foe within 30 feet as a ranged touch attack. This attack deals 2d6 points of damage plus an additional 1d6 points of damage for every level of the spell or spell slot you sacrificed. 0-level spells may not be sacrificed in this manner.</p>
			<p>This is a supernatural ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Insight" title="Arcane Insight" groups="" description="Magical insight helps you evade attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Shield, arcane spellcaster, caster level 10th, worshiper of the god of magic or knowledge.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use Arcane Shield, you also gain a +1 insight bonus to AC for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Jinxer" title="Arcane Jinxer" groups="" description="You can sacrifice arcane spells or spell slots in order to make it harder to resist your jinxes.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane spellcaster, Halfling Jinx alternate racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you attempt to jinx a creature, you can expend one of your prepared arcane spells or available arcane spell slots to give your target a penalty on its jinx save equal to the level of the expended spell or spell slot. This does not alter the effect of the jinx, only the saving throw to resist the jinx.</p>
			<p>Pathfinder Player Companion: Halflings of Golarion </p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane School Spirit" title="Arcane School Spirit" groups="" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, arcane school class feature, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a full-round action, you extol the virtues of your school of magic to one creature within 30 feet. Make a Bluff check opposed by a target&apos;s Sense Motive check; if you win the check, the target takes a &#x2013;2 penalty on saving throws made to resist the next spell of this school that you cast. If your chosen school is universalist, choose a specific school each time you use this ability. If your Bluff check succeeds, however, your lack of true commitment to the school means the target takes only a &#x2013;1 penalty on its saving throw.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Shield" title="Arcane Shield" groups="" description="You can convert any spell into a defense.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane spellcaster, caster level 10th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a immediate action, you can sacrifice a prepared spell or unused spell slot of 1st level or higher and gain a deflection bonus to AC equal to the level of the spell or spell slot you sacrificed for 1 round. 0-level spells may not be sacrificed in this manner.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Strike" title="Arcane Strike" groups="Combat" description="You draw upon your arcane power to enhance your weapons with magical energy.">
		<Prerequisites>Ability to cast arcane spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, you can imbue your weapons with a fraction of your power. For 1 round, your weapons deal +1 damage and are treated as magic for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction. For every five caster levels you possess, this bonus increases by +1, to a maximum of +5 at 20th level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Talent" title="Arcane Talent" groups="" description="Magic is in your blood, and at your fingertips.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 10; elf, half-elf, or gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose a 0-level spell from the sorcerer/wizard spell list. You can cast this spell three times per day as a spell-like ability. The caster level is equal to your character level. The save DC is 10 + your Charisma modifier.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcane Vendetta" title="Arcane Vendetta" groups="" description="The mistreatment of your people by an arcane society has made you particularly eager to inflict harm on those who use arcane magic.">
		<Prerequisites>SpellCraft 1 rank</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You deal +2 damage with weapon attacks made against any target you have witnessed casting an arcane spell (not using a spell-like ability) in the last 5 rounds. You must have successfully identified the spell with a Spellcraft check to know without a doubt that the spell is arcane.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Archon Diversion" title="Archon Diversion" groups="Combat" description="You throw yourself in front of blows meant for allies, giving those allies a chance to strike back against the enemy once they have attacked you.">
		<Prerequisites>Archon Style; Combat Expertise; Combat Reflexes; base attack bonus +4 or monk level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The penalty to AC for using Archon Style to grant nearby allies a bonus to AC against a single opponent decreases to -1. Once per round while using Archon Style, when you have at least one hand free or when wielding a shield, you can divert one melee weapon attack targeting an adjacent ally to yourself. After resolving the attack, the ally you protected can make an attack of opportunity against the diverted opponent. You expend no action to divert the attack, but you must be aware of it and must not be flat-footed. You must choose to divert the attack after the opponent has declared the melee attack, but before the attack roll is rolled.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Archon Justice" title="Archon Justice" groups="Combat" description="Attacking you during your period of vigilance opens foes up to allies' strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Archon Diversion; Archon Style; Combat Expertise; Combat Reflexes; base attack bonus +8 or monk level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You no longer take a penalty to AC for using Archon Style to grant nearby allies a bonus to AC, and you can activate this effect as a swift action or a move action.</p>
			<p>Whenever you take damage from an attack you diverted to yourself using Archon Diversion, each ally threatening the attacking creature can make an attack of opportunity against that creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Archon Style" title="Archon Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You protect your allies from harm, even at the cost of your own safety.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Expertise; Combat Reflexes; base attack bonus +2 or monk level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, as a move action, you can protect adjacent allies from a single opponent that you currently threaten. This grants adjacent allies a +2 dodge bonus to AC against that opponent&apos;s next melee attack (as long as that attack comes before the beginning of your next turn), but causes you to take a -2 penalty to AC against that opponent until your next turn. The dodge bonus against the designated opponent&apos;s attacks persists even if your allies move away from you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arcing Weapon" title="Arcing Weapon" groups="Combat" description="You can send magical blasts through your weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Diverse training class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can cast a ray spell that requires a ranged touch attack and deliver the effect through your melee weapon, either through a melee attack or as a ranged attack. If you deliver this spell as a melee attack, this functions as the magus spellstrike ability.</p>
			<p>If you deliver the spell as a ranged attack, the spell is a ranged touch attack that discharges from your weapon and applies the weapon&apos;s enhancement bonus to the spell&apos;s damage.</p>
			<p>When fired in this way, the spell uses the weapon&apos;s critical threat range, but the spell effect deals only &#xD7;2 damage on a successful critical hit. You can use a ranged touch attack spell that targets more than one creature (such as scorching ray), but you make only one attack through your weapon to deliver one ranged touch effect; additional ranged touch attacks from the spell are wasted and have no effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arctic Adaptation" title="Arctic Adaptation" groups="" description="You are comfortable in the driving snow and glaring ice of frigid climes, and you can survive much longer in such harsh environments than those who are unaccustomed to the cold.">
		<Prerequisites>Favored terrain (cold) class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You treat cold environments as though they were one step less severe than they normally are. Additionally, you gain a +2 bonus on Perception checks against creatures that gain a racial bonus on Stealth checks in snowy conditions, and you gain a +4 bonus on saving throws and checks to avoid becoming blinded or dazzled by ice or snow glare.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Area Jinx" title="Area Jinx" groups="" description="You can jinx multiple creatures so long as they are near each other.">
		<Prerequisites>Widen Spell, Halfling Jinx alternate racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use your jinx, you create an instantaneous invisible burst with a maximum radius of 10 feet anywhere within the normal range of your jinx, affecting multiple targets. Any creature within this burst, regardless of whether or not you can see it, must make a saving throw to resist your jinx. If you use your jinx again, all of your current jinxes immediately end.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Each time you do, the maximum area of your jinx burst increases by an additional 10 feet.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arithmancy" title="Arithmancy" groups="" description="You are able to unravel the hidden meanings behind words by translating them into numerical equations. You can apply this insight to empower your magical effects.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Spell Focus (divination), Spellcraft 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Immediately before casting a spell, as a swift action, you can attempt to augment a spell&apos;s casting using Arithmancy. To do so, determine the digital root of the name of the spell you are casting.</p>
			<p>To find the digital root of a spell name, first assign a numerical value to each letter of the name, per the Letter Values table. Once you have a string of digits, sum them.</p>
			<p>If the result has more than one digit, sum those digits.</p>
			<p>Repeat this process until you arrive at a single number, called the digital root.</p>
			<p>Once you&apos;ve translated the name of the spell into a single digital root, attempt a Spellcraft check with a DC equal to 10 + the spell level + the digital root. If your check succeeds, the spell is cast at +1 caster level. If your check fails, the spell is cast at &#x2013;1 caster level. If you do not cast the spell you intended to augment with arithmancy, the spell is expended with no effect, though you retain the action you would have spent to cast it. Metamagic effects are not included in a spell&apos;s name when determining the spell&apos;s digital root, but they increase the spell&apos;s level as normal when determining the DC of the Spellcraft check.</p>
			<p>You can use this ability a number of times per day equal to the number of caster levels you possess.</p>
			<p>For example, a wizard wants to use Arithmancy to cast an augmented fireball. First, he translates the spell name into numbers. Fireball translates to 6, 9, 9, 5, 2, 1, 3, 3. Then he calculates the digital root. In this case, 6 + 9 + 9 + 5 + 2 + 1 + 3 + 3 = 38, 3 + 8 = 11, and 1 + 1 = 2. Therefore, the digital root of fireball is 2. He then attempts a Spellcraft check against a DC of 15 (10 + 3 [fireball&#x2018;s spell level] + 2 [fireball&#x2018;s digital root]).</p>
			<p>If his check succeeds, he can cast the fireball this round at +1 caster level. If he fails, he can cast the spell at &#x2013;1 caster level this round. He may also choose not to cast fireball and perform another action, though he expends the spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Arming Grab" title="Arming Grab" groups="Combat" description="Opponents would be foolish to underestimate you, even if you appear unarmed and helpless. You are practiced at turning the tables on armed foes and using their own weapons against them.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, Catch Off-Guard, Combat Expertise, Improved Disarm.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You take no penalty on your attack roll when attempting to disarm an opponent while you are unarmed.</p>
			<p>If you succeed at a disarm attempt without using a weapon and choose to pick up the disarmed weapon, you can attack with that weapon as though you were proficient with it until the end of your next turn. If you are already proficient with that type of weapon, you gain a +2 morale bonus to your attack rolls with that weapon until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Attempting to disarm a foe while unarmed imposes a -4 penalty on the attack.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armor Adept" title="Armor Adept" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at using customized armor.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose two armor modifications (such as deflecting or jarring). You no longer suffer the drawbacks of wearing armor with those modifications.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Each type of armor modification imparts a drawback on a wearer.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times, choosing two different armor modifications each time.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armor Focus" title="Armor Focus" groups="Combat" description="Your familiarity with a specific type of armor increases the amount of protection you receive from it.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, proficiency with selected armor.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one type of armor, such as chain shirt or splint mail. The AC bonus granted by the selected armor increases by 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new type of armor. The Armor Focus feat counts as the armor training class feature for the purpose of armor mastery feat prerequisites and determines what types of armor you can use with armor mastery feats.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armor Proficiency, Heavy" title="Armor Proficiency, Heavy" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at wearing heavy armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Light Armor Proficiency, Medium Armor Proficiency.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>See Armor Proficiency, Light.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>See Armor Proficiency, Light.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>Fighters and paladins automatically have Heavy Armor Proficiency as a bonus feat. They need not select it.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armor Proficiency, Light" title="Armor Proficiency, Light" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at wearing light armors.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you wear light armor, the armor check penalty for that armor applies only to Dexterity- and Strength-based skill checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A character who is wearing armor with which he is not proficient applies its armor check penalty to attack rolls and to all skill checks that involve moving.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>All characters except monks, sorcerers, and wizards automatically have Light Armor Proficiency as a bonus feat. They need not select it.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armor Proficiency, Medium" title="Armor Proficiency, Medium" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at wearing medium armor.">
		<Prerequisites>Light Armor Proficiency.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>See Armor Proficiency, Light.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>See Armor Proficiency, Light.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>Barbarians, clerics, druids, fighters, paladins, and rangers automatically have Medium Armor Proficiency as a bonus feat. They need not select it.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armor Trick" title="Armor Trick" groups="Combat" description="Contents">
When used cleverly, armor becomes far more than a defensive implement. Armor tricks are actions available to characters who have the Armor Trick feat for the appropriate equipment.
			<p>Choose one armor trick option (light, medium, heavy, or shield). You can perform armor tricks in combat when wearing the appropriate armor option.</p>
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use any armor tricks related to the chosen armor option if you meet the trick&apos;s prerequisites and are proficient with any armor that you use as part of the trick.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain Armor Trick multiple times. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new armor trick option.</p>
			<p>In addition to the prerequisites listed in parentheses for each of the following armor tricks, you must be proficient with any armor used in the trick and have the Armor Trick feat with the appropriate armor option.</p>
			<p>Light armor tricks are often used to supplement the modest defense provided by lighter armors by maximizing flexibility and mobility.</p>
			<p>In addition to the prerequisites listed in parentheses for each of the following armor tricks, you must be proficient with any armor used in the trick and have the Armor Trick feat with the appropriate armor option.</p>
			<p>Medium armor tricks are employed by those who want to retain flexibility and agility in combat.</p>
			<p>In addition to the prerequisites listed in parentheses for each of the following armor tricks, you must be proficient with any armor used in the trick and have the Armor Trick feat with the appropriate armor option.</p>
			<p>Heavy armor tricks are most common among those who utilize the mass and heft of armor, and don&apos;t function when you&apos;re wearing heavy armor that uses magic or materials to be treated as medium armor for any purpose, unless the heavy armor trick says otherwise.</p>
			<p>In addition to the prerequisites listed in parentheses for each of the following armor tricks, you must be proficient with any armor used in the trick and have the Armor Trick feat with the appropriate armor option.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armor of the Pit" title="Armor of the Pit" groups="Tiefling" description="Your fiendish traits take the form of a protective scaly skin.">
		<Prerequisites>Tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 natural armor bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the scaled skin racial trait, you instead gain resistance 5 to two of the following energy types that you don&apos;t have resistance to already: cold, electricity, and fire.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Armored Athlete" title="Armored Athlete" groups="Combat" description="You have experience using a skill while armored.">
		<Prerequisites>Light armor proficiency, medium armor proficiency, 3 ranks in any Dexterity- or Strength-based skill.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one Dexterity- or Strength-based skill in which you possess at least 3 ranks. When you attempt a check for the chosen skill, your armor check penalty on that check for wearing light or medium armor is reduced by 3 (to a minimum of 0). If you have 10 or more ranks in the skill, the penalty is instead reduced by 6 (to a minimum of 0). If you have armor training 2 and are proficient with heavy armor, this benefit also applies to armor check penalties for wearing heavy armor.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can gain this feat multiple times. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a new skill.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Artful Dodge" title="Artful Dodge" groups="Combat" description="You are practiced at avoiding attacks when outnumbered.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you are the only character threatening an opponent, you gain a +1 dodge bonus to AC against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>The Artful Dodge feat acts as the Dodge feat for the purpose of satisfying prerequisites that require Dodge.</p>
			<p>You can use Intelligence, rather than Dexterity, for feats with a minimum Dexterity prerequisite.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Artillery Team" title="Artillery Team" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="Together, you and an ally can operate an oversized and unwieldy weapon.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficiency with light crossbow, heavy crossbow, or musket; size Small or Medium.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you&apos;re adjacent to an ally who also has this feat, together you count as being Large for the purpose of using Large light crossbows, Large heavy crossbows, and Large muskets. Firing such a weapon this way requires your ally to support the barrel or bow of the weapon. You must be able to trace a line from your space to the target&apos;s space in such a way that the line passes through the ally&apos;s space. The ally doesn&apos;t provide soft cover to your target.</p>
			<p>Your ally uses her actions to load the weapon, and you use your actions to make attacks. Similarly, your ally&apos;s feats and abilities apply to reloading, while your feats and abilities apply to making attacks. This feat does not allow you and your ally to act simultaneously on the same initiative.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Artistry" title="Artistry" groups="Combat" description="You can do more with your blade than slash and stab.">
		<Prerequisites>Exotic Weapon Proficiency (dueling sword), Weapon Finesse, base attack bonus +2.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one of the following combat maneuvers: disarm, reposition, steal, sunder, or trip. You gain a +2 bonus when performing the selected maneuver while wielding a dueling sword. This bonus does not stack with the bonus provided by a combat maneuver feat with -improved- in its name (such as Improved Trip).</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can select this feat multiple times, choosing a different combat maneuver each time.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ascendant Spell" title="Ascendant Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You have learned how to emulate mythic spells using non-mythic forces.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can modify a spell to imitate the mythic version of that spell. An ascendant spell uses the mythic version of the spell, but doesn&apos;t count as a mythic spell for the purposes of effects that interact with the spell, unless you are a mythic creature. You can&apos;t use the augmented version of the mythic spell, or use spells effects that require you to expend uses of mythic power (even if you have uses of mythic power available).</p>
			<p>An ascendant spell uses up a spell slot 5 levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ascetic Form" title="Ascetic Form" groups="Combat" description="You have mastered the ability to blend the use of arms with martial arts.">
		<Prerequisites>Ascetic Style; Weapon Focus with the chosen melee weapon; base attack bonus +5 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use the chosen melee weapon with any class ability that can be used with an unarmed strike, such as an unchained monk&apos;s style strike ability. In addition, you are treated as a monk with a level equal to your character level for the purpose of determining the number of times per day that you can use feats with uses per day that depend upon your monk level, such as the Stunning Fist or Perfect Strike feats.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ascetic Strike" title="Ascetic Strike" groups="Combat" description="Your weapon strikes deal more damage than usual.">
		<Prerequisites>Ascetic Form; Ascetic Style; Weapon Focus with the chosen weapon; base attack bonus +7 or monk level 7th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use the unarmed strike damage of a monk 4 levels lower than your character level (minimum 1st) instead of the base damage for the chosen weapon. Ascetic Strike functions in all other ways as the brawler&apos;s close weapon mastery class feature.</p>
			<p>In addition, you ignore the still mind class feature prerequisite for the Monastic Legacy feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Ascetic Style" title="Ascetic Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You blend arms and martial arts, using weapons with the same ease as unarmed strikes.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with the chosen melee weapon; base attack bonus +1 or monk level 1st.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one weapon from the monk fighter weapon group. While using this style and wielding the chosen weapon, you can apply the effects of feats that have Improved Unarmed Strike as a prerequisite, as well as effects that augment an unarmed strike, as if attacks with the weapon were unarmed attacks.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A 5th-level monk or character with the weapon training (monk) class feature can use Ascetic Style with any monk weapon, in addition to the chosen melee weapon.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aspect of the Beast" title="Aspect of the Beast" groups="" description="Whether by magic or a curse of your blood, some part of you is more beast than man.">
		<Prerequisites>wild shape class feature, see Special.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your bestial nature manifests itself in one of the following ways. You choose the manifestation when you choose the feat, and then you cannot change it.</p>
			<p>Night Senses (Ex): If your base race has normal vision, you gain low-light vision. If your base race has low-light vision, you gain darkvision out to a range of 30 feet. If your base race has darkvision, the range of your darkvision increases by 30 feet.</p>
			<p>Claws of the Beast (Ex): You grow a pair of claws. These claws are primary attacks that deal 1d4 points of damage (1d3 if you are Small).</p>
			<p>Predator&apos;s Leap (Ex): You can make a running jump without needing to run 10 feet before you jump.</p>
			<p>Wild Instinct (Ex): You gain a +2 bonus on initiative checks and a +2 bonus on Survival skill checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A character that has contracted lycanthropy can take this feat without having to meet the prerequisites. A ranger who selects the natural weapon combat style can take this feat without having to meet the prerequisites (even if he does not select Aspect of the Beast as a bonus feat).</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Associate" title="Associate" groups="" description="You are on good terms with a large organization, though not necessarily an official member.">
		<Prerequisites>Maintain a positive relationship with an organization for at least 6 months or achieve a major accomplishment on behalf of an organization.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select a single organization with which you have a positive relationship. You gain a +4 circumstance bonus on Diplomacy checks to influence members of that group or when making gather information checks about the organization. In any settlement that is the size of a small town or larger, you can spend 1d4 hours to attempt to track down a representative of your organization to gain a minor resource or service for free (such as information), a place to stay, or transportation. If you succeed at a Diplomacy check (DC = 20 + the gp cost of the service requested [minimum 1 gp]), you successfully call in a favor and gain that service for free; otherwise, you must pay the normal fee. You can attempt this check once per week.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you select this feat, you associate yourself with an additional organization.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Asura Sight" title="Asura Sight" groups="Combat" description="Taking inspiration from the many faces of asuras, you have learned to split your focus to avoid being caught off guard.">
		<Prerequisites>Asura Style, base attack bonus +9 or monk level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Asura Style, you gain improved uncanny dodge as a rogue of your character level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Asura Spellrend" title="Asura Spellrend" groups="Combat" description="Your blasphemies shatter divine magic.">
		<Prerequisites>Asura Sight, Asura Style, base attack bonus +13 or monk level 13th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can replace one of your attacks at your highest base attack bonus each round with a spellrending strike. If your spellrending strike hits, it deals no damage, but you can attempt to dispel a harmless divine spell affecting this target as per dispel magic, with a caster level equal to your character level. If you succeed at your dispel check, the target is sickened as if you had interrupted the spell with Asura Style and receives no saving throw to reduce the sickened duration.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Asura Style" title="Asura Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Blasphemy comes quite naturally to you. When you interrupt your foes' divine spells, you use words, symbols, or gestures so abhorrent to their faith that they are repulsed by your deeds.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +5 or monk level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use a monk weapon or unarmed strike to attack a creature that is casting a divine spell, the target is sickened for 1d4 rounds. A target can attempt a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + half your character level + your Wisdom modifier) to reduce the duration of the sickened effect to 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Athletic" title="Athletic" groups="" description="You possess inherent physical prowess.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on Climb and Swim skill checks. If you have 10 or more ranks in one of these skills, the bonus increases to +4 for that skill.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Attuned to the Wild" title="Attuned to the Wild" groups="Elf" description="You share a strong mystic connection with one type of wilderness terrain.">
		<Prerequisites>Elf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one type of terrain from the ranger class&apos;s favored terrain class feature (except urban). While you are in your selected terrain type, your natural healing rate (the amount of hit points and ability damage you heal from a full night&apos;s rest) doubles.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time you take it, it applies to a different terrain type.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Augment Summoning" title="Augment Summoning" groups="" description="Your summoned creatures are more powerful and robust.">
		<Prerequisites>Spell Focus (conjuration).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Each creature you conjure with any summon spell gains a +4 enhancement bonus to Strength and Constitution for the duration of the spell that summoned it.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aura Flare" title="Aura Flare" groups="" description="You are able to flare your alignment aura to debilitate your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13; aura, aura of good, or aura of evil class feature; channel energy 4d6; strong or overwhelming good or evil aura.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, when you channel energy, you are also able to cause your divine aura to flare in a display of overwhelming force, affecting all good creatures within the aura (if you channel negative energy) or all evil creatures in the aura (if you channel positive energy). This effect is in addition to the normal effects of channeling energy.</p>
			<p>When you flare your aura, select from one of the following options based on the strength of your alignment aura. You can select a lower-strength effect.</p>
			<p>Strong: Affected creatures must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your class level in the class granting you the channel energy ability + your Charisma bonus) or be fatigued for 1d4 rounds.</p>
			<p>Overwhelming: Affected creatures must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your class level in the class granting you the channel energy ability + your Charisma bonus) or be staggered for 1d4 rounds.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Authoritative Spell" title="Authoritative Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your magic holds all the intricacies of Axis's idealized laws, enforcing their strictures upon your enemies.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can alter any spell that targets a single creature to become an authoritative spell. When you cast an authoritative spell, choose one of the following activities to prohibit: move closer to you, move away from you, make a melee weapon attack, make a ranged weapon attack, cast an offensive spell, or cast a non-offensive spell.</p>
			<p>A creature that is affected by the spell and fails its saving throw against that spell (if the spell allows a saving throw to resist) cannot perform any action of the selected type on its next turn. An authoritative spell gains the lawful descriptor, and the additional effect is a mind-affecting compulsion effect.An authoritative spell uses a spell slot 2 levels higher than the spell&apos;s normal spell level. Spells with the chaotic descriptor can&apos;t be authoritative spells.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Aversion Tolerance" title="Aversion Tolerance" groups="" description="You have been hunted for so long that you have developed resistances to slayers' usual scare tactics.">
		<Prerequisites>Vampire.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on saves made to resist aversions to objects, sounds, and materials appropriate to your vampire type (such as garlic, holy symbols, and mirrors for a moroi). When confronted with such things, you can attempt a saving throw immediately instead of after 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Awe-Inspiring Smash" title="Awe-Inspiring Smash" groups="Combat,Performance" description="Your fury in combat translates into crowd-pleasing displays.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Power Attack, base attack bonus +3</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can apply your Strength modifier instead of your Charisma modifier to performance combat checks.</p>
			<p>In addition, when you spend a swift action to attempt a performance combat check that was triggered by a successful bull rush or sunder combat maneuver check, you gain a +2 bonus on the performance combat check. For every 5 points by which your attack exceeded your opponent&apos;s CMD, this bonus increases by 2.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: After successfully performing a bull rush or sunder combat maneuver, you can spend up to 5 stamina points to increase the bonus on performance combat checks that you gain from Awe-Inspiring Smash by 1 per stamina point spent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Awesome Charge" title="Awesome Charge" groups="Combat" description="When you charge, you can send your opponent flying.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 25, Awesome Blow, Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you hit your opponent with a charge attack, you can attempt an awesome blow combat maneuver against that opponent as a free action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Awesome Throw" title="Awesome Throw" groups="Combat" description="Your ranged attacks can send smaller opponents flying.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 25, Throw Anything or rock throwing, Improved Bull Rush, size Large or larger.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can perform the awesome throw combat maneuver. You do this by making a thrown weapon attack; if you don&apos;t have the Throw Anything feat, you must use a large, bulky, and relatively regular-shaped object with a hardness of at least 5 (such as a rock or treasure chest). If that attack hits a corporeal opponent smaller than you, the opponent takes damage and is knocked away, flying 10 feet in a straight line away from you and falling prone. If an obstacle prevents the completion of your target&apos;s move, the target and the obstacle each take 1d6 points of damage, and the target is knocked prone in a space adjacent to the obstacle.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Azata Mischief" title="Azata Mischief" groups="Combat" description="You move with uncommon grace that disorients enemies, causing foes that strike at you to overreach and stumble.">
		<Prerequisites>Agile Maneuvers, Azata Style, Dodge, Mobility, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Azata Style, whenever an opponent misses you with an attack of opportunity provoked by your movement through its threatened squares, you can attempt a trip combat maneuver against that creature at the end of your turn as a swift action, provided you are still adjacent to the creature when you end your movement for the round.</p>
			<p>This trip attempt does not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
			<p>You gain a bonus on your combat maneuver check equal to any bonuses to AC you gain against attacks of opportunity provoked by movement (such as that granted by the Mobility feat).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Azata Sprint" title="Azata Sprint" groups="Combat" description="You move across the battlefield in a blur.">
		<Prerequisites>Agile Maneuvers, Azata Mischief, Azata Style, Dodge, Mobility, Wind Stance, base attack bonus +10.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Azata Style, your base speed increases by 10 feet and you ignore the movement penalties applied by the first 10 feet of difficult terrain you move through in the round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Azata Style" title="Azata Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your quickness and grace keep you alive.">
		<Prerequisites>Dodge, Mobility, base attack bonus +2.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, during any round in which you move at least 15 feet, you gain a +1 dodge bonus to your AC. This bonus lasts until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Babble-Peddler" title="Babble-Peddler" groups="" description="Your talent for flimflam allows you to trick creatures into exchanging valuable objects for whatever junk you happen to offer.">
		<Prerequisites>Appraise 5 ranks, Bluff 5 ranks, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Make a Bluff check to praise the value and worth of an object in your hand while denigrating an object held by a nearby creature; this takes anywhere from 1 round to 1 minute depending on the appearance and nature of the items. If the creature fails its check, it agrees to exchange your object for its own. Obvious differences in the value between the exchanged items give your roll a +4 or &#x2013;4 modifier, at the GM&apos;s discretion (offering a clay cup for a jeweled dagger gives your roll a &#x2013;4 penalty). The GM may rule that some items are too obviously valuable or worthless for this feat to apply (a king wouldn&apos;t trade his crown for any item, and no normal person would trade an item for a piece of garbage). If you fail the check by 5 or more, the target is insulted and his attitude toward you worsens by one category.</p>
			<p> Once the exchange happens, make an Appraise roll opposed by the target&apos;s Appraise or Sense Motive roll. If the target wins, it immediately realizes the true value of the object you offered it and behaves accordingly. If you succeed, it believes your false assessment for 1 round; for every 5 by which your check exceeds your opponent&apos;s check, the deception lasts 1 more round. As with disbelieving illusions, the target&apos;s ally can point out the true value of the object, giving the target another check with a +2 bonus.</p>
			<p> You cannot use this ability in combat, against a creature whose attitude toward you is hostile or unfriendly, against a creature that does not understand you, or against a creature that has an Intelligence score of 3 or less.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Back to Back" title="Back to Back" groups="Teamwork" description="Your ally's eyes are your own, and yours are his.">
		<Prerequisites>Perception 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are flanked and adjacent to an ally with this feat, you receive a +2 circumstance bonus to AC against attacks from opponents flanking you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Balor Whip" title="Balor Whip" groups="Combat" description="You can drag distant foes toward you with your whip.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus (whip), Whip Mastery, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you perform a drag combat maneuver with your whip, you can choose not to move with your target, instead bringing your target closer to you. If you do this, you can&apos;t drag the target any farther than the distance it takes to move it adjacent to you, even if your result was high enough to drag the target farther. You gain a +2 bonus on drag combat maneuver checks when using a whip to drag, but this bonus doesn&apos;t stack with the bonus from Improved Drag.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Balor Whip counts as Improved Drag for the purpose of qualifying for Quick Drag.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Baneful Judgment" title="Baneful Judgment" groups="Combat" description="You dole out judgment to a particular foe.">
		<Prerequisites>Bane class feature, judgment class feature, monster lore class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can declare a specialized judgment against a creature as a swift action. When pronouncing this judgment, you attempt a Knowledge check to identify the creature, or refer to your previous result if you&apos;ve already identified the creature. If you succeed at the check or have already identified the creature, you can spend 1 round of bane and choose one judgment other than the healing judgment. You gain the benefits of this judgment against that creature for only 1 round plus 1 additional round for every 5 by which you exceeded the DC to identify the target. Subsequent uses of this judgment do not stack with this ability. A creature cannot be the target of this ability again for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Banish Possessor" title="Banish Possessor" groups="" description="You are quite skilled at forcing a possessing creature from its host.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you cast a spell or use a spell-like ability or supernatural ability that allows a creature that is being possessed by another creature to attempt a new saving throw to end the spell or effect (such as protection from evil), the possessed creature can roll the new saving throw twice and take the better of the two results as the actual result.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Banishing Critical" title="Banishing Critical" groups="Combat,Critical" description="Contents">
	PPC:BoA
	With your combination of combat and spellcasting prowess, you send otherworldly monsters back to their place of origin.
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, ability to cast dismissal or banishment, caster level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you confirm a critical hit with a slashing or bludgeoning weapon, you may cast dismissal or banishment on that target as an immediate action, and the target takes a &#x2013;4 penalty on its Will save to resist the spell&apos;s effect. You must have dismissal or banishment prepared or otherwise available to cast, and using this ability casts the corresponding spell.</p>
			<p>PPC:MSH</p>
			<p>Your familiarity with summoning creatures has taught you how to send them away with a well-timed strike.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Strike or Disruptive; Spellcraft 8 ranks; arcane pool class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you confirm a critical hit against a target while using Arcane Strike or with a weapon enhanced by your arcane pool, if the target was summoned by a spell you identified using a Spellcraft check, it must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Intelligence modifier) or be sent back to its home plane as per the dismissal spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Banishing Critical - BoA" title="Banishing Critical" groups="Combat" description="With your combination of combat and spellcasting prowess, you send otherworldly monsters back to their place of origin.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, ability to cast dismissal or banishment, caster level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you confirm a critical hit with a slashing or bludgeoning weapon, you may cast dismissal or banishment on that target as an immediate action, and the target takes a -4 penalty on its Will save to resist the spell&apos;s effect. You must have dismissal or banishment prepared or otherwise available to cast, and using this ability casts the corresponding spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Banishing Critical - MSH" title="Banishing Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your familiarity with summoning creatures has taught you how to send them away with a well-timed strike.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Strike or Disruptive; Spellcraft 8 ranks; arcane pool class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you confirm a critical hit against a target while using Arcane Strike or with a weapon enhanced by your arcane pool, if the target was summoned by a spell you identified using a Spellcraft check, it must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Intelligence modifier) or be sent back to its home plane as per the dismissal spell.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Banner of Doom" title="Banner of Doom" groups="Combat" description="The mere sight of your fiendish banner is enough to send ripples of fear through your enemies.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +8, banner class feature, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long your banner is clearly visible, all enemies within 60 feet take a -2 penalty on saving throws against fear. This penalty does not stack with other effects that provide enemies with penalties on saving throws against fear.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Barracuda Dash" title="Barracuda Dash" groups="Combat" description="You use powerful, deadly bursts of speed to charge and attack an additional foe.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Barracuda Slam, Barracuda Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 7 ranks, Swim 7 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a swim speed equal to your base speed. When you attack on a charge in water or on land and the attack hits, you can immediately make a second charge attack against a second opponent. All the normal requirements for making a charge, such as moving at least 10 feet and moving in a straight line, apply to this second attack. The total distance of the two charge attacks cannot exceed the normal maximum distance for a charge (usually double your speed).</p>
			<p>The movement, including leaving the first target&apos;s threatened area, provokes attacks of opportunity as normally. You cannot use pounce or other abilities that grant extra attacks on your turn if you use Barracuda Dash to make a second attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Barracuda Slam" title="Barracuda Slam" groups="Combat" description="You learn to ram the whole weight of your body into an opponent to take it by surprise.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Barracuda Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 5 ranks, Swim 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>With a successful Swim check, you can move half your speed as a move action or your full speed as a full-round action. You can run and charge underwater, though the maximum distance you can move while doing so is half the normal maximum distance. Further, while making a charge attack in water or on land, you can add twice your Strength bonus on the damage roll for your first unarmed strike on your turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You cannot charge or run underwater unless you have a swim speed. With an unarmed strike, you usually add your Strength bonus on damage rolls.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Barracuda Style" title="Barracuda Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You study a combat style consisting of fluid, circular motions suited for moving and fighting underwater.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, Acrobatics 3 ranks, Swim 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your unarmed strikes deal normal damage underwater, and you don&apos;t take penalties on attack rolls with unarmed strikes made underwater. You add your Wisdom modifier in addition to your Strength modifier on Swim checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Attacks with bludgeoning weapons (such as unarmed strikes) deal half damage and take a -2 penalty on attack rolls underwater.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Barrage of Styles" title="Barrage of Styles" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="The diverse martial traditions of you and your allies' backgrounds blend into a unique combination.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a cumulative +1 morale bonus (maximum +4) on combat maneuver checks for each human ally who also has this feat, is threatening the same foe, and does not share an ethnicity with you or any other ally threatening that foe.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Barroom Brawler" title="Barroom Brawler" groups="Combat" description="You have learned how to mimic the combat tricks and forms of others.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +4.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day as a move action, you can gain the benefit of a combat feat that you do not possess for 1 minute. You must otherwise meet the feat&apos;s requirements.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the martial flexibility class feature, this feat instead grants you one additional use per day of that ability.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bashing Finish" title="Bashing Finish" groups="Combat" description="You follow a powerful blow from your weapon with an opportunistic bash from your shield.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Shield Bash, Shield Master, Two-Weapon Fighting, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit with a melee weapon, you can make a shield bash attack against the same target using the same bonus as a free action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Basic Harmony" title="Basic Harmony" groups="Teamwork" description="Your performance interweaves with and enriches your ally's skills.">
		<Prerequisites>Bardic performance or raging song.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can attempt a DC 10 Perform check to aid the Perform check of an ally who also has this feat. If you succeed, your ally gains a +1 bonus for each 5 points of your check result; a check result of 10 grants a +2 bonus, a result of 15 grants a +3 bonus, and so on. If you fail, the discord applies a &#x2013;5 penalty on your ally&apos;s check.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Aid another checks grant a +2 bonus.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Battering Repair" title="Battering Repair" groups="Grit" description="Sometimes smacking your firearm against a solid surface is all that's needed to unjam it. Sometimes that solid surface is a creature.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (alchemy) 3 ranks; grit class feature or Amateur Gunslinger; pistol-whip gunslinger deed; quick clear gunslinger deed.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can ignore the broken condition of a firearm you&apos;re wielding to perform the pistol-whip deed. If you hit a creature with this deed, you can spend 1 grit point as an immediate action to remove the broken condition from the firearm, but only if the firearm gained that condition from a misfire.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Battering Repair" title="Battering Repair" groups="Grit" description="Sometimes smacking your firearm against a solid surface is all that's needed to unjam it. Sometimes that solid surface is a creature.">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (alchemy) 3 ranks; grit class feature or Amateur Gunslinger; pistol-whip gunslinger deed; quick clear gunslinger deed.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can ignore the broken condition of a firearm you&apos;re wielding to perform the pistol-whip deed. If you hit a creature with this deed, you can spend 1 grit point as an immediate action to remove the broken condition from the firearm, but only if the firearm gained that condition from a misfire.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Battle Cry" title="Battle Cry" groups="Combat" description="Your shout heartens your allies and encourages them in the fight.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13; base attack bonus +5 or Perform (act, oratory, or sing) 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A number of times per day equal to your Charisma bonus, you can let out a battle cry as a swift action. When you do, allies within 30 feet who can hear you gain a +1 morale bonus on attack rolls and a +4 morale bonus on saving throws against fear. This effect lasts for 1 minute.</p>
			<p>If an ally is under the effect of this feat and fails a saving throw, she can choose to end the battle cry&apos;s effect on her to reroll the failed save against a fear effect. The ally must take the result of the reroll, even if it&apos;s lower. Each ally can use this effect only once per use of this feat.</p>
			<p>This is a combat feat, and can be selected as a brawler, fighter, gunslinger, swashbuckler, and warpriest bonus feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Battle Singer" title="Battle Singer" groups="Goblin" description="Your battle songs can drive your fellow goblins to new heights of frenzy.">
		<Prerequisites>Goblin, bardic performance class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using bardic performance to inspire courage in allies, you can choose to sing in Goblin&#x2014;allies who do not speak Goblin gain no benefits from this performance. Allied goblins who hear your battle songs become more energetic and brave, and thus add the bonus granted by your inspire courage ability to all saving throws as a morale bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bear Hug" title="Bear Hug" groups="Combat" description="You can crush your foes with your powerful arms.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 17, Beartrap Bite, Weapon Focus (bite), base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can attempt to initiate a grapple against a foe trapped by your Beartrap Bite feat without provoking attacks of opportunity. You gain a +2 bonus on damage rolls against foes you are grappling.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat is available to werebears, werebear-kin, and those who associate with these creatures.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bear's Balance" title="Bear's Balance" groups="Combat" description="Your anger is always available below the surface, but can be carefully directed. Those who would force you to lose control encounter an unpleasant surprise.">
		<Prerequisites>Iron Will, rage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Intimidate checks when not raging. When you fail a saving throw against a fear effect, you can choose to enter your rage rather than succumb to fear. You can not voluntarily end your rage until the fear effect expires or is ended in some other way (such as due to the death of the fear-inducing creature) or you exhaust your rounds of rage for the day. This feat has no effect if you are already raging when exposed to a fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Beartrap Bite" title="Beartrap Bite" groups="Combat" description="You can hold your foes even if you do not manage to grapple them.">
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus (bite), base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you confirm a critical hit against a foe with your bite attack, if your confirmation roll matches or exceeds your foe&apos;s CMD, you can clamp down on your foe to prevent it from moving away as a free action.</p>
			<p>The foe cannot move outside the area threatened by your bite attack unless it breaks free of your bite. It can attempt to free itself with a combat maneuver check or Escape Artist check as if you were grappling it, but neither of you gains the grappled condition. You cannot use your bite attack while you maintain your grip on your foe, but you can release the bite as a swift action to end the effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat is available to werebears, werebear-kin, and those who associated with these creatures.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Beast Hunter" title="Beast Hunter" groups="Combat" description="Thanks to your experience hunting in the wilds, you are capable of tracking animals in your most often traveled terrains, and you can easily take down animals larger than yourself.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1; Knowledge (nature) or Survival 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Pick one of the ranger&apos;s favored terrains. You gain a +2 bonus on Survival checks to track animals native to that terrain. Additionally, against animals native to that terrain that are at least one size category larger than you, you gain a +1 dodge bonus to your AC and a +1 insight bonus on attack rolls.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat multiple times. Each time you select this feat, you can choose an additional favored terrain to gain the listed benefits in.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Beast Rider" title="Beast Rider" groups="Orc/Half-Orc" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion or mount class feature, character level 7th, half-orc or orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one of the following creature types: elephant, pteranodon, rhinoceros, stegosaurus, or triceratops. Add this creature type to your list of possible animal companions or mounts. When summoning a creature of the selected type to serve as a mount or companion, treat your effective druid level as if it were two levels higher (to a maximum of your character level). If the creature is large enough for you to ride, it gains the combat training general purpose (see Handle Animal) at no cost.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Beastmaster Ire" title="Beastmaster Ire" groups="Combat" description="Seeing your animal companion attacked or hurt causes you to retaliate with a bestial fury of your own.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Alertness, Beastmaster Salvation, Beastmaster Style, Handle Animal 9 ranks, Sense Motive 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you activate Beastmaster Style&apos;s benefit, you gain a +2 morale bonus on melee weapon attack rolls and +4 morale bonus on weapon damage rolls against the attacking creature. If the enemy attack dealt damage to your animal companion, these bonuses increase to +4 and +8, respectively. These bonuses last until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Beastmaster Salvation" title="Beastmaster Salvation" groups="Combat" description="Your presence grants your companion the toughness and will to resist all manner of threats.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Alertness, Beastmaster Style, Handle Animal 5 ranks, Sense Motive 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you are adjacent to your animal companion when it attempts a saving throw, you can attempt a Handle Animal check as an immediate action. Your animal companion does not attempt the saving throw, but instead uses your Handle Animal result as its result for the save.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Beastmaster Style" title="Beastmaster Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your animal companion is your most treasured friend, and you steadfastly protect it from your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Handle Animal 1 rank, must have an animal companion.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you are adjacent to your animal companion and an attack is made against it, if you are also adjacent to the attacking creature, you can attempt a Handle Animal check as an immediate action to negate the hit. The hit is negated if your Handle Animal check result is greater than the attacker&apos;s attack roll.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You cannot use this style if you are mounted on your animal companion.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Befuddling Strike" title="Befuddling Strike" groups="Combat" description="You know just where to strike to temporarily send your enemy into a confused stupor.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Wis 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Befuddling Strike forces a foe damaged by your unarmed attack to attempt a Fortitude saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Wisdom modifier), in addition to dealing damage normally. You must declare that you are using this feat before you make your attack roll&#x2014;thus, a failed attack roll ruins the attempt. A defender who fails this saving throw is confused for 1d4 rounds. You can attempt to use Befuddling Strike once per day for every 4 character levels you have, but can use it no more than once per round. Constructs, incorporeal creatures, mindless creatures, plants, undead, and creatures that are immune to critical hits cannot be affected by this ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Believer's Boon" title="Believer's Boon" groups="" description="Your deity rewards you for your faithfulness.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, alignment must be within one step of your deity&apos;s.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you take this feat, choose one domain granted by your deity. You can use the 1st-level domain ability that clerics of that domain can use a number of times or rounds per day, but you can use it only once per day or 1 round per day, whichever is appropriate. Your effective cleric level in regard to this ability is 1st level. If the domain has a 1st-level ability that does not meet this specification, you cannot use it.</p>
			<p>Choose one domain granted by your deity. Once per day, you can use all 1st-level domain abilities granted to </p>
			<p>clerics of that domain. You gain access to this one ability only, not the higher-level domain ability, domain spells, or additional class skills that the domain might grant, or any bonus feats that are listed under its granted powers. Your effective </p>
			<p>cleric level in regard to this ability is 1st level. </p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can take this feat twice. When you take it a second time, you choose another domain granted by your deity.</p>
			<p>If you grossly violate the code of conduct required by your deity, your alignment shifts so that it is more than one step away from your deity&apos;s, or you no longer worship your deity, you lose access to this feat. You can regain it once you atone for your misdeeds to your deity (see the atonement spell).</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Believer's Hands" title="Believer's Hands" groups="" description="You can heal others with a touch of your hand.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, Believer&apos;s Boon, must be lawful good, alignment must be within one step of your deity&apos;s.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day, you can use the paladin&apos;s lay on hands ability. Your effective paladin level is equal to 1/2 your character level (minimum 1). If you already have (or later gain) the lay on hands ability, you instead gain one extra use of lay on hands each day.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This feat counts as having the lay on hands ability for the purpose of qualifying for feats such as Extra Lay on Hands.</p>
			<p>If you grossly violate the code of conduct required by your deity, your alignment shifts so that it is more than one step away from your deity&apos;s, or you no longer worship your deity, you lose access to this feat. You can regain it once you atone for your misdeeds to your deity (see the atonement spell).</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Benthic Spell" title="Benthic Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Explorers in the depths of the Arcadian Ocean have learned that deadly pressure can be just as lethal as any flame.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can modify a spell that deals acid, cold, electricity, or fire damage to deal damage through high-pressure water instead. The spell gains the water descriptor, and you can either replace the spell&apos;s normal damage with bludgeoning damage or split the spell&apos;s damage so that half is bludgeoning and half is of its normal type. Creatures with damage reduction apply their damage reduction to bludgeoning damage from a benthic spell, but the spell counts as bludgeoning and magic for the purposes of bypassing damage reduction.</p>
			<p>A benthic spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bestow Hope" title="Bestow Hope" groups="" description="You instill hope in the creatures you heal.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Channel, channel energy class feature, worshiper of a good deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you heal a creature by channeling positive energy, you also relieve its fear. If a creature you heal is shaken, that condition ends. If the creature is frightened, it becomes shaken instead. If the creature is panicked, it becomes frightened instead.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bestow Luck" title="Bestow Luck" groups="Human" description="You are extremely lucky and sometimes your allies are as well.">
		<Prerequisites>Defiant Luck, Inexplicable Luck, human.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain an extra use per day of your Defiant Luck ability. You can also use your Inexplicable Luck ability to grant an ally that can see and hear its benefit as an immediate action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Betrayal Sense" title="Betrayal Sense" groups="Combat" description="You can sense betrayal and intrigue as well as physical traps.">
		<Prerequisites>Wis 13, rogue level 3rd, trap sense class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a bonus on Perception checks to pierce another creature&apos;s disguise and Sense Motive checks to avoid being surprised by an attack. These bonuses are equal to the bonus you gain from trap sense.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Betrayer" title="Betrayer" groups="" description="You can charm people into lowering their defenses, allowing you to ambush them more effectively.">
		<Prerequisites>Quick Draw, Persuasive, base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you succeed at a Diplomacy check to change a creature&apos;s attitude, you can draw a weapon and make a single melee attack against that creature as an immediate action. If you changed your target&apos;s attitude to friendly or better, your target is considered flat-footed against this attack. If the target survives, it takes a &#x2013;2 penalty on its initiative check for this combat. Once you attack a creature, its attitude becomes hostile.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Betraying Blow" title="Betraying Blow" groups="Combat" description="When you break an alliance, you make sure it's broken for good.">
		<Prerequisites>Solo Maneuvers, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you use a melee attack to deal nonlethal damage to a creature that only you threaten, roll a Bluff check opposed by your opponent&apos;s Sense Motive check. You deal an additional amount of nonlethal damage equal to 1/2 the difference between your Bluff check and your opponent&apos;s Sense Motive check (minimum 0). If your opponent has an attitude of friendly or helpful toward you (including temporarily due to Intimidate checks, charm person, and similar effects), you instead deal an amount of extra nonlethal damage equal to the difference between your checks. Regardless, the amount of extra nonlethal damage you deal with this feat cannot exceed your Hit Dice.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bewildering Koan" title="Bewildering Koan" groups="" description="You can pose unanswerable questions that leave creatures momentarily dumbfounded as they dwell on their significance.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, ki pool class feature, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a swift action, spend 1 point from your ki pool and make a Bluff check by asking a creature one of the impossible questions you ponder when meditating.</p>
			<p>If the creature fails its check*, you choose whether it loses its next action or you gain a +2 bonus on all damage rolls you make against that creature for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Big Game Hunter" title="Big Game Hunter" groups="Local" description="	<Benefit>">
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls and a +2 bonus on weapon damage rolls against Large or larger creatures.</p>
		
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Binding Throw" title="Binding Throw" groups="Combat" description="You can strike your enemy and use the blow as an opportunity to grab and hold him.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Grapple, Improved Trip, Improved Unarmed Strike, Ki Throw.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>After you successfully use the Ki Throw feat on an opponent, you can use a swift action to attempt a grapple combat maneuver against that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The grapple combat maneuver is a standard action.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk can gain Binding Throw as a bonus feat starting at 14th level.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Black Cat" title="Black Cat" groups="Catfolk" description="Bad luck befalls those who dare to cross you.">
		<Prerequisites>Catfolk.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day as an immediate action, when you are hit by a melee attack, you can force the opponent who made the attack to reroll it with a &#x2013;4 penalty. The opponent must take the result of the second attack roll. This is a supernatural ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you take this feat and don&apos;t already have all black fur, your fur turns completely black when you takes this feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Black Marketeer" title="Black Marketeer" groups="" description="You have many contacts and a keen eye for hidden opportunities in the marketplace.">
		<Prerequisites>Appraise 1 rank, Diplomacy 1 rank, Knowledge (Local) 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>By utilizing your black market connections, you acquire a resource pool worth 100 gp. This can only be used on illegal or illicit items or services (note that something may be illegal or illicit in one area but perfectly acceptable in another).</p>
			<p>Typical illegal or illicit items are drugs, poisons, evil magic items, slaves, or dead bodies, though intangibles such as secret information may also qualify (and for these items, a secret of equal value&#x2014;at the GM&apos;s discretion&#x2014;must be contributed to the pool).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Black Powder Spectacle" title="Black Powder Spectacle" groups="Combat, Grit, Performance" description="You can sacrifice ammunition to make a grand spectacle.">
		<Prerequisites>Amateur Gunslinger or the grit class feature, base attack bonus +4</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you spend a swift action to attempt a performance combat check, you can sacrifice one cartridge or an amount of black powder required for a single shot to make either a loud sound or an impressive flash. If you choose to make your weapon&apos;s report louder, you gain a +4 bonus on all Intimidate checks you attempt for 1 round. If you choose to create an impressive flash, you gain a +4 bonus on any Perform checks you attempt for 1 round.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points when using Black Powder Spectacle in order to gain a +4 bonus on Intimidate checks and Perform checks for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blade Binder" title="Blade Binder" groups="Combat" description="Not only are you skilled at binding your opponent's weapon, you can seize the advantage while he struggles to retrieve his blade.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +4, proficiency with khopesh or temple sword.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You receive a +2 bonus on CMB checks made to bind an opponent&apos;s weapon, as well as any opposed checks to maintain the bind. This bonus stacks with the +2 bonus from wielding a khopesh or temple sword. If you succeed in blade binding your opponent, your opponent becomes flat-footed until he either wrestles his blade free or drops his weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A monk may add Blade Binder to their bonus feat list at 6th level.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bladed Brush" title="Bladed Brush" groups="Combat" description="Note: This is associated with a specific deity.">
You know how to balance a polearm perfectly, striking with artful, yet deadly precision.
		<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus (glaive), must be a worshiper of the associated deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use the Weapon Finesse feat to apply your Dexterity modifier instead of your Strength modifier to attack rolls with a glaive sized for you, even though it isn&apos;t a light weapon. When wielding a glaive, you can treat it as a one-handed piercing or slashing melee weapon and as if you were not making attacks with your off-hand for all feats and class abilities that require such a weapon (such as a duelist&apos;s or swashbuckler&apos;s precise strike).</p>
			<p>As a move action, you can shorten your grip on the glaive, treating it as though it lacked the reach weapon property. You can adjust your grip to grant the weapon the reach property as a move action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blades Above And Below" title="Blades Above And Below" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You attack high and your ally attacks low, denying your foe the chance to dodge your attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you and your ally who also has this feat threaten the same enemy, you&apos;re both considered to be flanking that enemy, regardless of your actual positioning. To gain this benefit, you and your ally must be of different size categories, and your target must be the same size category as either you or your ally.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blasting Charge" title="Blasting Charge" groups="" description="You funnel the power of your bloodrage into a strike capable of erupting with arcane power.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +7, ability to cast 2nd-level bloodrager spells, bloodrage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are bloodraging, at the end of a charge you can expend a bloodrager spell slot as a swift action to imbue your charge attack with extra power. You deal an additional 1d6 points of damage per level of the spell slot expended. This extra damage is force damage, and it&apos;s not multiplied in the case of a critical hit.</p>
			<p>If your bloodline has a specific energy type associated with it (such as the elemental or draconic bloodlines), you can choose to increase the damage to 1d8 points per level of the spell slot expended, and this extra damage is of that energy type.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blazing Aura" title="Blazing Aura" groups="Combat, Conduit" description="You cover yourself in coils of flame drawn from the Plane of Fire.">
		<Prerequisites>Knowledge (planes) 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can shroud yourself in fire. Until the end of your turn, whenever a creature makes a successful melee attack against you, that creature takes a number of points of fire damage equal to 1d6 plus half your ranks in Knowledge (planes); attacks made using reach weapons ignore this effect. A creature can halve this fire damage with a successful Reflex save (DC = 10 + half your level + your Constitution modifier).</p>
			<p>You can use this feat&apos;s benefit a number of times per day equal to your ranks in Knowledge (planes). If you have at least 9 ranks in Knowledge (planes), activating this ability is a move action. If you have at least 15 ranks in Knowledge (planes), you can activate this ability as a move action or a swift action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blazing Aura - Ifrit" title="Blazing Aura" groups="Combat, Ifrit" description="An inferno rages inside you, causing your body to radiate intense heat.">
		<Prerequisites>Inner Flame, Scorching Weapons, character level 13th, Ifrit.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use Scorching Weapons, on your turn as a free action, you may create an aura of heat that lasts for 1 round. This aura deals 1d6 points of fire damage to any creature that begins its turn adjacent to you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blazing Channel" title="Blazing Channel" groups="" description="Your holy power burns the undead like fire.">
		<Prerequisites>Turn Undead, channel positive energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you use your Turn Undead feat, undead failing their saving throw are engulfed in holy fire. This functions identically to catching on fire, but the damage dealt is divine (like the divine damage from flame strike) rather than fire. Water cannot extinguish this holy fire, but any negative energy effect that heals the creature of at least 5 points of damage extinguishes the flames instantly.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bleeding Attack" title="Bleeding Attack" groups="Combat" description="Your unarmed strikes cause your opponent to bleed.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you damage an opponent with an unarmed strike, you deal an extra 1d4 bleed damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>This ability does not stack with other special abilities, attacks, or items that allow you to deal bleed damage.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bleeding Critical" title="Bleeding Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits cause opponents to bleed profusely.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +11.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit with a slashing or piercing weapon, your opponent takes 2d6 points of bleed damage each round on his turn, in addition to the damage dealt by the critical hit. Bleed damage can be stopped by a DC 15 Heal skill check or through any magical healing. The effects of this feat stack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bleeding Stare" title="Bleeding Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your stare causes your foe to bleed out of its eyes.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 5th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you trigger your painful stare, the target takes an amount of bleed damage equal to 1/3 your mesmerist level. Bleed damage from multiple uses of Bleeding Stare doesn&apos;t stack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bless Equipment" title="Bless Equipment" groups="" description="You can bless armor and weapons with a touch to imbue them with magical properties.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 3rd, channel energy class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you may expend uses of your channel energy ability to touch a single weapon, suit of armor, or shield and temporarily grant it one weapon, armor, or shield special ability. To bless a piece of equipment with a particular blessing, you must expend a number of uses of channel energy equal to the number listed in the table above, and your caster level must be equal to or greater than that listed for the selected blessing.</p>
			<p>This blessing lasts for a number of rounds equal to the number of damage dice you are capable of dealing or healing with your channel energy ability (for example, the blessing of a cleric capable of channeling 3d6 points of damage would last for 3 rounds), during which time the item is treated as though it possessed the selected special ability. If the piece of equipment belongs to an unwilling creature, that creature may attempt a Will save to prevent the blessing, as if attempting a saving throw against your channel energy ability (so bonuses from channel resistance and similar effects apply); if the creature succeeds at its save, the channeled energy is expended to no effect.</p>
			<p>Only magical and masterwork weapons, armor, and shields may be blessed with this feat. When you bless a masterwork item, you must expend one additional use of your channel energy ability beyond those normally expended to grant the selected blessing. In addition to the selected blessing, the masterwork item gains a temporary +1 enhancement bonus for the blessing&apos;s duration.</p>
			<p>You can grant a piece of equipment only one blessing at a time. Blessing an item that has already been blessed by you or another character replaces the preexisting blessing with the new one and resets the duration.</p>
			<p>* You must choose the creature type or subtype at the time of blessing.</p>
			<p>* Cannot be applied to shields.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blessed Striker" title="Blessed Striker" groups="" description="You attacks are augmented by the strength of your and your deity's shared alignment.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +11, ability to cast divine spells, alignment must be within one step of your deity&apos;s.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>All of your attacks are treated as having whatever alignment components you and your deity share for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you grossly violate the code of conduct required by your deity or no longer worship your deity, you lose access to this feat. You can regain it once you atone for your misdeeds to your deity (see the atonement spell).</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blight Guide" title="Blight Guide" groups="" description="Your confidence in exploring dangerous regions inspires the same in your companions.">
		<Prerequisites>Blight Survivalist, Skill Focus (Survival).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your bonus on saving throws gained from the Blight Survivalist feat extends to your allies within 30 feet. Furthermore, once per day, if you would fail a saving throw against an environmental hazard or weather effect, you can reroll that save, but you must use the second result, even if it is lower.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blight Survivalist" title="Blight Survivalist" groups="" description="You have learned to survive in dangerous environments.">
		<Prerequisites>Skill Focus (Survival).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus on saving throws against environmental hazards and weather effects.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>If you have the favored terrain class feature and the blighted land being explored matches one of those terrains, you can choose to use your favored terrain bonus in place of the +3 bonus granted by this feat.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blighted Critical" title="Blighted Critical" groups="Critical" description="With a critical hit from a spell or spell-like ability, you give the target a minor spellblight.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you confirm a critical hit with a touch spell, ranged touch spell, or spell-like ability against an opponent, the victim gains a random minor spellblight.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can apply the effects of only one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blighted Critical Mastery" title="Blighted Critical Mastery" groups="" description="You control the type of spellblight your critical hits give your opponent.">
		<Prerequisites>Blighted Critical, caster level 9th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you apply a spellblight by way of the Blighted Critical or Greater Blighted Critical feat, you can choose the spellblight you apply rather than determining it randomly.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blind-Fight" title="Blind-Fight" groups="Combat" description="You are skilled at attacking opponents that you cannot clearly perceive.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>In melee, every time you miss because of concealment (see Combat), you can reroll your miss chance percentile roll one time to see if you actually hit.</p>
			<p>An invisible attacker gets no advantages related to hitting you in melee. That is, you don&apos;t lose your Dexterity bonus to Armor Class, and the attacker doesn&apos;t get the usual +2 bonus for being invisible. The invisible attacker&apos;s bonuses do still apply for ranged attacks, however.</p>
			<p>You do not need to make Acrobatics skill checks to move at full speed while blinded.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Regular attack roll modifiers for invisible attackers trying to hit you apply, and you lose your Dexterity bonus to AC. The speed reduction for darkness and poor visibility also applies.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>The Blind-Fight feat is of no use against a character who is the subject of a blink spell.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinded Blade Style" title="Blinded Blade Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You hold no fear of blindness, as your other senses improve without the distractions of sight.">
		<Prerequisites>Blind-Fight, Perception 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using this style, you gain a number of benefits whenever you are blinded or unable to see (including when you wear a blindfold or close your eyes). Under such circumstances, you do not take any penalties on Strength- or Dexterity-based skill checks due to blindness. In addition, you gain a +4 bonus on hearing- and smell-based Perception checks and gain the scent special ability with a range of 10 feet; if you already have scent, the range of your scent ability increases by 10 feet instead. Having this feat counts as having 10 ranks in Perception for the purpose of satisfying the prerequisites of the Improved Blind-Fight feat, as well as any feat that lists Improved Blind-Fight as a prerequisite.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinded Competence" title="Blinded Competence" groups="Combat" description="Your lack of sight enables you to strike your foes with uncanny precision.">
		<Prerequisites>Blinded Blade Style, Blind-Fight, Improved Blind-Fight, Perception 10 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Blinded Blade Style and you are blinded or unable to see, you do not need to succeed at Perception checks to pinpoint the location of creatures within reach of your melee weapon, or your unmodified reach if you are not wielding a melee weapon. This ability functions like blindsense, except creatures you cannot see do not gain total concealment against you. Having this feat counts as having 15 ranks in Perception for the purpose of satisfying the prerequisites of the Greater Blind-Fight feat, as well as any feat that lists Greater Blind-Fight as a prerequisite.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinded Master" title="Blinded Master" groups="Combat" description="Your skill at arms while unable to see is astounding.">
		<Prerequisites>Blind-Fight, Blinded Blade Precision (Blinded Competence?), Blinded Blade Style, Greater Blind-Fight, Improved Blind-Fight, Perception 15 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Blinded Blade Style and you are blinded or unable to see, your ability to pinpoint creatures&apos; locations using Blinded Competence improves to function like blindsight rather than blindsense, and the range increases to 30 feet. In addition, you add half your character level to the DCs of Bluff checks to feint you in combat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinding Critical" title="Blinding Critical" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits blind your opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Critical Focus, base attack bonus +15.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit, your opponent is permanently blinded. A successful Fortitude save reduces this to dazzled for 1d4 rounds. The DC of this Fortitude save is equal to 10 + your base attack bonus. This feat has no effect on creatures that do not rely on eyes for sight or creatures with more than two eyes (although multiple critical hits might cause blindness, at the GM&apos;s discretion). Blindness can be cured by heal, regenerate, remove blindness, or similar abilities.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one critical feat to a given critical hit unless you possess Critical Mastery.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinding Flash" title="Blinding Flash" groups="Combat" description="You can temporarily blind your opponent by using your weapon or shield to flash sunlight into its eyes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Combat Expertise.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a move action, you can expertly angle the blade of your weapon or shield to reflect light into an opponent&apos;s eyes, dazzling your foe for 1 round. This feat functions as a gaze attack, and the target must make a Fortitude save (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Dex modifier) to resist the effect. This is a sight-dependent effect, and does not work on creatures that are already blinded or creatures that do not rely on sight as their primary sense. You must be wielding a weapon or shield with a polished or reflective surface in order to use this feat. You must be in an area of bright light to use this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinding Light" title="Blinding Light" groups="" description="You use your impenetrable luminescence to disorient harbingers of darkness.">
		<Prerequisites>Inner Light, aasimar, daylight spell-like ability.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever an enemy unsuccessfully attempts to counter or dispel your daylight spell-like ability, it must succeed at a Fortitude saving throw (DC 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Charisma modifier) or become blinded for 1 round as its mind is overwhelmed with celestial light. This is a supernatural mind-affecting effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinding Sneak Attack" title="Blinding Sneak Attack" groups="Combat" description="When you strike from the cover of darkness, you inject foes with a fraction of your foul magic.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +5, darkness spell-like ability, sneak attack class feature, tiefling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully deal sneak attack damage to a foe while you are within an area of magical darkness, you temporarily blind your opponent for 1 round. A successful Fortitude save (DC 10 + the amount of sneak attack damage dealt) negates this effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blinding Stare" title="Blinding Stare" groups="Combat" description="Your stare robs your foe of all sight.">
		<Prerequisites>Mesmerist level 7th, painful stare class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you trigger your painful stare, the target must succeed at a Will save (DC = 10 + half your mesmerist level + your Charisma modifier) or be blinded for 1 round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blissful Spell" title="Blissful Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="The absolute peace of Nirvana infuses your spells, giving pause to foes and granting boldness to allies.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can alter any spell that targets a single creature to become a blissful spell, although the exact effects of the metamagic vary depending on whether the spell is beneficial or offensive. A creature successfully hit by an offensive blissful spell (if the spell requires an attack roll) or that fails its saving throw against an offensive blissful spell takes a &#x2013;2 penalty on attack rolls and weapon damage rolls for 1 round. A beneficial blissful spell instead grants affected creatures a +2 morale bonus on skill checks and saving throws for 1 round in addition to its normal effects.</p>
			<p>A blissful spell gains the good descriptor, and the additional effect is a mind-affecting compulsion effect.A blissful spell uses a spell slot 1 level higher than the spell&apos;s normal spell level. Spells with the evil descriptor can&apos;t be blissful spells.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blistering Feint" title="Blistering Feint" groups="Combat,Ifrit" description="Your foes flinch from the heat of your weapon, giving you an opportunity to slip past their defenses.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Expertise, Improved Feint, Ifrit.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on feint checks made while wielding a weapon that deals fire damage. Anytime you successfully feint a creature while using such a weapon, you may deal its fire damage to the enemy.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Beak" title="Blood Beak" groups="Combat,Tengu" description="Your bleed attack is bloody and dangerous.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +5, natural weapon racial trait, tengu.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Increase the damage of your beak attack to 1d6. Furthermore, when you confirm a critical hit with your beak attack, you also deal 1 point of bleed damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>The bleed effect from this feat stacks with that of the Bleeding Critical feat and similar effects, adding 1 point to your bleed damage.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Disciple" title="Blood Disciple" groups="" description="Your research has gained attention which rewards you with access to its libraries.">
		<Prerequisites>Associate (a temple).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Once per day you can combine your own blood and a vial of unholy water to create a potion of cure light wounds or a potion of inflict light wounds as a full-round action. This blood loss deals 1 point of Constitution damage to you. In addition, in any settlement that is the size of a small town or larger, you can always find scrolls of the following spells available for purchase regardless of their legality: animate dead, control undead, create undead, detect undead, disrupt undead, false life, greater false life, ghoul touch, lesser animate dead, mass repair undead, repair undead, and undead anatomy I&#x2013;IV.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Drinker" title="Blood Drinker" groups="Dhampir" description="Consuming blood reinvigorates you.">
		<Prerequisites>Dhampir.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Choose one humanoid subtype, such as &#x201C;goblinoid&#x201D; (this subtype cannot be &#x201C;dhampir&#x201D;). You have acquired a taste for the blood of creatures with this subtype. Whenever you drink fresh blood from such a creature, you gain 5 temporary hit points and a +1 bonus on checks and saves based on Constitution. The effects last 1 hour. If you feed multiple times, you continue to gain hit points to a maximum of 5 temporary hit points for every three Hit Dice you have, but the +1 bonus on Constitution-based skill checks and saving throws does not stack.</p>
			<p>Normally, you can only drink blood from an opponent who is helpless, grappled, paralyzed, pinned, unconscious, or similarly disabled. If you have a bite attack, you can drink blood automatically as part of your bite attack; otherwise, you must first cut your target by dealing 1 hit point of damage with a slashing or piercing weapon (though you may feed upon a creature with severe wounds or a bleed effect without cutting it first). Once you cut the target, you can drink from its wound as a standard action. Drinking blood deals 2 points of Constitution damage to the creature you feed upon. The blood must come from a living creature of the specified humanoid subtype. It cannot come from a dead or summoned creature. Feeding on unwilling intelligent creatures is an evil act.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Feast" title="Blood Feast" groups="Combat, Monster" description="You become more aggressive and vicious when you taste living flesh and blood.">
		<Prerequisites>Bite attack.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you damage a living creature with your bite attack, you gain a +1 morale bonus on attack and damage rolls with your bite attack until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Feaster" title="Blood Feaster" groups="Dhampir" description="Consuming blood gives you superhuman strength.">
		<Prerequisites>Blood Drinker, base attack bonus +6, dhampir.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you use your Blood Drinker feat to drain 4 or more points of Constitution from a living creature, you gain a +2 bonus on damage rolls and a +1 bonus on Strength-based skill checks. This bonus lasts for a number of rounds equal to 1/2 your Hit Dice.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Frenzy Assault" title="Blood Frenzy Assault" groups="Combat" description="The scent of blood intensifies your fury, and every wound you tear into your foes increases both your drive and ability to wreak havoc.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 17, Blood Frenzy Strike, Blood Frenzy Style, Bloody Assault, Improved Unarmed Strike, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6, aquatic subtype.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Blood Frenzy Style, when you make a full attack, you can make an additional unarmed or natural weapon attack for each enemy within your reach that is affected by a bleed effect. Until your next turn, you take a -2 penalty to AC for each additional attack gained in this way. In addition, the bleed damage your unarmed strikes deal from Blood Frenzy Strike increases to 2d6 points of bleed damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Frenzy Strike" title="Blood Frenzy Strike" groups="Combat" description="Your strikes tear at an opponent's flesh, inflicting serious wounds, and you can unleash all of your pent-up rage in a single powerful blow.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Blood Frenzy Style, Improved Unarmed Strike, Power Attack, base attack bonus +4, aquatic subtype.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Blood Frenzy Style, when you damage an opponent with your unarmed strikes or natural attacks, you deal an extra 1d6 points of bleed damage; this bleed damage does not stack with itself. Once every 1d4 rounds, you can make an unarmed attack with a -5 penalty; if you hit, you deal an additional 2d6 points of bludgeoning damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Frenzy Style" title="Blood Frenzy Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You have learned to turn your pain into power, whipping yourself into a blood frenzy whenever you take damage.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +1, aquatic subtype.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are using Blood Frenzy Style, you gain a +2 bonus to your Strength and Constitution, and you take a -2 penalty to AC.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can enter Blood Frenzy Style only as an immediate action when you take damage. You cannot enter this style as a swift action, as with other style feats.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Salvage" title="Blood Salvage" groups="Dhampir" description="You do not need to drink blood from a living creature to gain healing benefits.">
		<Prerequisites>Blood Drinker, dhampir.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can use your Blood Drinker feat on a dead creature of the appropriate humanoid subtype. The creature must have died less than 6 hours beforehand.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You only benefit from the Blood Drinker feat if you consume fresh blood from a living creature.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Spurt" title="Blood Spurt" groups="Combat" description="When cut in combat, you spray your blood into the faces of your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +2, susceptibility to bleed damage.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever a creature adjacent to you hits you with a melee attack that deals bleed damage, that creature must succeed at a Fortitude save (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Constitution modifier) or become blinded for 1d4 rounds as your blood sprays it in the face.</p>
			<p>Additionally, if you have a special ability that deals bleed damage (such as a rogue&apos;s bleeding strike rogue talent), as a standard action, you can deal 1 point of bleed damage to yourself to spray blood in the face of an adjacent creature of your choice, causing the same effect. The creature only needs to attempt the saving throw for the first of its attacks that deals bleed damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Ties" title="Blood Ties" groups="" description="Pointing out your shared kinship with someone gives you the chance to win over creatures associated with your bloodline.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 1 rank, bloodline class feature, gnome.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When attempting a Diplomacy check to influence a creature with a plausible connection to your sorcerous bloodline, you may instead make a Bluff check. For example, a gnome sorcerer with the draconic bloodline may use this feat against dragons and their kin, but no other creatures.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood Vengeance" title="Blood Vengeance" groups="Orc/Half-orc" description="Seeing an ally fall in combat fills you with a raging and murderous fury.">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc or orcs, nonlawful.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever one of your allies is reduced to negative hit points or killed, you may enter a state similar to but less powerful than a barbarian&apos;s rage as a free action on your next turn. If you have the rage class feature and are already raging, your morale bonuses to Strength and Constitution increase by +2 for the duration of your rage. If you do not have the rage class feature, or you have no more rage rounds left, this weaker rage gives you all the benefits and penalties of a barbarian&apos;s rage, except your morale bonus to Strength and Constitution is only +2. In either case, this state lasts for 4 rounds.</p>
			<p>As with a barbarian&apos;s rage, when this weaker rage ends, you are fatigued; if another ally falls before this duration ends, the weaker rage lasts for an additional 4 rounds. This feat does not allow you to enter a rage if you are fatigued. You may only use this feat if the fallen ally had at least as many Hit Dice as you (excluding conjured or summoned allies).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blood of Heroes" title="Blood of Heroes" groups="Luck" description="You have a sense of destiny about you and always seem to succeed, even when the odds are against you.">
		<Prerequisites>Hero&apos;s Fortune.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you gain a level, you gain 2 hero points instead of 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Whenever you gain a level, you gain 1 hero point.</p>
			<p>Note: See Hero Points for full details.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blooded Arcane Strike" title="Blooded Arcane Strike" groups="Combat" description="Arcane energy guides your devastating attack.">
		<Prerequisites>Arcane Strike, ability to cast arcane spells, bloodrage class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you are bloodraging, you don&apos;t need to spend a swift action to use your Arcane Strike&#x2014;it is always in effect. When you use this ability with Vital Strike, Improved Vital Strike, or Greater Vital Strike, the bonus on damage rolls for Arcane Strike is multiplied by the number of times (two, three, or four) you roll damage dice for one of those feats.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bloodletting" title="Bloodletting" groups="Combat" description="When you attack with a piercing or slashing weapon, the wounds you cause bleed profusely.">
		<Prerequisites>Worshiper of a deity of darkness, loss, or pain</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you threaten a critical hit with a piercing or slashing weapon (regardless of whether you confirm the critical hit or not), you deal 1 point of bleed damage to the targeted creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bloody Assault" title="Bloody Assault" groups="Combat" description="Sacrificing accuracy, you can inflict bloody wounds that are slow to heal.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Power Attack, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can choose to take a -5 penalty on all melee attack rolls and combat maneuver checks to inflict 1d4 points of bleed damage with your weapon melee attacks, in addition to the normal damage dealt by the weapon. A creature continues to take bleed damage every round at the start of its turn. Bleed damage can be stopped by a DC 15 Heal check or through any magical healing. Bleed damage from this feat does not stack with itself. You must choose to use this feat before making the attack roll, and its effects last until your next turn (although the bleeding lasts until healed, as normal).</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bloody Mess" title="Bloody Mess" groups="Combat" description="Your recklessness often puts you in harm's way, and you are terrifying to behold when covered in your own blood.">
		<Prerequisites>Skill Focus (Intimidate).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you take an amount of piercing, slashing, or bleed damage equal to or greater than double your character level, you can attempt an Intimidate check as an immediate action to demoralize the creature that dealt the damage as long as it is within 30 feet of you. If the damage resulted from a critical hit, you can cause the target creature to be sickened instead of shaken if you successfully demoralize it. You can use this feat only once per round to attempt an Intimidate check to demoralize an opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bloody Sabres" title="Bloody Sabres" groups="Combat" description="Imitating the forms of your god, you strike deep and inflict a bloody wound.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Exotic Weapon Proficiency (sawtooth sabre), Two-Weapon Fighting, worshiper of a deity of blood, death, or assassination.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If you hit an opponent with both your primary weapon and your off-hand weapon as part of the same attack action, and both of those weapons are sawtooth sabres, you deal 1 point of bleed damage in addition to the normal damage dealt by these attacks.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 2 stamina points when dealing bleed damage with the Bloody Sabres feat to increase the amount of bleed damage your opponent takes by 1.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bloody Vengeance" title="Bloody Vengeance" groups="Combat" description="Your retaliatory strikes have long-lasting effects.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, worshiper of a chaotic neutral deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>If an opponent within line of sight has damaged you within the last minute, you may study that opponent as a standard action. Thereafter, if you hit that opponent with a melee attack, you deal 1 point of bleed damage to that creature in addition to the normal damage dealt by your attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bludgeoner" title="Bludgeoner" groups="Combat" description="You can knock foes out cold with just about any blunt instrument.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>You take no penalty on attack rolls for using a lethal bludgeoning weapon to deal nonlethal damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You take a -4 penalty on attack rolls when using a lethal weapon to deal nonlethal damage. You cannot use a lethal weapon to deal nonlethal damage in a sneak attack.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>A rogue with this feat can use a lethal bludgeoning weapon to deal nonlethal damage with a sneak attack.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blundering Defense" title="Blundering Defense" groups="Combat, Halfling" description="Your feverish and sometimes comical defensive techniques offer enough distraction to aid allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Cautious Fighter, halfling.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you fight defensively or use the total defense action, allies gain a luck bonus to AC and CMD equal to 1/2 the dodge bonus you gain from the action you are taking. Allies only gain this bonus while they are adjacent to you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Blustering Bluff" title="Blustering Bluff" groups="" description="You can verbally bully others into believing unlikely or outrageous lies.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Bluff 1 rank, Intimidate 1 rank.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When using Bluff to fool a foe, you can bully that person to reduce the penalty for telling an unlikely or far-fetched lie by 5. If you do so and your check would not have succeeded otherwise, after 1d6&#xD7;10 minutes, the person you fooled realizes you bullied him into believing a lie, treats you as unfriendly, and might report you or take other actions against you.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The penalty for telling unlikely lies is &#x2013;5, and the penalty for telling far-fetched lies is &#x2013;10.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Boar Ferocity" title="Boar Ferocity" groups="Combat" description="Your flesh-ripping unarmed strikes terrify your victims.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Boar Style, Intimidate 6 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You add piercing damage to the damage types you can deal with your unarmed strikes. Further, you gain a +2 bonus on Intimidate checks to demoralize opponents. While using Boar Style, whenever you tear an opponent&apos;s flesh, you can spend a free action to make an Intimidate check to demoralize that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Boar Shred" title="Boar Shred" groups="Combat" description="The wounds you inflict with your unarmed strikes bleed, giving you renewed vigor.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Boar Ferocity, Boar Style, Intimidate 9 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can make an Intimidate check to demoralize an opponent as a move action. While using Boar Style, whenever you tear an opponent&apos;s flesh, once per round at the start of that opponent&apos;s turn he takes 1d6 bleed damage. The bleed damage dealt while using Boar Style persist even if you later switch to a different style.</p>
			<p>FAQ</p>
			<p>Boar Style seems to deal 2d6 bleed damage, which by the normal rules of bleed damage would apply each round, but then Boar Shred, which requires Boar Style and a much higher level, deals 1d6 bleed damage and specifies that it happens on each round. Did Boar Style mean something else?</p>
			<p>Yes, Boar Style means to say that it deals 2d6 additional damage once when you hit a foe twice, similar to the rend ability, and then Boar Shred actually does 1d6 ongoing bleed damage. This will be reflected in future errata.</p>
			<p>[Source]</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Boar Style" title="Boar Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Your sharp teeth and nails rip your foes open.">
		<Prerequisites>Improved Unarmed Strike, Intimidate 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can deal bludgeoning damage or slashing damage with your unarmed strikes&#x2014;changing damage type is a free action. While using this style, once per round when you hit a single foe with two or more unarmed strikes, you can tear flesh. When you do, you deal 2d6 extra points of damage with the attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Body Shield" title="Body Shield" groups="Combat" description="With a sly maneuver, you force a grappled opponent into the path of an incoming attack.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As an immediate action while you are grappling an adjacent creature, you can make a grapple combat maneuver check against that creature to gain cover against a single attack. If you are successful and the attack misses you, that attack targets the creature you used as cover, using the same attack roll. You cannot use this feat against a creature grappling you, and the cover you gain ends after the attack you gained cover against is resolved.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bodyguard" title="Bodyguard" groups="Combat" description="Your swift strikes ward off enemies attacking nearby allies.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Reflexes.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When an adjacent ally is attacked, you may use an attack of opportunity to attempt the aid another action to improve your ally&apos;s AC. You may not use the aid another action to improve your ally&apos;s attack roll with this attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Aid another is a standard action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bolster Jinx" title="Bolster Jinx" groups="" description="Your ability to resist certain effects somehow makes it even harder for creatures you jinx to do the same.">
		<Prerequisites>Great Fortitude, Iron Will, or Lightning Reflexes; Halfling Jinx alternate racial trait.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>A jinxed target&apos;s penalty on Fortitude, Reflex, or Will saves increases by 2 if you have the Great Fortitude, Lightning Reflexes, or Iron Will feat, respectively. If you have more than one of these feats, the additional penalties apply to all of the corresponding saves.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bolstered Resilience" title="Bolstered Resilience" groups="" description="You can dramatically increase your damage reduction in exchange for its temporary loss.">
		<Prerequisites> Damage reduction.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As an immediate action, you can double your DR against a single attack, to a maximum of DR 20. The type of the DR remains unchanged. If the attack you are guarding against is not successful, the increased damage reduction persists until you are hit with an attack or until the start of your next turn, whichever happens first. At the start of your next turn, you become fatigued. You cannot use this feat while you are fatigued.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bonded Mind" title="Bonded Mind" groups="Teamwork" description="You and your partner are so close that you can almost read each other's minds.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>As long as you can see each other, you and an ally who also has this feat can trade nonverbal messages. These function as the message spell, except that you don&apos;t need to whisper or point, and you cannot be overheard.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bonebreaker" title="Bonebreaker" groups="Combat" description="When your opponent is unable to adequately defend against them, your precise unarmed strikes break bone and tear tissue.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike, Jawbreaker, Stunning Fist, Heal 9 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you make a successful Stunning Fist attempt against an opponent that is grappled, helpless, or stunned, you can forgo any other Stunning Fist effect to deal 1d6 Strengthor Dexterity damage to that opponent.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bookish Rogue" title="Bookish Rogue" groups="" description="Thanks to your preparation, your arcane ability is more varied than most.">
		<Prerequisites>Minor magic rogue talent.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>By studying a spellbook for 10 minutes, you can change one spell you are able to cast using your minor magic or major magic rogue talent to one sorcerer/wizard spell of the same level contained in the spellbook. This change is permanent until you take the time to change it via this feat again.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Boon Companion" title="Boon Companion" groups="" description="Your bond with your animal companion or familiar is unusually close.">
		<Prerequisites>Animal companion class feature or familiar class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>The abilities of your animal companion or familiar are calculated as though your class were 4 levels higher, to a maximum effective druid level equal to your character level. If you have more than one animal companion or familiar, choose one to receive this benefit. If you dismiss or lose an animal companion or familiar that has received this benefit, you can apply this feat to the replacement creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>You can select this feat more than once. The effects do not stack. Each time you take the feat, it applies to a different animal companion or familiar.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Born Alone" title="Born Alone" groups="Orc" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you kill or knock unconscious an opponent with a melee attack, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Constitution bonus (minimum 1) until your next turn. These temporary hit points do not stack. You do not gain this bonus if the opponent is helpless or has less than half your Hit Dice.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bouncing Spell" title="Bouncing Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can direct a failed spell against a different target.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever a bouncing spell targeting a single creature has no effect on its intended target (whether due to spell resistance or a successful saving throw) you may, as a swift action, redirect it to target another eligible creature within range. The redirected spell behaves in all ways as if its new target were the original target for the spell. Spells that affect a target in any way (including a lesser effect from a successful saving throw) may not be redirected in this manner.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +1 (a bouncing spell uses up a spell slot one level higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bounding Hammer" title="Bounding Hammer" groups="Combat" description="You can throw a hammer so it rebounds near you.">
		<Prerequisites>Proficiency with hammer, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you may throw a hammer at an opponent within 20 feet. If you hit (whether or not the attack damages the target), the hammer rebounds off of the creature and lands in your square. If you have the Snatch Arrows feat, you may choose to catch the hammer when it enters your square (though this does not give you the ability to immediately throw the hammer). This ability may not work against some creatures or in certain circumstances as determined by the GM; for example, your weapon does not bounce off Incorporeal creatures (unless it has the ghost touch ability), it may stick to creatures with the adhesive ability, the slowing effect of fighting underwater prevents you from using this feat, and so on.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>A thrown weapon drops in the square where it hits your target.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brackish Spell" title="Brackish Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You can conjure a seawater orb to protect yourself.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>This feat can be applied only to spells with the water descriptor. You can modify the spell to surround you with a thin sheath of brackish salt water in addition to the spell&apos;s normal effect. You gain DR/piercing equal to the spell&apos;s level for 1 round after you finish casting the spell.</p>
			<p>After this round, the water collapses into a briny puddle and the effect ends. A brackish spell does not use up a higher-level spell slot than the spell&apos;s actual level.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Branch Pounce" title="Branch Pounce" groups="Combat" description="You are adept at exploiting higher ground to its greatest advantage in battle, and can leap from above to deal incredible damage to your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Climb 3 ranks, Stealth 3 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When charging a target by jumping down from above (such as when jumping out of a tree), you can soften your fall with a melee attack. If the attack at the end of your charge hits, the attack deals damage as normal and you also deal the amount of falling damage appropriate to your fall to the target (1d6 points for a 10-foot fall, 2d6 points for a 20-foot fall, and so on). This falling damage is not multiplied on a critical hit. You land in an unoccupied square of your choosing adjacent to the target, and you take falling damage as if your fall had been 10 feet shorter. You can attempt an Acrobatics check as normal to treat the fall as an additional 10 feet shorter for the purpose of determining the damage you take from the fall. If your attack misses, you land prone in a random square adjacent to the target and automatically take the full amount of falling damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Branded for Retribution" title="Branded for Retribution" groups="" description="You brand an enemy with your bane weapon, making it more vulnerable to your allies' attacks.">
		<Prerequisites>Bane class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, expend 3 rounds of your bane class feature and make a melee touch attack with the weapon affected by bane. If you hit, your target takes no damage but is branded until the start of your next turn. While this brand remains, your allies&apos; weapons are considered to have the bane ability with which your weapon is imbued when they attack the branded creature.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bravery in Action" title="Bravery in Action" groups="" description="Sometimes the key to bravery is acting before you have time to be scared.">
		<Prerequisites>Bravery class feature, worshiper of a god of luck or drink.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can add the bonus from bravery to your initiative checks.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Breadth of Experience" title="Breadth of Experience" groups="" description="Although still young for your kind, you have a lifetime of knowledge and training.">
		<Prerequisites>Dwarf, elf, or gnome; 100+ years old.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus on all Knowledge and Profession skill checks, and can make checks with those skills untrained.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Break Guard" title="Break Guard" groups="Combat" description="You can use one of your two weapons to occupy your opponent's defenses while attacking with the other.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 15, Int 13, Combat Expertise, Improved Disarm, Two-Weapon Fighting.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While wielding two weapons, whenever you successfully use one weapon to disarm an opponent, you can spend a swift action to attack the opponent you attempted to disarm using your other weapon.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Breaker of Barriers" title="Breaker of Barriers" groups="Combat" description="You see it as your sacred duty to destroy all obstacles.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 17, worshiper of an evil deity</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Strength checks to break down doors, walls, dams, and other barriers and on combat maneuver checks to bull rush and overrun opponents. You ignore the first 5 points of hardness when you deal damage to doors, walls, dams, and other barriers.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brew Fleshcrafting Poison" title="Brew Fleshcrafting Poison" groups="Item Creation" description="In addition to the several fleshcrafting procedures listed, it's encouraged in drow society for characters experienced with fleshcrafting to constantly experiment and invent new ways of twisting flesh. The following feat is required to successfully brew a fleshcrafting potion.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 10th, 8 or more ranks in Craft (alchemy).</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create a fleshcrafting poison capable of mimicking one monster ability. Brewing a poison takes 1 day. When you create a fleshcrafting poison, you set the caster level, which can be no higher than your own level. The base price of a temporary fleshcrafting poison is its caster level &#xD7; the CR of the creature used in the fleshcrafting &#xD7; 50 gp. To brew a poison, you must spend 1/25 of this base price in XP and use up raw materials costing 1/2 this base price.</p>
			<p>The base price of a permanent fleshcrafting poison is its caster level &#xD7; the CR of the creature used in the fleshcrafting &#xD7; 1000 gp. To brew a poison, you must spend 1/25 of this price in XP and use up raw materials costing 1/2 this base price.</p>
			<p>Note: If the fleshcrafting is an original creation, use the nearest equivalent monster that possesses a similar body part or ability.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brew Potion" title="Brew Potion" groups="Item Creation" description="You can create magic potions.">
		<Prerequisites>Caster level 3rd.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can create a potion of any 3rd-level or lower spell that you know and that targets one or more creatures or objects. Brewing a potion takes 2 hours if its base price is 250 gp or less, otherwise brewing a potion takes 1 day for each 1,000 gp in its base price. When you create a potion, you set the caster level, which must be sufficient to cast the spell in question and no higher than your own level. To brew a potion, you must use up raw materials costing one half this base price.</p>
			<p>When you create a potion, you make any choices that you would normally make when casting the spell. Whoever drinks the potion is the target of the spell and spells with a range of personal cannot be made into potions.See magic item creation rules for more information.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brewmaster" title="Brewmaster" groups="Dwarf" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Craft (alchemy) 1 rank, Profession (brewer) 1 rank, dwarf.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus on Craft (alchemy) and Profession (brewer) checks, and you add +1 to the DC of any ingested poison you create.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brilliant Planner" title="Brilliant Planner" groups="" description="Your experience and intellect enable you to create prescient plans and contingencies.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, character level 5th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can prepare for future contingencies without defining what those preparations are until they are relevant. As a part of this preparation, while in a settlement for at least 24 hours, you can take 8 hours and spend up to 50 gp per character level, which becomes your brilliant plan fund. While you have a brilliant plan pending, you are always treated as carrying 20 additional pounds of weight, even before you define your brilliant plan.</p>
			<p>Once per day, you can take 10 minutes to enact a brilliant plan, withdrawing an item that would have been available in a settlement you visited or procuring a mundane service that your character planned ahead of time. Once you enact the plan, subtract the price of the item or service from this feat&apos;s fund. Any item procured must weigh 10 pounds or less. Likewise, the GM must approve any non-magical service you gain by using this feat as being appropriate for the location selected.</p>
			<p>Once you have spent all the money in your brilliant plan fund or procured 20 pounds of objects with this feat, you cannot use the feat again until you replenish your brilliant plan fund.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brilliant Spell Preparation" title="Brilliant Spell Preparation" groups="" description="You have the foresight to prepare just the right spell for the troubles you face.">
		<Prerequisites>Int 13, ability to prepare 3rd-level spells.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Select one class for which you prepare spells of 3rd level or higher. Once you select a class, it can&apos;t be changed. When you prepare spells for that class, you can leave one spell slot open as a special slot. The slot must be at least 2 levels lower than the highest-level spell you can cast. You can then prepare a spell in this special open slot as a standard action instead of it taking 15 minutes.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brisk Spell" title="Brisk Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="Your movement spells make allies swifter than normal.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13+.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can alter spells that grant a creature a movement type it doesn&apos;t normally have to increase the speed for that movement type by 10 feet.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +0 (a brisk spell uses a spell slot equal to the spell&apos;s normal spell level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bristling Bull Rush" title="Bristling Bull Rush" groups="Combat" description="You deal damage to opponents when bull rushing them through difficult terrain, using the environment itself to harm your targets.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully bull rush a creature, it takes 1d4 points of damage for every 5 feet it is pushed through naturally occurring difficult terrain. This damage is in addition to any damage the creature might normally take from moving through the difficult terrain. Creatures with the woodland stride special ability or who are otherwise unaffected by difficult terrain are immune to this extra damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bristling Drag" title="Bristling Drag" groups="Combat" description="You deal damage to opponents when dragging them through difficult terrain.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Drag, Power Attack, base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully drag a creature, it takes 1d4 points of damage for every 5 feet it is dragged through naturally occurring difficult terrain. This damage is in addition to any damage the creature might normally take from moving through the difficult terrain. Creatures with the woodland stride special ability or who are otherwise unaffected by difficult terrain are immune to this extra damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bristling Drag" title="Bristling Drag" groups="Combat" description="You deal damage to opponents when dragging them through difficult terrain.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Drag, Power Attack, base attack bonus +3.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully drag a creature, it takes 1d4 points of damage for every 5 feet it is dragged through naturally occurring difficult terrain. This damage is in addition to any damage the creature might normally take from moving through the difficult terrain. Creatures with the woodland stride special ability or who are otherwise unaffected by difficult terrain are immune to this extra damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Broken Wing Gambit" title="Broken Wing Gambit" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="You feign weakness, making yourself a tempting and distracting target.">
		<Prerequisites>Bluff 5 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you make a melee attack and hit your opponent, you can use a free action to grant that opponent a +2 bonus on attack and damage rolls against you until the end of your next turn or until your opponent attacks you, whichever happens first. If that opponent attacks you with this bonus, it provokes attacks of opportunity from your allies who have this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brutal Coup de Grace" title="Brutal Coup de Grace" groups="Combat" description="Your killing blows are so brutal that they scare other foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dazzling Display, Weapon Focus, base attack bonus +5, proficiency with the selected weapon.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you deliver a coup de grace with the selected weapon and kill the target, enemies within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you must succeed at a Will saving throw (DC = 10 + 1/2 your character level + your Charisma bonus) or become shaken. This is a mind-affecting fear effect.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brutal Grappler" title="Brutal Grappler" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="...">
		<Prerequisites>Half-orc or orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you and an ally with this feat have grappled the same creature, you may attempt to damage the opponent on your turn (whether you were the one who first initiated the grapple or were assisting your ally in doing so). You and the ally are treated as aiding each other in the grapple (+2 bonus on your grapple combat maneuver) as long as you both decide to maintain the grapple.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>When multiple creatures grapple one target, the creature that first initiates the grapple is the only one that makes a check to damage a grappled opponent, with a +2 bonus for each creature that assists the grapple using the Aid Another action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brute Assault" title="Brute Assault" groups="Combat" description="With brute force, you can bowl over and cripple opponents by treading on them.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 23, Int 13, Brute Stomp, Brute Style, Combat Reflexes, Improved Overrun, Improved Trip, Improved Unarmed Strike, Vicious Stomp, base attack bonus +10.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Brute Style, when you successfully perform an overrun or trip combat maneuver against an opponent that causes that opponent to fall prone, your opponent takes 1d6 points of Strength damage, and its base speed is halved until the Strength damage is healed. A successful Fortitude save (DC = 10 + your base attack bonus) reduces the Strength damage to 1 point and negates the movement speed reduction.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brute Stomp" title="Brute Stomp" groups="Combat" description="Few can avoid the brutal violence of your bone-crushing kicks and stomps.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 19, Int 13, Brute Style, Combat Reflexes, Improved Overrun, Improved Trip, Improved Unarmed Strike, Vicious Stomp, base attack bonus +8.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Brute Style, when you make a full attack with a prone opponent adjacent to you that includes at least one unarmed strike, you can make an additional unarmed strike at your highest base attack bonus against that prone creature. These additional attacks don&apos;t stack with those granted by Medusa&apos;s Wrath, and this does not allow you to make an additional attack against a creature you tripped during your full attack. Additionally, you can use your Vicious Stomp feat against any opponent within your natural reach regardless of whether it falls prone adjacent to you.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Brute Style" title="Brute Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="Through strength, study, and intense inner reflection, you have become an expert at battering fallen opponents.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Int 13, Combat Reflexes, Improved Overrun, Improved Trip, Improved Unarmed Strike, Vicious Stomp, base attack bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you can use your Vicious Stomp feat against any opponent within 10 feet of you, as long as it is within your natural reach. If you don&apos;t have the Vicious Stomp feat, you gain no benefit from this feat.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>The Vicious Stomp feat only works against an opponent that falls prone adjacent to you.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bulette Charge Style" title="Bulette Charge Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You use the weight of your armor to enhance the momentum of your charge.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Overrun, Power Attack, proficiency with heavy armor.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using this style, you gain a +4 bonus feats on combat maneuver checks to overrun an opponent. Any magic ability or material that reduces your armor check penalty also reduces the bonus you gain for this style.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>A character with the armor training class feature can use Bulette Charge Style while wearing any type of armor with which she is proficient. Medium armor grants a +3 bonus, and light armor grants a +2 bonus.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bulette Leap" title="Bulette Leap" groups="Combat" description="You can shove aside multiple opponents while leaping into the air.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Bulette Charge Style, Improved Overrun, Power Attack, proficiency with heavy armor.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While using Bulette Charge Style, you gain a bonus on Acrobatics checks to jump equal to your Strength bonus. Additionally, when you perform an overrun combat maneuver, you can attempt to overrun multiple foes, but you take a cumulative -2 penalty on each successive overrun attempt in the same round. If an overrun attempt fails, you cannot make any further attempts until your next round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bulette Rampage" title="Bulette Rampage" groups="Combat" description="You are able to channel your enhanced momentum to deal incredible damage to multiple foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 15, Bulette Charge Style, Bulette Leap, Improved Overrun, Power Attack, proficiency with heavy armor.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>While you&apos;re using Bulette Charge Style, whenever you succeed at an overrun combat maneuver check against a foe, that foe takes an amount of damage equal to 1d8 (if your size is Medium) or 1d6 (if your size is Small) + 1/2 your armor bonus to AC + 1-1/2 times your Strength bonus.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bull Rush Strike" title="Bull Rush Strike" groups="Combat" description="Your critical hits can push back your foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Str 13, Improved Bull Rush, Power Attack, base attack bonus +9.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you score a critical hit with a melee attack, you can push your opponent back, in addition to the normal damage dealt by the attack. If your confirmation roll exceeds your opponent&apos;s CMD, you may push your opponent back as if from the bull rush combat maneuver. You do not need to move with the target if successful. This does not provoke an attack of opportunity.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>You must perform a bull rush combat maneuver to bull rush an opponent.</p>
		</Normal>
		<Special>
			<p>You can only apply the effects of one of the following feats to a given critical hit: Bull Rush Strike, Disarming Strike, Repositioning Strike, Sundering Strike, or Tripping Strike. You may choose to use this feat after you make your confirmation roll.</p>
		</Special>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bull-Catcher Style" title="Bull-Catcher Style" groups="Combat,Style" description="You brace yourself to catch oncoming foes.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you can ready yourself against oncoming foes. Until the start of your next turn, if a creature moves at least 10 feet in your direction and enters a square you threaten, you can attempt a grapple combat maneuver against that creature. If the creature is charging, you gain a +2 bonus on the check. A creature you grapple with this style can make only a single natural attack after its movement or charge, even if it has the pounce ability. You can make only one grapple attempt in this manner per round.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bull-Catcher Toss" title="Bull-Catcher Toss" groups="Combat" description="You can use a charging foe's momentum to throw them aside.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Bull-Catcher Style, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike; base attack bonus +8, brawler level 4th, or monk level 4th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you successfully grapple a creature with the Bull-Catcher Style feat, you can immediately move that creature into any square you threaten. After it is placed, you can break your grapple as an immediate action to move the creature an additional 5 feet in any direction. You can&apos;t use this maneuver to move a foe into a space that is intrinsically dangerous or unstable, such as a pit, wall of fire, or midair.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bull-Catcher Wrangler" title="Bull-Catcher Wrangler" groups="Combat" description="You can wrestle a charging foe to the ground.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Bull-Catcher Style, Bull-Catcher Toss, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike; base attack bonus +12, brawler level 8th, or monk level 8th.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When a creature is charging you, and you successfully grapple it with the Bull-Catcher Style feat, you can immediately move it as per the Bull-Catcher Toss feat. Once the creature is moved, you can break your grapple as an immediate action. If you do, select another creature in the repositioned target&apos;s threatened area. That creature becomes the new target of the initial charge attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bullseye Shot" title="Bullseye Shot" groups="Combat" description="You slow your breath, calm yourself, and hit the bullseye, just as you were trained to do.">
		<Prerequisites>Point-Blank Shot, Precise Shot, base attack bonus +5.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You can spend a move action to steady your shot. When you do, you gain a +4 bonus on your next ranged attack roll before the end of your turn.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: You can spend 5 stamina points to use Bullseye Shot as a swift action.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bully Breed" title="Bully Breed" groups="" description="Your animal companion can terrify as well as fight.">
		<Prerequisites>Handle Animal 4 ranks, Intimidate 4 ranks, animal companion or mount class feature.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Your animal companion or mount gains Intimidate as a class skill. It can attempt to demoralize an opponent using the Intimidate skill as a move action on the same round that it damages an opponent with a natural attack.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Special>
			<p>Your animal companion can select the Dazzling Display and Shatter Defenses feats if it meets the prerequisites. This feat does not allow your animal companion to use Intimidate to make a target friendly or gain their assistance.</p>
		</Special>
		<Normal>
			<p>Animal companions and mounts with an Intelligence score of 2 or less must select feats from a limited list.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bullying Blow" title="Bullying Blow" groups="Combat,Orc" description="With a simple hit, you more easily intimidate an opponent.">
		<Prerequisites>Intimidate 1 rank, orc.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>As a standard action, you may make a melee attack with a &#x2013;2 penalty on the attack roll. If the attack damages your opponent, you may make an Intimidate check to demoralize that opponent as a free action.</p>
		</Benefit>
		<Normal>
			<p>Intimidating an opponent is a standard action.</p>
		</Normal>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Burn It Down!" title="Burn It Down!" groups="Combat,Teamwork" description="Burning torches and the discordant symphony of riotous singing ignite the fervor within you.">
		<Prerequisites>Base attack bonus +1, goblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you make an attack with a torch, a flask of lamp oil fitted with a fuse, alchemist&apos;s fire, or a flaming weapon, you gain a morale bonus on your damage roll equal to the number of goblin allies within 30 feet who also have this feat (maximum +4). This bonus damage is fire damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Burn! Burn! Burn!" title="Burn! Burn! Burn!" groups="Goblin" description="">
		<Prerequisites>Disable Device 1 rank, Goblin.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You deal an extra 1d4 points of fire damage when you attack with fire from an alchemical or non-magical source (such as with alchemical fire or torches) and gain a +4 competence bonus on Reflex saving throws made to avoid catching on fire or to put yourself out when on fire. Additional damage caused by this feat does not apply to magical attacks (such as an alchemist&apos;s bomb) or to splash damage.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Burning Amplification" title="Burning Amplification" groups="" description="You can expend some of the energy of your fire spells to make the flames linger long enough to cause your opponents to catch ablaze.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>Whenever you cast a spell with the fire descriptor, you can take a &#x2013;1 penalty on the spells&apos; attack rolls and reduce the spell&apos;s saving throw DC by 1 to cause any target that is dealt fire damage to catch on fire. The targets do not take burning damage for catching on fire until their next turn, and each target can attempt a Reflex saving throw to put out the fire before being damaged each round. Rather than the normal DC 15 Reflex saving throw to put the fire out, the target must succeed at a Reflex saving throw with a DC equal 10 + the spell&apos;s level + the modifier of your spellcasting ability score). You must choose to use this feat before making an attack roll or before your targets attempt their saving throws. This feat has no effect on spells that neither allow a saving throw nor require an attack roll.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Burning Spell" title="Burning Spell" groups="Metamagic" description="You cause creatures to take extra damage when you affect them with a spell that has the acid or fire descriptor.">
		<Benefit>
			<p>The acid or fire effects of the affected spell adhere to the creature, causing more damage the next round. When a creature takes acid or fire damage from the affected spell, that creature takes damage equal to 2x the spell&apos;s actual level at the start of its next turn. The damage is acid or fire, as determined by the spell&apos;s descriptor. If a burning spell has both the fire and acid descriptor, the caster chooses what kind of damage is dealt by the burning spell effect.</p>
			<p>Level Increase: +2 (a burning spell uses up a slot two levels higher than the spell&apos;s actual level.)</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Burrowing Teeth" title="Burrowing Teeth" groups="Ratfolk" description="You have teeth and claws that suit you well to digging.">
		<Prerequisites>Sharpclaw, Tunnel Rat, ratfolk.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>You gain a burrow speed equal to 1/2 your base speed. You can burrow through sand, dirt, clay, gravel, or similar materials, but not solid stone. You do not leave a hole behind, nor is your passage marked on the surface.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Bushwhack" title="Bushwhack" groups="Combat" description="You can subdue an unsuspecting foe quickly.">
		<Prerequisites>Dex 13, Improved Grapple, Improved Unarmed Strike.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When a flat-footed creature is unaware of your presence and you successfully grapple it, you can attempt a second grapple combat maneuver check to pin the creature as a free action. If you have the Chokehold feat, you can instead use this second combat maneuver check to initiate a chokehold.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="But a Scratch" title="But a Scratch" groups="Combat" description="Your bravado convinces your enemies that their deadliest attacks are mere trifles, making you seem nigh invulnerable.">
		<Prerequisites>Cha 13, Bluff 4 ranks.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When an opponent confirms a critical hit against you with a melee weapon, you can attempt a special Bluff check against that opponent as an immediate action.</p>
			<p>The DC of this check is the same as the DC to demoralize the opponent with the Intimidate skill. If you are successful, the attacking opponent is shaken for 1 round as if you had successfully demoralized it with Intimidate.</p>
			<p>Exceeding the DC by 5 or more does not add to the shaken condition&apos;s duration. If you fail the special Bluff check granted by this feat, you can attempt it against opponents who saw you attempt the earlier check and fail, but you take a -2 cumulative penalty on that Bluff check and any subsequent Bluff checks attempted in conjunction with this feat against those opponents for 24 hours.</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
	<Bundle id="Butterfly's Sting" title="Butterfly's Sting" groups="Critical" description="You can forgo a critical hit in order to pass it on to an ally.">
		<Prerequisites>Combat Expertise, worship of the associated deity.</Prerequisites>
		<Benefit>
			<p>When you confirm a critical hit against a creature, you can choose to forgo the effect of the critical hit and grant a critical hit to the next ally who hits the creature with a melee attack before the start of your next turn. Your attack only deals normal damage, and the next ally automatically confirms the hit as a critical.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick</p>
			<p>Source PPC:WMH</p>
			<p>Note If using the optional Stamina Pool rules, the following trick may be used with this feat.</p>
			<p>Combat Trick: When you confirm a critical hit, you can spend 10 stamina points to use Butterfly&apos;s Sting without forgoing your own critical hit.</p>
			<p>Saturday Potpourri: Butterfly&apos;s Sting Feats</p>
		</Benefit>
	</Bundle>
</Bundles>
